Chapter 33: Portkeys, Trains and Carriages, Pt 2

"It is a common mistake to glorify those you have tricked, to imagine that you have toppled their cleverness by your own subtlety. Arrogance leads men to imagine their adversaries great, in retrospect." - Lucius Malfoy

"And then what happened?" asked Professor Lockhart. Their carriage hit a bump right as he spoke, and he jostled up against Horace Slughorn's enormous belly. The short trip from the train to their quarters should only take a few more minutes.

"Then the little bastard spewed his infernal drink right into my eyes and coughed for several minutes. 'Swallowed the wrong way,' he said. And apologized profusely, but of course he'd just been trying to keep me from peeking into his mind. The funny thing is, I don't think the boy's had Occlumenency training, although with a Malfoy who knows?"

Gilderoy smiled broadly at that. "So, you think he just guessed or suspected you might invade his mind? Seems paranoid. At least young Draco has learned my lessons about ambushes, but still... all signs point to him being somewhat estranged from Narcissa."

"Estranged or not, she may still have taught him. Assuming it isn't a ruse. Anyway, of course I accepted his apology and went back and cleaned myself up. And while I was doing that he calmly explained that he'd hired Grindelwald as a tutor for history, Transfiguration, and what not, and that they'd gone into business together. He wouldn't go into details, so I suspect it's something not-quite-legitimate, but probably not terrible either. He also mentioned seeing your date with Narcissa..."

"And did you? Peek into his mind?" Gilderoy asked.

"No need to be so touchy and try to change the subject, my dear fellow. I have no idea how young Malfoy got the impression that I was courting his mother – not that it wouldn't be pleasant – but I have a reasonable understanding of how I am viewed by Witches. I don't begrudge you the experience."

Professor Lockhart merely crossed his arms across his chest and cocked his head.

"Erm. Well, yes, of course I peeked into his mind. The Headmistress asked and I am but her humble servant. But I was only looking for anything untoward, not a full scale rummaging around. In any case, his story about Grindelwald is true. What little I saw before getting a face full of that drink – you'd be surprised how sticky it is, who drinks sticky liquids? - confirmed it. The business is inconsequential. No, that's not the worrisome part."

Gilderoy started tapping his foot softly.

"No, the part that worries me is the gaps in young Malfoy's memory."

"Gaps?" said Lockhart, alarmed "How many? When?"

"You should know that's not how it works, Gilderoy. At least twice over the holidays and who knows how many prior to that. Sloppy work, too. Imprecise. Of course Draco just chalked it up to tiredness, but he's worried about them at some level."

The carriage pulled up to a stop, they were right outside the front gate of Hogwarts. They could see the students just starting to walk on campus, Hagrid and the non-Heads of House leading them along.

"And are you going to tell the Headmistress?" asked Professor Lockhart.

Horace Slughorn pulled out a handkerchief and started rubbing his forehead. "Well, I have to. Part of the job."

Professor Slughorn started to ease his way out of the carriage, but the Offense Professor put his hand his arm. "I have a … confession … that may affect your decision. Hear me out."

Minerva McGonagall stared at Professor Slughorn. "Are you not feeling well, Horace?"

"Perhaps something I ate disagreed with me." Professor Slughorn could see the flicker of disapproval before the Headmistress controlled her emotions. No, she'd never make a good Occlumens. In fact Professor Slughorn had eaten lightly at dinner, but he'd snacked constantly on the train trip up while hosting his little get-together. He stared back across the Headmistress's desk. She looked less fierce than last year, as if the toll of the job had washed over her and she'd started to relax into it. The office looked mostly as it had during his earlier tenure as Potions Professor, except the one giant frame behind the desk, labeled "Albus Dumbledore." Other portraits had been shifted to make space for the latest addition to the wall, but unlike the rest of the portraits, there was nothing to see.

Just a blank canvas. The sight unnerved him.

"Well then, about Draco Malfoy. Anything of note? Should we be worried about him? He's very ambitious, more so than most of your House..."

"Minerva, all of my students - make that all students - are ambitious. Everyone dreams of being the next Merlin or Idlewind or Flamel or whoever kids emulate these days. What sets Draco apart from the rest of them aren't his dreams but the dedication and training to follow through. I never thought I'd say this, but he'd make an excellent Hufflepuff. Don't fear Draco's desires, admire his execution and tenacity. That boy has steel in his spine, probably because of his father's murder. But, since you asked. He's not getting into anything nefarious with Grindelwald. It's a poorly thought out business. I personally think that he's going to take a bath on this investment but Draco isn't going in with any illusions. He thinks making money will be nip and tuck, but even if he lost everything he's put into it – a considerable sum – he's gotten private tutoring with an excellent Wizard and turned the entire Jugson clan into an ally."

"That's rather ... involved for a twelve year old."

"He also views it as an investment to help him understand Muggle business practices. I don't really understand, perhaps Professor Asimov would have better insights. Remember, Madame, A great plot threatens multiple victories It sounds better in the original Latin, but certainly the most basic tenet of Salazar's cunning was written over Malfoy's first bassinet. As far as Draco is concerned, he's already profited. He might win several more times over."

The Headmistress considered this, but she seemed satisfied. "I see what you mean about ambition versus execution. And what about his date with Miss Granger?"

"Now now, Minerva, you said you were investigating Dark Secrets and didn't want to know about minor peccadilloes, didn't you? I didn't delve into his memories like a voracious grubworm..."

Minerva sighed. "No, of course not. I just don't want to see that girl get hurt."

Professor Slughorn got up. "Of course not, she's charming. And while I happen to know that he had a few ulterior motives for the date - No, I didn't see that in his mind, but I do keep myself informed - but it was just a date. If the lad isn't smitten yet, he's well on his way."

"Yes, well. Do keep me informed about Draco. And the rest of your House. I don't want to expel another single student, is that clear?"

Professor Slughorn agreed, said his goodbye and showed himself out. He started the long walk back to his quarters, Occlumency barriers up even though alone. Perhaps he should have told Minerva about the gaps in Draco's memory. He would have, except that Horace Slughorn had been doing digging of his own. He'd wondered where the two most famous second years, students who should have rightfully been guided and mentored by himself, spent their days. It certainly wasn't in classes. He'd been shocked at the amount of power wielded by those two, but months of quiet talk and letters had confirmed it.

Potter practically ran Hogwarts and Peverell, albeit from behind the scenes, and had major influence in the government. Horace Slughorn knew any secret he told the Headmistress would be heard by Harry Potter.

And that wouldn't do, because of the other worrisome thing he'd glimpsed in Draco Malfoy's mind. Despite Lucius Malfoy's death, Legilmency against a Malfoy remained an enormous risk but Draco's actions looked alarming enough to risk. So he'd agreed to the Headmistresses request and asked point blank what Draco did during his break right as he'd probed Draco's mind.

Draco had instantly thought of his actions with Grindelwald, but they weren't his primary reaction. No, the clearest image was Draco locked inside his own vault, writing a letter to Harry Potter. Professor Slughorn could see Draco scratching the words onto the parchment.

And if you are Voldemort – or should I say, Tom Riddle - ...

The thought had stunned Horace Slughorn more than the barrage of soda hitting his face a second later.

How had Draco Malfoy worked out that Tom Riddle was Voldemort? The name Tom Riddle meant nothing to someone Draco's age. There were probably only a handful of people who'd made the connection, not counting those who understood only a few seconds before death. He himself had taken years to piece it together, then decades to finally admit it to himself.

And a twelve year old boy had solved it ... in a year or two at most.

It made Draco's other suspicion much more plausible.

Horace Slughorn never planned to feed any information about Draco Malfoy back to Harry Potter. At least, not until he finished his own investigations. He'd only shared his secret to Professor Lockhart as insurance. When operating against Voldemort (or any other Dark Wizard) it didn't do to keep too many secrets. That made you much more valuable dead than alive, or got yourself tortured for information. No, best to give a dedicated and persistent opponent an easier way to discover your secrets. Also, if his lie to the Headmistress did get revealed, he'd be able to spin it innocently if he'd shared it with someone else.

Maybe not enough to save his job, but enough to keep his reputation. He consulted with another Professor, at least.

Surprisingly, Gilderoy's confession provided a compelling excuse to lie to the Headmistress in good faith. It had been such a lucky stroke, Horace wondered that he hadn't accidentally spilled Felix Felicis into his tea. Now even if the worst happened and the Headmistress caught him in a lie, Horace Slughorn would have a reason that even she'd balk at condemning. And an ally in Professor Lockhart.

That young fool desperately wanted to hunt a Dark Wizard.

Chapter 35: Wargames, Pt 2 (Purple and Green)

"Beware the angry man. Beware the violent man. But mostly beware the man you cannot predict." - Lucius Malfoy

Monday

Today was Hermione's turn to lecture the first years, so Draco joined Gregory and Vincent's martial arts practice after breakfast. Of all of them, Draco missed practice most often – Harry's schedule was flexible enough to make practice whenever, but Draco had to lecture as well as take a full course load. So he lagged behind, but at least he wasn't doubled over panting in the first half hour. They ended the session sparring and Draco partnered with Harry while Neville watched.

They'd circled around each other early, warily. Draco took a quick step forward and jabbed, then pulled back, but Harry had stepped back. Harry tried to jab, but Draco circled away. This was typical for them, they didn't have any flashy moves yet, not like Vincent and Gregory. Draco was about to jab again but instinct stopped him. He shifted his feet – left foot forward - Harry stepped forward and jabbed, but Draco was also moving forward, snapping a hard kick into Harry's stomach. Harry's fist brushed Draco's chin at the same time, but just barely.

Harry doubled over and collapsed onto the ground.

"Sorry!" Draco said. Wizards could take more damage than Muggles, but it didn't make it any less painful. Vincent or Gregory would have pulled their kick back, Draco wasn't skilled enough. Harry rolled on the ground, not quite retching but making gurgling noises. Gregory was talking to Harry and Vincent pulled Draco aside.

"He walked into that," Vincent said. "And you over-committed. If he'd jumped out of the way, or swept your leg aside he'd have knocked you over and sat on you." They'd practiced that. If someone wound up sitting on your chest they'd pin your arms underneath their legs. Even if you had a wand out you'd be hard pressed to use it. You'd lose to gravity. Vincent and Gregory could sometimes recover from that disadvantage, with their years of training and conditioning. Crabbe could throw any of them off and Gregory managed to slip out. But neither Harry, Neville or Draco could. For them, having an opponent on top of you meant losing, and badly.

"Point taken," said Draco, looking over at Harry who had at least gotten up to his knees. They walked over to Harry.

"Good kick," Harry managed to gasp out. "What did I do wrong?" he asked Gregory, after he was finally able to stand up straight. They started walking back inside the castle, the only had twenty minutes to make it up all those flights to Offense Against the Dark Arts and Harry wasn't walking quickly.

"You telegraphed it, and you took an actual step, which takes you off balance and makes you slow. I keep saying 'shuffle your feet.' You can take steps when you aren't really close, but at striking distance... just don't. Anything to add?" Gregory looked at Vincent.

"I'm not sure you should be closing against Draco, certainly not drastically like that. You're taller. That counts for a lot, at least until you develop a personal style." They started up the first of the flights of stairs and Harry kept going up with them, wincing at the first few stairs.

"Are you joining us today?" Draco asked.

Harry nodded. "I think I'm going to sit in on Offense from now on. I'm missing out, not attending. It's the one class where I can't just read the materials and plow ahead faster than the teacher can talk. It's really the only surprising class so far. And I need to keep up with what everyone knows to plan the Muggle Naval Simulation scenarios."

A year ago, that would have offended Draco immeasurably. Not what Harry said, but just the reminder that he was above taking classes. Now Draco felt that nothing Harry could say or do would offend him.

"Besides, I hear there's going to be an announcement for everyone," Harry added, and Draco remembered that Harry could still annoy him easily enough.

The group was one of the last to arrive at Offense. Harry joined Draco and Gregory among the Slytherin contingent while Neville and Vincent took their usual seats with the Hufflepuffs. Draco noticed Hermione sitting with the Gryffindors. He was about to nudge Harry when Professor Lockhart strolled out from the teacher's office and flashed the smile he opened every class with.

It was easy to like Professor Lockhart.

"Hello, and I hope you all had a refreshing weekend. Let's just jump right into it, shall we?" Professor Lockhart looked out among the students listening to his every word and smiled again, broadly.

"Battles are fought for so many reasons. To overthrow a government. To steal something, or keep it from being stolen. Vengeance. Honour. To defend a key point, be it a choke-point – although those mostly apply for muggles, since they can't apparate – or a trade route, or ley line. For glory. And usually, for power. Dominance. And as we've seen before battles can sweep up and rage across a land with innocent civilians caught in the middle."

The room started grumbling at the mention of that particular battle, and Draco unconsciously rubbed his left shoulder. Professor Lockhart shook his head, but still smiled.

"Well, I don't blame you for not taking that well. But hopefully you will be more pleased that for our next battle the Headmistress has graciously allowed me to include the entire student body of Hogwarts! Now now, please, let me finish."

"This does put you at a disadvantage, but in any battle – I suppose I should say 'war,' really, since the scale is so much bigger – for this war you have so many skills besides spell casting that come into play. Battles are won on the battlefield, to be sure. Wars are won by planning, cunning, guile and bravery! You win wars by fighting the right battles, and that's something I have been woefully neglecting to teach."

"So, a brief summary of the format. There are South American tribes called the D'razi that fight a civil war every five summers. They put in bunch of green and purple sashes into a big barrel, and then reach in and pull out a sash. Whoever draws a purple sash joins the purple team, and whoever draws a green sash joins the green team. After the ceremony the D'razi are symbolically split in two, and they fight until there is just one side! Sometimes it takes a full year. So, at Friday's dinner we'll have barrels for each house. You'll pick a stone and that will decide which team you are on!"

"But, those are Slytherin colours!" Neville said. "Can't we pick something more ... neutral?"

"Not everything has to be about houses!" Professor Lockhart said, somewhat sharply. "But in fact, I did try to come up with two colours that weren't just black and white. I also considered solids and stripes, but as sartorial choices go..." he shook his head.

"It just wouldn't do. If it offends you then we'll just consider it a way to honor the D'razi or - if you prefer - Professor Quirrell. So, on Friday we'll have our lottery and your robes will adjust accordingly. Each house will have one leader for purple and one for green. If you are 'killed' in the game your robes will adjust accordingly. An hour after the lottery ends, the war will start and it will continue until one side has all their leaders killed. To represent the Fidelius Charm, you will be safe in your bed, but nowhere else."

Professor Lockhart stopped to take in a breath and Tracey Davis spoke up. "That seems simple, at least compared to having secret agents like last time. What's the catch?"

Professor Lockhart just smiled. "It's neither fun or realistic to know all the rules ahead of time. But in any case many wars actually have well defined sides. While nobody knew for sure who the Death Eaters were, classical wars often involved differing nationalities that are often easy to tell apart by sight. Consider purple and green as your flags, two countries that hate each other. Don't be late for dinner on Friday! Now, let us turn to the discussion of scrying and how it pertains to scouting out territory..."

"He said What?"

Headmistress McGonagall's tone had neither risen or fallen at the end, it had merely … sharpened, ending in a final, tight point then quickly expiring. Harry Potter pushed down the urge to be anywhere else. It was stupid, a reaction to being glared at by an adult who had such considerable experience intimidating children that she did it naturally. He felt sure it wasn't directed at him. Not exactly. Still, it didn't make it any more comfortable.

"It's not a bad idea," chuckled Mad-eye, standing in the back corner of the Headmistress's office, where he could keep an eye on the room and the fireplace. "Mind you, I'm not sticking up for the lad. We could've used more people who knew about intrigue for the Order. Including Albus. Lot of time and people lost, learning those lessons." Several of the paintings around Alastor harrumphed or tsk'ed him with the portrait of Headmaster Walter Aragon calling out "Shame! Shame!" down at him.

If Mad-eye Moody heard the portraits, he gave no indication.

"I agree," said Harry. "It's a good idea. I mean, I thought he had checked with you first, of course, but this is just what we've been learning on a grander scale."

"The armies that Quirrell started are a voluntary activity. This involves everyone. It will be chaos," Minerva sighed. "Which is why you are positively giddy, Mr. Potter. But I would expect more from you, Alastor." She leaned back in her chair as far as it would go. She wasn't exactly lying down, but she came fairly close to being horizontal. "I will talk with Gilderoy later. As for now, I intend to relax until the next unforeseen disaster strikes. I hope to get the full hour," she said as she pulled her hat over her face, dismissing them.

Author's Note - I will be on a somewhat reduced schedule, but posting at least once a week.

Chapter 36: Too Much Information

"Passion makes fools of the clever, yet turns fools into geniuses." - Lucius Malfoy, quoting Albus Dumbledore

Wednesday

Draco sat down heavily in the Potions classroom. He dropped his scroll onto his desk. Ten inches on the proper technique for mixing Arnica roots into Occulus potion. He'd stayed up late to finish it, but also to avoid going to bed early. He'd slept reasonably well back at home, still tossing and turning during the night, but always falling asleep after a few minutes.

Rest had not followed him back to Hogwarts. He'd spent hours each night awake, alone with his thoughts. Draco realized that he'd had too much to do in too little time. Getting his business arrangements set up, his correspondence. He'd filled up his daytime hours and collapsed into a dreamless sleep, or if he was awake he had pressing matters.

Now that Draco had urgent matters but no self-imposed deadlines he'd spent his first few nights lying awake, unable to sleep. If he closed his eyes the noise sounded like vines creeping along the ground, and the wind smelled of snow and pine needles. Gregory's snoring sounded relaxing in comparison, but set Draco's teeth on edge and something of it reminded him of the sound of ripping tendons. His shoulder would throb. After an hour or two Draco would sigh quietly in get up to review his lessons or do his homework. His grades would be exemplary for as long as he couldn't sleep.

Until he cracked.

Draco knew he could just go to the infirmary for a sleeping draught and he knew his pride was foolish, but he wasn't yet ready to go. Perhaps he'd just try to make some after class, but the thought of Professor Slughorn knowing felt even worse. He reconsidered talking to Madame Pomfrey.

"Good morning, Draco, Gregory" said Padma Patil, sitting to Draco's right. Had she been there when he was sitting down? Gregory had taken the seat to his left, of course, but Draco didn't remember if the other seat had been occupied. He hadn't heard her sit down. She was smiling at him broadly.

He hadn't heard much, this morning.

"Good morning, Padma," Draco said, stiffing a yawn."I was up late," he said as an apology, motioning to his scroll as Gregory said hello. Draco looked around and saw Neville and Vincent. Today was a doubles session with Hufflepuff. If he'd been paying attention he would have sat next to them...

Pay attention to your guest! Lucius' voice rang sternly in Draco's head and he turned back to Padma. He hadn't really done more than glance around the room, really. But Draco focused his attention.

"You wrote way more than I did," Padma said, pointing to her own scroll.

"I couldn't think of a way to summarize it. I rambled. Too much information and all that."

"That's an interesting way of putting it," Padma said, leaning forward and resting her chin on her hands.

"It's something Harry says, Too much information and not enough insight" Gregory interjected, then quickly gave an abashed look and leaned back, away from the conversation.

Draco knew that Harry didn't consider the Bayesian Conspiracy an important secret. He'd be perfectly happy to lecture the entire school on it, if he felt they were ready. But Harry did recognize that by limiting the group ensured that people gave his lessons importance. If – when – Harry spouted off insights that revealed deep truths of human fallacy or the natural order people ignored him or even ridiculed him.

(Draco made fun of Harry, too. Half of the fun of camaraderie involved mocking your friends foibles. And sometimes Draco didn't want people to have quite as good an understanding as Harry was willing to impart.)

But when Harry doled out the truth slowly and made the recipients feel like a self-selected elite crowd, the same people would hang on his every word. Even knowing the trick, Draco felt more respectful during Conspiracy meetings. Harry left Galleons all over the place and nobody picked them up, but when he parceled out Knuts to their secret society, everyone quickly deposited them and thanked Harry profusely.

Gregory, and most of the newer members of the Conspiracy, considered it their duty to guard the information they'd learned, lest the shared knowledge make them less important. Draco found it amusing, sometimes.

"It's basically the same thing that Professor Quirrel talked about last year. If you know that exposing trolls to sunlight turned them to stone, you might be tempted to use that information..."

"Instead of just apparating away," Padma finished. The classroom was filling up, but Professor Slughorn hadn't arrived yet. Gregory was pretending to proofread his homework, face slowly losing his crimson blush.

"Right. Or deciding what spell to attack with, when you aren't even sure you should be dueling. You see?"

"Oh absolutely," she said and Draco mentally added Or like carrying on a friendly conversation with a girl who has romantic intentions with you without understanding what's going on. Fortunately at that moment Professor Slughorn strolled into the room, chuckling at some private joke, and said "Today we are going to learn how to brew the Wiggenweld Potion. Incredibly useful if you happen to be attacked by Sleeping Sirens or if you tend to oversleep and are late, yes I'm referring to you Mr. MacMillan. Don't think I didn't see you try to slink in behind me!"

Thursday

Daphne Greengrass heard the footsteps behind her as she went up the stairs towards the Great Hall and breakfast. She glanced back to see Draco Malfoy barely putting one foot in front of the other, head down, behind her. As always, his robes and appearance looked immaculate, but the effect was ruined for once.

"Another long night?" she asked cheerfully.

Draco snorted, head still down, and she laughed. "What's funny?" It sounded like the words had escaped Draco's mouth by accident.

"Your snort. The rudest thing you've done to me, so I know you consider me a friend. To a mere acquaintance you would have answered. You only grunt to friends, when you think others can't hear you."

"And before breakfast," Draco added with a shrug.

They walked up the next few flights of stairs in silence and came out of the Dungeons.

"Daphne," Draco paused for a second, glancing around as they walked, and Daphne realized that there wasn't anyone else around. "What do girls say about me?"

Daphne almost giggled or rolled her eyes, but something in Draco's expression stopped her. They were both Silvery Slytherins, after all. And he seemed so. Despondent. Draco had been full of energy all last year, even after he almost got murdered. Especially after he almost got murdered, and then when he rushed around trying to help after coming back to Hogwarts. But now his bursts of energy seemed to happen less often. He'd sit and think or hang out in the library. Now he only had energy when he was interacting with other people, in public.

Was Draco moping about a girl? Did boys even do that? Boys in stories performed wildly outlandish acts to impress girls and - judging from the gossip - Draco had. Although Daphne did not for one minute believe Milicent Bulstrode's claim that Draco had dueled an Auror in Training for Hermione's hand. But the funny thing was, that wasn't out of the realm of reason. Draco probably had the ability, he'd been ambushed several times and while he hadn't won all of those duels he'd hardly been disgraced. No, the story didn't feel believable because she couldn't imagine Draco having to duel some foolish auror-wannabe.

Outwardly, Daphne considered the question for seven more steps. Her mother had told her that treating other people's questions as serious and considering them fully would mark her as a serious thinker. And seven was lucky, after all. But she did actually come up with a few interesting thoughts during her pause.

"Because of Hermione?"

"No, because of Padma," Draco answered. "I … I didn't realize she liked me, so I'm thinking about everything I said to her – or didn't say – and it all seems innocent enough. But undoubtedly I've forgotten things. Does she think I've been cruel? Do others?"

"Fortunately for you, girls think all boys are oblivious. This is the rare case where the fundamental attribution error doesn't apply. Not for a few years, at least. We're all very quick to point out to each other that sometimes when a boy isn't paying attention, it just means you haven't gotten his attention. Although now that I think about it Girls are usually oblivious, too. Your date with Hermione did get a lot of gossip and talk, but it's just talk..."

"Talk is never just talk," Draco interrupted. Then, more softly, "Sorry."

Daphne nodded, she saw his point. Draco hadn't asked what to do, he'd asked how he appeared to others. A subtle difference, but an important one. Daphne took seven more steps, then realized something she could say.

"Do you remember last year during our battle in the Hallways, when I challenged Neville to a duel?

Draco nodded. She noticed that he'd straightened up as they got closer to the hall. He'd gone from looking like a tired boy to a bored noble over the last hundred steps, like Draco Malfoy could transfigure himself into the outward appearance he desired. His strides lengthened, although he'd slowed after starting to pull away from Daphne.

"Did you ever consider why?" she asked him.

"To win the battle, obviously," Draco said, taking four steps. He suddenly stopped and turned towards her. Daphne blushed. At the time, she'd wanted people to notice. She'd felt annoyed they hadn't noticed...

"So," Draco said, starting to walk again, "I think about it much more than anyone else? Just because I can say 'egocentric bias' doesn't make me immune."

The nice thing about being with a fellow Bayesian Conspirator is that you could have public conversations and sometimes nobody else could follow. Harry called that the Darmok effect for no reason Daphne could see. They'd walked into the Great Hall now and sat down to breakfast. Draco's words drew few glances, everyone knew he sometimes spoke in the cryptic way more suited to Harry Potter than the Most Noble and Ancient House of Malfoy.

"No..." Daphne drawled the words out. There had been hours of discussion spread over the last few days. She'd discussed it with the Slytherin witches, who had noticed Padma's crush a few months ago and had wondered how she'd react to the news of Draco's date with Hermione. Tracey Davis had said Parvati had teased her sister during the entire second half of the train ride, until Hannah Abbot had stepped in to separate them. There had been ominous talk of love potions, duels, and an intra-family feud that would last a lifetime. Typical teenage girl declarations, the kind of thing that Daphne heard on a monthly basis.

"Let's just say that witches don't assign you much agency," she said. "In this regard" she added hastily.

Draco had cut up some fruit and took a bite, chewing slowly. Even though he'd paused to eat, it made him seem wise. That really was good advice, to treat all questions with respect. "So, I'm a plot's goal?" he said, after he swallowed. Several heads swung around to look at Draco and smile. The last two sentences had been easily to understand. Draco just rolled his eyes and mumbled "Witches" under his breath and Lesath Lestrange and Blaise Zabini just laughed and returned to their breakfast.

Daphne took a bite of her pancakes and chewed slowly. Two could play that game.

"Only to the uninterested parties. And not a plot, a play. The audience mingles in the lobby during intermission, trying to guess the ending. Or at least the next scene. It's just a distraction from their problems for the evening."

"And that's all?" Draco asked, before biting down on a strawberry. He'd tilted his head at her and she felt like they were playing a subtle game. This was a discussion about Draco's romantic life - or lack thereof - but they were sitting in the Slytherin table and students slowly streamed into the room. Padma would be walking in any minute now, as would Gregory. And Draco and Daphne were breaking one of the unwritten rules of dating: witches don't conspire with wizards against witches. She just assumed that wizards had a similar rule.

And the people around them had figured out the conversation. Or at least enough. She needed to be obscure enough, to Darmok the conversation.

"Hey, random question, everyone." She spoke up, addressing the table around them. "Which city has the bigger population, Detroit or Milwaukee? And another pair, Edinburgh or Aberdeen? Wait, don't blurt out the answers. Everyone write down your answers. Or whisper them to me." She took out a scroll and quill and passed it around the table.

All of the Bayesian Conspirators had been reading up on cognitive biases and psychology, and Harry had - of course - given them all a different reading list so that they could take turns presenting their findings. For once Daphne knew something before the rest of the Conspiracy and she was going to use it. She got up from the table and leaned over and jotted down the answers that everyone gave, just putting tick marks. Then she went over to the other house tables and repeated the experiment, until she'd gotten enough responses.

She came back and set down the scrolls in front of Draco. "See?"

Gregory, Lesath, Blaise, all looked at the scroll. Tracey Davis, who'd just arrived as Daphne returned, looked over Daphne's shoulder as well, then just walked away.

Detroit: 26, Milwaukee: 5

Aberdeen: 13, Edinburgh:17 (Not sure:1)

Gregory said, "What are the right answers?"

"Oh," Daphne said, "Detroit and Edinburgh. People got it right, which you'd expect. Some people wouldn't know and they'd guess, and some people would know and they'd get the right answer. For things like this - questions of common knowledge - a poll usually gets the right answers. But that's not the interesting thing."

Lesath looked up from the scroll. "We were much more sure about Detroit."

Daphne beamed. "Yes, and that doesn't make sense! Why are we much more sure about an American cities? In both cases the larger city is about twice the population of the smaller one. You'd think we'd know more about ours."

Gregory said "Well, I hadn't heard of Milwaukee. So I figured it was smaller. But I wasn't sure about the other two. I got it right! But it was just a guess."

Daphne nodded. "Yes, when they originally did this experiment, it was in Germany and they used Hannover and Bielefeld as the local cities. And the Germans all knew that Detroit was bigger, but they were pretty evenly divided on the German cities. But when they asked a bunch of Americans, the percentages reversed. All the Americans knew Hanover was bigger. They'd never heard of Bielefled. But only sixty percent of Americans knew Detroit was bigger. Because all the Americans had heard of Milwaukee."

"Weird," said Theodore Nott.

Daphne sat back down next to Draco, speaking softly. "It's called the recognition heuristic. People just assume that things they have heard of are bigger or more important than things they haven't heard of. It's a good rule of thumb, actually. It can lead you astray, of course, but as this example shows people who have more information don't necessarily do better." She took another bite of the pancake. The others were drifting away, as she lectured Draco on psychology.

"The funny thing is the researchers were studying something else. It was a German guy, and the Hanover question was meant to be the easy question and the Detroit one was the hard question. But then the results came back ... and they had a new study."

Daphne leaned over to Draco, "Do you get what I'm trying to tell you?" she asked, glancing round the table and raising an eyebrow questioningly.

Draco had finished the last of his fruit, but chewed slowly on a piece of buttered bread.

"I think I do, Miss Greengrass. I think I do. 'Do not meddle in the affairs of witches...'" He shoved the remaining toast into his mouth. Daphne could hear the end of the quote in her head. For they are subtle and quick to anger. Harry had said that several times over the last year, although with wizards instead of witches.

Draco finished chewing and then leaned over, smiling. "You are right, I wouldn't want too much information. Thanks for your help."

Author's Note - The recognition heuristic study was (accidentally) performed by Goldstein & Gigerenzer in 2001.

Currently Detroit's population is much closer to Milwaukee's, but it has lost 300,000+ people since the 1990 census. Picking UK examples was much tougher, because I don't understand how they define cities vs metropolitan areas. I may have gotten it technically wrong.

Darmok (the Star Trek: Next Generation episode) originally aired on Sept 30, 1991.

Chapter 38: Wargames, Pt 4

Friday night, 8pm

A loud knock on the oaken door and five figures shifted wands to cover it. Colin nodded to Theodore Nott, who said "Who's there?" loudly.

"Harry Potter," came the answer, in Harry's distinctive voice.

Everyone relaxed, but Theodore shook his head. There were traitors. Still, if Potter was a traitor they'd be in big trouble. "Put a slip of your sleeve under the door. Or tell me the password."

"I don't know the password," came the rather arch reply, "and a traitor could know it in any case," but there was a rustling outside the door and a piece of a green cloth appeared under the door for a second, then disappeared. "This isn't a great position out here, you know. Not very defensible." The cloth disappeared. Colin looked around nervously and waved his hand, and Padma rushed over to the door and opened it a crack. Harry Potter slipped in, pushing the mussed hair away from his forehead and taking in the room in glance. Padma closed the door behind Harry.

"So," said Harry, "What do we know?"

Friday night, 8:15 pm

Hermione dived behind the couch, which blocked three Somniums. She probably could have dodged them, she'd dodged multiple spells in practice before. But she'd discussed it with Harry extensively over the week, what they should not reveal about her abilities during the battle. Harry argued they should both sit this out, like they'd resigned their General positions, but his heart hadn't been in it. He'd missed it. If he hadn't been so afraid of revealing Hermione's secrets, he'd still be out there, every battle. But while they could explain away missing classes because of their tutoring, missing all-school events was too much. Hermione already felt the distance between her and other students. Harry had lived with it last year, but he was psychologically distant from most people anyway. Hermione missed the camaraderie.

Harry probably missed it to, judging by how easily he'd given in.

She could hear Ron Weasley moving to flank her while Parvati Patil and Seamus Finnigan kept up a steady stream of spells. She could rush Ron, tackle him and get out of the room, but that would look suspicious. Weasley wasn't a great Wizard, but he was athletic. No, she'd need some other way out. She'd left the Cloak of Invisibility in her room. They definitely wouldn't reveal that, just for a game.

Hermione would reveal an in-game secret.

I bet in Slytherin they are all quietly plotting, she thought, as she looked around the Gryffindor common room for something useful. Probably in Ravenclaw, too. But no, Gryffindors just join up with the nearest group and start attacking.

Although she had to admit that, as strategies went, it was surprisingly hard to argue against. At least, not from her current position of almost being one of the first casualties of war. Hermione poked her head above the couch. Ron had used several large chairs to move over behind a small chess table, that he noisily flipped over, then crouched behind. For some reason he'd ignored the perfectly good shield hanging on the wall behind him. It had belonged to Iucounu the Silent in the sixteen hundreds, who'd used it to defeat a small goblin army singlehandedly.

So of course Gryffindor had claimed him as one of their own, even though he'd never gone to Hogwarts. Apparently the thought of actually using the shield never occurred to Ron. It would easily stop Somnium spells, practically anything would. The shield itself was an older Roman design used by Legionnaires, meant to cover the front lines from attacking archers, and would be quite useful against a variety of spells. She dropped to her hands and knees and then, raising her wand

Accio Shield!

Iucounu's shield lifted off the wall and flew towards her, bowling Ron over and knocking him from out behind the overturned table and into a clearing. She used her left hand to catch the shield edge first and with her right hand cast Somnium on Ron, whose robes turned from a deep purple to crimson red.

Even if Ron had been watching, instead of rolling around grabbing the back of his head where the shield hit, he likely wouldn't have noticed Hermione's coordination. She could hear the surprise from Parvati and Seamus exchanged words, mostly gibberish but she heard the word Accio easily enough. Her instructions had given her a list of spells to pick from. She'd almost gone with Glisseo or Stupefy. But she'd decided Accio would more useful and have the element of surprise, since the summoning charm was normally taught to fourth years.

Now she had to deal with Parvati and Seamus, to keep the element of surprise for as long as possible. That would have been difficult, a minute ago.

Now she had a shield.

Hermione strapped it onto her left arm and started walking towards them.

Saturday, 1 am

Lesath Lestrange watched as Draco talked to his Patronus, a silver Krait whispering in Draco's voice in that bizarre language that the Green Robes spoke. He didn't really trust Draco Malfoy, it was practically too good to be true that one of the cleverest Slytherins also happened to be able to speak the enemy language. On the other hand, the cleverest Slytherin was advising Colin Creevey - or so he'd been informed - so he took his luck where he could get it. Now Draco was speaking to his Patronus, easily understandable as he'd switched back to English.

"Go to each of the Purple leaders, and ask if they have anything to report. Inform them that Slytherin fight goes slowly, we have a lot of rooms in this dungeon and there's a definite advantage to defending, so we're not charging around the place blindly. We could send a team or two if you had some specific requirements," Draco glanced at Lesath, who nodded at this, and Draco continued, "but we'd need to know why. I'm looking for any information you have on identifying traitors. I believe that the password for neutrals secretly loyal to green may be 'Salamander,' but that's not 100%. May just be for Slytherins."

Draco finished up and his Patronus slithered away right through the door, probably towards Ravenclaw first. Lesath resumed his pacing. It had been exciting, drawing the sash of leadership, and he'd spent the first hour rushing around until Draco and Gregory found him and convinced him to hole up. He wasn't in that much danger, he could use any spell he knew - a perk of leadership - and probably nobody else knew their way around the dungeons as well, due to his years of skulking.

But Draco had pointed out that if he kept wandering around he would eventually run into a pack of green Slytherins, and then he'd be in trouble. So they'd set up camp in a defensible position, advertised it widely enough to make sure that people could deliver any information.

"Leadership is much more tedious than I imagined it," Lesath said to Draco.

"The inverse of authority is responsibility. You are in charge, so you can't just go run around and do what you want. I imagine Gregory is having loads of fun right now, flying around. He'll have plenty of excitement and stories on Monday."

"If he doesn't die right away," Lesath added. "Tell me, what's it like, hearing the Green people speak."

"It just sounds like they've got a ridiculous French accent. It's how I can tell they are speaking Green. I need to copy the accent to speak it to them."

"That's actually kind of funny," Lesath said, then fell silent. "Do we have a plan, yet? I think I see one, with the new information we've got. With Percy Weasley killed we have the advantage..."

Draco was shaking his head. "That's a scoreboard advantage, not a positional advantage. Necessary, but not sufficient. Losses on both sides are roughly even among Gryffindors and so the Survivors are abandoning the towers and heading out to just attack purples wherever they can. And you know they'll probably attack us first, once they secure someone that can help guide them down here. Granger's rumoured to have taken out a half dozen of us, and I believe those rumours. They have just the right hint of improbability, if that makes sense. Actually, if they do plan on attacking we could use my room as a base of operations. Those bridges just outside are a natural chokepoint. But a guide will know that..."

Lesath sighed. Draco was just thinking out loud, he didn't need to pay attention. Lesath instinctively knew that Lord Potter would want him to do his best and win this war as purple, despite being on the green side. It would keep people from suspecting that he was Potter's vassal. The experience would strengthen him for the coming years. But he also knew - because everyone knew - that his Lord would try his fullest to win as Green. Lesath had been acquiring power steadily over the last year, but personal power. Magical power. Socially, he still avoided most Slytherins although Potter had asked him to relax and make friends.

Being ordered to make friends didn't make it easier, it felt like being ordered to not think of elephants. The order contradicted the intent.

Lesath realized he'd been ignoring Draco and focused. Draco was still talking about the entrance to the dungeons.

"Draco, How do you learn to become a leader? Is there a crash course you can give me?"

Draco stopped for a second and considered. Lesath felt doubt gnawing at him when Draco replied "Of course I can, but since it's a crash course I'm going to skip details. The first and hardest step is to project confidence. When in doubt, over do it. At least in public..."

Saturday, 7:30 am.

The Great Hall normally bustled during breakfast. A typical Saturday wasn't nearly as busy, many students preferred to sleep in late and just skip breakfast unless there was an early Quiddich game or battle they had to attend. But today's breakfast was particularly sparse. Each table had only a few dozen students sitting at it. The Slytherin table held mainly green robes, and the Gryffindor table at the other end held purple robes only. The two middle tables had mainly neutral robes, or students wearing Red. The dead.

"I'm surprised they aren't in open warfare," Minerva McGonagall said to Professor Lockhart, who sat at her side picking at a small omelet.

"When you were in the order of the Phoenix, you still took time out for meals, as did Death Eaters," he replied, lifting a forkful of eggs into his mouth.

"Not in the same room," she pointed out. "How does it go?"

"Unexpectedly. I'd expected surprises, but Hufflepuffs inflicting the most casualties in their struggle? Hadn't expected that."

"Well, of course they did," said Pomona Spout, who'd shuffled up to the table on the other side of the Headmistress and sat down. "Gilderoy, Minerva. We're the House of Getting Things Done, even if 'Things' are your silly games. If you'd paid attention at all ... but Headmistress, I must protest. The students have broken into the gardens and stolen things."

"I'm sure they will return them once this is over," said Minerva, "won't they, Professor Lockhart?"

Gilderoy Lockhart smiled, full of unabashed delight. "Wonderful! I'd expected them to raid the potions stores and Professor Slughorn set up defenses. Why, young Mr. Vaughn is wearing red robes because of one of Horace's traps, although his compatriots escaped with enough compounds to brew several dozen Pepperup potions ..." he trailed off under Spout's withering glare. "Well, yes, I should have informed you as well, I do apologize, but it honestly slipped my mind. I must admit I was never much for Herbology..."

"I know," said Pomona, coldly.

"Although now that I think about it, I do have some friends who can import some excellent plants and some new books for the library, although we'll have to get them translated from Spanish...but do tell me what they've taken!"

Saturday, 11 am.

Harry had been helping Padma coordinate the Green Gryffindor's assault on Slytherin. They'd tried to smuggle a guide or two out past the purples, but so far they'd all been turned back or killed. Colin's leadership was mixed, at best, but they were muddling along. Several people had openly ignored Colin and waited for Harry to give an order, but he'd just offered advice and backed whatever the Green Leader had ordered. It wasn't a great simulation, having random leaders. But given the short time frame an internal power struggle could be devastating. So, he'd quietly taken aside some dissenters and talked them down. He'd spent several hours last night doing that, which also allowed him to try and feel out who (if anybody) may be a traitor and who just felt annoyed at having to take orders from a first year.

It gave him some empathy for what he'd done to Amelia Bones.

But they'd sorted the situation out and the plans had been going smoothly (if slowly) for several hours. Currently Harry was coordinating the Green Slytherins capable of casting a patronus spells to communicate with the other green factions. They were planning an assault on the Slytherin house. It would be hopeless, nobody from outside would be able to navigate down here, and the bridge itself served as a formidable defensive position. They'd tried to sneak some people out to help, but they'd been unsuccessful. Still, Harry's proposed plan had been accepted. Now they were just coordinating. They needed to time the assault with their attack on the other side of the bridge, and have both go simultaneously with a feint against Lestrange's room.

Coordinating these things was infuriatingly slow.

Harry had been proposing noon when he saw Peregrine Derrick start to cast. Harry shouted and had his wand out, but Nott stood between him and Derrick. Harry didn't have a shot, so he pointed his wand at Colin and shouted Expelliarmus. Colin's wand flew out of his hand right before Derrick's Stupefy hit him squarely in the back. Then Harry hit the floor and rolled, everyone had their wands out and spells were flying. Harry shouted "Take him alive!" and then cast Expelliarmus at Derrick and saw his wand go flying. Chaotic Theodore - Harry still thought of him that way, even though he was in Basilisk now - had managed to jump on the loose wand and now had it pointed at Derrick, who had his hands up and stood motionless.

Colin Creevey lay sprawled across the floor, his robes were bright red but there was no sash on them. Harry looked down at his own robes and their new adornment.

"It worked!" said Peregrine Derrick, "Although I thought I would be leader, that doesn't matter. Harry's better at this than I am, but the important thing is that now we aren't hampered by that sniveling little"

"So, you are saying you aren't the traitor?" Padma asked, beating Harry to the punch.

"Obviously. The green leader isn't dead. Just look," said Peregrine, lowering his hands. He didn't have a wand, so there was no point. "If a player kills their own leader, that isn't a death. Just a change of command. I mean, obviously its still a death, and I'm sorry, but Colin wasn't a great loss..."

Harry thought about it. He'd vetted Peregrine, and didn't believe he'd been a traitor. Of course, that could be biasing him right now, he didn't want to admit that he could be wrong. But Peregrine was an obvious candidate for being a traitor, since he spoke Purple, one of the few bilingual wizards they had. But Peregrine had volunteered the information, and provided useful information for the last twelve hours. Information that Harry had taken pains to confirm independently.

"How did you know it would work?" Harry asked, and everyone fell silent.

"Well, I overheard some Purples when they were coming back from the fourth level restroom, the one a few halls away from where they've set up shop. They are planning on getting rid of Lestrange. He's not very popular, as you know. They didn't know that I was hiding and they were just going to take command."

"I see. And they weren't just putting on a show for you?"

"No, they were speaking in Purple. Even if they knew I was there, they weren't speaking to me. Gregory was warning Draco not to try a coup..."

"Draco?" Harry cast his mind back to last night after the lottery, at the weird way Draco had acted. He groaned and almost slapped his forehead.

"Yeah, he said he'd just stupefy Lesath later on, maybe after lunch and blame some random green person. Look, I could only hear them for a minute or two, and they were being quiet so that nobody else could hear them, so it was good information. I knew if I told you, Harry, you'd just try to talk me out of it or kill me as a traitor, but we had to get rid of Colin. No offense."

He directed the last bit towards Colin Creevey, who had gotten shakily up to his feet and walked over to grab his wand. He couldn't speak, of course, but he glared at Peregrine Derrick as he snatched the wand of the floor and stomped out. Harry called out an apology, to no avail. Then he said "Wait!" and Colin's retreating form stopped.

Harry turned to Peregrine. "I don't think you were a traitor, Peregrine. And honestly, it wasn't even stupid, just an honest mistake. I don't think you are a traitor. Somnium." Peregrine Derrick crumpled to the ground, and his robes were bright red before he hit the floor. "But we can't let people we're supposed to to trust do things like that." Harry walked over to Chaotic Theodore and took Derrick's wand and flipped it over to Colin. "When he wakes up I'll tell him to find you to get his wand back. I'm sorry Colin."

Colin caught the wand, but he was still gritting his teeth. Padma looked at Harry then Colin, putting it together. "Harry could have taken command whenever he wanted to. He only did it when you were going to be killed in any case. Maybe you should be mad it him, but nobody else saw it coming either." She moved away from the body on the ground. Nobody moved to wake up Peregrine Derrick as Colin Creevey walked off, shoulders slouched.

Chapter 40: Chess and other Wargames

Saturday, 10pm.

Draco Malfoy bolted upright as Harry flew through the doorway, wand out, firing spells rapidly into each corner of the room. Harry saw one spell fizzle - hitting the ward - in front of Draco's bewildered face before landing on his cot beside the door. Harry lifted up his head and looked around the room, empty save for his blond roommate.

"Sorry if I woke you, Draco," Harry said. Harry had been awake since 6pm last night, having adjusted his sleep schedule in preparation for the wargame. He'd been up nearly twenty eight hours at this point and wasn't tired yet, but with the battle still raging inside the dungeons he needed to get ready. Harry didn't trust any place without serious warding and dare not wait until sleep started pounding his judgement like a snare drum, so he'd arrived in bed early.

Normally his extra long sleep cycle was an advantage, if you had a time turner at least, but Harry couldn't stretch out multiple all-nighters with only cat naps. Others had offered him time to sleep, during the small pause after the Battle of Slytherin Bridge, but his body just didn't work like that. He needed a long break. Harry was going to crash, and soon. Draco stared at Harry's sash and said something, shaking his head.

"Oh, come off it Draco. I know you understand me," Harry said. Draco cocked his head and shrugged, his gesture clearly saying I don't know.

Harry raised his voice so that anyone nearby could hear him. "So, I talked to The-Girl-Who-Revived about your date, and she mentioned some interesting facts about flower arrangements. I hadn't realized..."

"OK, OK," Draco said. "Just. Sheesh. Keep a sense of proportion. I thought I'd done well. What did I do wrong?"

"Even you need feedback to figure out how to trip up people spying on you. I could believe you'd feed random misinformation to spies. It's not a huge stretch to imagine that anyone who tried to spy on you would understand you, although that would be much more obvious to someone who was bilingual. No, your plan to convince Derrick to kill Colin Creevey was too inspired. He already wanted to do it, he'd been chafing at working for a first year. You overheard their grumbling, and your plan felt absolutely perfect. Then I remembered when the spell first hit. You kept looking to Gregory to see how he was acting, like you weren't sure what was going on. If you actually didn't understand me, that would be one thing. But you did and Gregory didn't, so you had to gauge your reaction. I should have known then, but I missed it. Once I found it it was you that Derrick conveniently overheard, I was almost certain. And now you just spoke to me in Green which is pretty good proof, considering."

Harry smirked at the last few words.

"So, if I hadn't spoken up just now and was actually innocent, you'd blab about Hermione to everyone." Draco adjusted his pillow so that he could lean back comfortably against the wall, then folded his hands across his chest. "Just to try and confirm it."

"I was ... 95% certain," Harry said, shrugging. "And there's nobody out in the hall to overhear. But you had a good plan. Tell me, did you know that it was possible to coup a leader?"

"I'd heard a rumour to that effect. Hadn't confirmed it, but that didn't matter. Just my luck that you actually had that tidbit of information. Who told you?"

"Started with it. But that isn't nearly as lucky as starting out bilingual. This war would have wrapped up three hours ago if I'd had that. War's chaotic uncertainty, you have to love it. Anyway, sorry if I woke you," Harry said. Draco just harrumphed.

"I wasn't asleep yet," he said. "But I was in the area and felt better safe than sorry. I'm pretty tired, I didn't catch any breaks last night. You?"

"Nope," Harry yawned. Draco hadn't slept much Thursday night either, not that Harry could remember. "You haven't been sleeping well."

"Too interesting to sleep."

"I meant in general, you haven't been sleeping well. Is everything OK? I mean you could take a Doorahkah potion, it doesn't keep you under, like the regular sleeping draught, but I'm told it makes it helps you fall asleep. It's not that potent, just the wizarding equivalent of warm milk."

"I hadn't heard of that," said Draco. "Is it easy to make?"

"Not too difficult. We've got the gubba nub nub plants on campus. Well, we did as of two days ago, I'm not sure we do now. We could brew up a pretty decent supply in a day or two. Maybe monday afternoon?"

"That sounds good," Draco said. "Although now I'm not really tired. Having someone fly into your room Auror Woo-style, all jumping sideways and firing blindly does that to me. A game of chess?"

"Sure." Draco set down his wand and leaned over to his desk. He was still on his cot, just grabbing pieces. He took a chess board and tossed it down to the middle of the room, where it landed with a dull splat. Harry put down his wand, his chess pieces were under his cot, and he reached under it until he felt the bag. "You know, I have no idea how the Babel spell affects this."

"I just assumed they'd understand us. But I think it will work. After all, they are tied to us." Draco carefully emptied his bag of pieces on the floor and then said something that Harry couldn't understand. A few of Draco's green pieces grumbled backtalk, but they all started trudging away from Draco's cot to the middle of the room and taking their assigned positions on the chess board. Harry carefully leaned down and rolled his pieces out of the bag and told them to go to the board.

The silver King just looked up at him and said "At this hour? Surely you jest!"

"I'm not kidding, and stop calling me Shirley," Harry said, pointing to the board. His pieces started the long march. Draco watched them moving slowly across the floor, like regal metallic roaches spreading out towards the board.

"I assume, Harry being Potter and all, that you've already come up with a plan on how you are going to get out of bed in the morning," Draco said. Most of his pieces were already on the board, since it had landed closer to his side of the room and they'd gotten a head start. They were now calling out to the silver pieces, exhorting them to hurry up, but neither side's chessmen could understand the other, so they eventually got bored when their enemy ignored them and quieted down. A few of his pieces fell asleep where they stood.

"It's not like I'd tell you what it was. I have a few options, of course. I'm not going through the pool, if that's what you are asking. I'm not exactly sure what happened, but I've got a few theories. It's like the sunlight potion ... I don't need to know exactly what you did to know it's a bad idea."

Draco chuckled in the maniacal fashion Harry sometimes did, then said "Pawn to Queen Four, please." He actually said it twice, once in gibberish for his pieces, and then translated for Harry's sake. He had to repeat the command a few times, but his queen pawn hopped forward twice. Harry couldn't recall pawns hopping before, they usually just walked. Maybe it was punch-drunk because of the time.

"How's Lesath doing? I mean, in general, nothing specific. Pawn to Queen Four, let's just go with a conservative game for now."

"Oh, he's doing fine. I mean, he doesn't really command respect but neither did Colin. Lesath's ... a solid performer. You know how our House is, Lesath's old enough and talented enough that we tolerate him. If Derrick hadn't been hopped up he'd have realized my plan to take out Lestrange would generate more ill will in the real world than any amount of glory I'd gain this weekend. But if he were clever he wouldn't be a bully. Pawn to Queen Bishop Four. Chop chop! Wake up! Lesath's got a good tactical grasp of the situation. He reminds me of Snape, in some ways. Obviously without the experience but he could blossom."

Harry wanted a simple game, since he could feel himself getting tired. He probably shouldn't have agreed to this. "Pawn takes pawn. That's good to hear. I don't think Colin took the coup very well, though. I did what I could to make it better."

"It's just a battle. Do you want me to talk with him? I teach monday's lecture and I could ... Oh, I teach monday's lecture! How am I going to have time to prepare? Anyway, I can pull him aside. I mean, we've all been there, losing a battle stings no matter how it happens. Pawn to king four."

The game proceeded. By now Harry and Draco were both good enough to avoid blunders, so each focused on limiting the other's options while accumulating small advantages. Enough small advantages would become a big advantage. A big advantage forced the other player into a defensive position, to answer threats with forced responses. And it was easy to plan, when your opponent's moves were all forced. Until then, the game felt equal.

"Being murdered by a non-traitor on your side who seriously thought he was doing the right thing? That has to hurt."

"Lockhart shouldn't have made everything random. Let the teams pick their leader, or something. And he should have probably limited magical devices," Draco said as the game moved from opening into middle game, "there were a couple of close calls that I'm aware of."

"I think the Headmistress will fix that flaw for next time," said Harry. If there is a next time.

Sunday 7.45 am

The Great Hall, significantly fuller than yesterday, turned as Draco Malfoy strode forcefully into the Hall, Nimbus in hand. Each of his footfalls had an accompanying squish and his brilliant purple robes dripped profusely even though he'd stopped to wring them out. He kept carefully to the purple side of the room - thankfully the unwritten truce had held for another day. The two center tables of red-robed students erupted into laughter.

Apparently the edict against dead people talking didn't apply to laughter. Draco ignored them all as he squished his way to the main table and Professor Lockhart, who had the good taste to have a somber face.

"Professor, since unauthorized spells result in disqualification," Draco said, spreading his arms wide, "I was wondering if I could ask you a favor."

Professor Lockhart took out his wand and wordlessly passed it across Draco's form, at which point the robes instantly dried and even felt pleasantly warm for a change. He leaned down and said, somewhat quietly, "The Hot Air charm has it's uses, but if you live in a jungle for any time you'll want to be more efficient. It's not completely simple, but if you'd like I can show you how to cast that later this week."

"Thank you, Professor," Draco said loudly and walked - footfalls sounding normal - back to the purple table. He put down his broom, took a plate, and some food.

"What happened?" Neville asked.

Draco finished chewing his piece of grapefruit. It provided a not-unpleasant shock, now that he was dry. "Well, I woke up and Gregory was sprawled out in the middle of our floor, robes red. Harry probably set some guards on the room for when I left, and they must have surprised him, and they didn't bother waking him up. I guess they were afraid that Harry or I had trapped the room."

"And did you?" asked Daphne Greengrass. She wasn't a purple robe, she was neutral, but this was also the Slytherin table. She hadn't done anything overtly biased, but Draco had made sure he could keep her in his field of view.

Draco noticed that the red robes on the next Hufflepuff table were following the conversation intently, but just shrugged. "Nothing extravagant. But anyway, Gregory's broom wasn't out which meant it was still at the bottom of the pool so I managed to get in to there and get through the tunnel and burst out of the water. They had guards, but they were sleeping and I guess they hadn't expected someone to come out of the water. Anyway, I got past them and here I am. What's the situation?"

"I don't think either side is going to eliminate the others leaders by dinner," said Neville. "Both Slytherin leaders are still alive, Katie Bell is still running Purple in Gryffindor, and Roger Davies is running Green in Ravenclaw."

"Davies," said Draco, "I though it was, uh," he paused, blanking on the name, "Hillard. The one who was held back a year?"

"Yeah, Davies overthrew him last night," said Neville. "Word got out after Harry took command from Colin."

"It wasn't like that," said Daphne, "Harry wouldn't do that."

Draco agreed internally, but Daphne's defense of Harry seemed odd. Draco would expect a neutral to be careful when complementing the enemy's leader. Doing that implied complete confidence, and honestly Draco didn't trust everyone at this table who wore purple. How could Daphne be so sure she wasn't executed as a spy? Draco looked up from his grapefruit as the far doors burst open and a dozen greens ran into the room, wands out.

"Run," Draco yelled and jumped up from the table. He grabbed the broom, tossed it in front of him while saying "Up" and jumped onto it in one smooth motion. (He'd actually practiced that with Gregory during martial arts. It really only saved a second or two from a standing start, but everyone agreed it looked amazing). He flew for the near door and then realized he'd have guarded it before sending in a huge number of visible troops, so he swerved away just before it opened, revealing more green troops. Draco saw Daphne fire a stupefy into Neville's back so he Somnumed her and she sprawled onto the ground, her robes flickered to green briefly, before turning red. No wonder she'd been projecting confidence. It was just an act. Many red robed students sitting in the middle tables raised personal shields, not to affect the battle but just to make sure that they weren't shot by accident.

Draco yelled "We need to," but didn't finish. Several spells impacted on him at once and as he crashed into the Slytherin table, his last thought was Realism is overrated.

Author's Note - it has been pointed out that the Fidelus Charm isn't really HPMOR canon. Lockhart/Harry used the name ("Fidelus") as a descriptive shorthand to indicate "safety." I have updated this chapter accordingly. It was not my intent to divert from canon.

Chapter 42: Surprise

Saturday

High inside Hogwarts a boy with a lightning shaped scar on his forehead sat on his desk, looking out the window across the landscape instead of working.

It wasn't the highest point view from inside the castle. He'd spent a full day last October trying to determine where the castle's highest point was. Finding his effort frustrated at every third turn - literally frustrated by staircases with several non-existent but visible steps that he'd nearly fallen through, and strong gusts of wind that shoved him ruthlessly but harmlessly back down - the boy decided to merely assume that a highest point in Hogwarts existed and gave up trying to find it.

Mathematically, this should be obvious. Every structure had a highest point (or points).

But this boy had encountered enough violations of supposedly axiomatic laws that he wasn't entirely convinced that two plus two equaled four everywhere in the wizarding world, much less Fermat's theorem of stationary points. Harry Potter didn't know exactly how high you could go and still be inside Hogwarts, but he was currently looking down on a flock of geese flying over the Forbidden Forest, fifty feet above the trees to avoid the Acromantula webs.

He'd created a small clearing before sitting on his desk, shoving papers aside. The clutter had grown slowly and haphazardly over the fall. Despite Hogwarts being one of the seats of the wizarding world, most of the clutter consisted of books, not scrolls. His trunks stored the vast majority of Harry's books, but he'd brought the most useful references upstairs to save himself numerous trips and those dominated the scrolls, parchments, official reports that passed from the magical government of Britain to him for review. Already read items were scattered among the ever-increasing number of bookshelves lining his room high above Hogwarts (if they possessed some redeeming value or fact Harry thought he'd need) or tossed unceremoniously into the fire place (if they didn't). Some books on his desk were those that he needed to read quickly, so that he could return them to the library before Madam Pince noticed they were missing.

It was obvious to anyone who paid attention that Harry Potter was not a normal student at Hogwarts. He still preferred not to draw attention to it, so Harry simply took the books he needed then returned them – hopefully unmissed – at a later date. It wasn't really stealing, after all. Headmaster Dumbledore had given him Hogwarts, although part of Harry knew it wasn't Dumbledore's to give. In any case Hogwarts didn't appear to mind. Still, the first time he'd snuck into the restricted section and swiped a few books from the shelves, he'd gotten a small thrill even though he knew that he hadn't broken the wards, they just didn't register his actions as theft. The wards merely shrugged instead of screaming and trapping him in an inky black tar, like they did for regular students.

Try as he might, Harry hadn't convinced Hermione to read any books from the restricted section. She'd said there would be time enough later and that she still had plenty of "good" magic to learn thank you very much and then she'd turned up her nose at him, swiveling her chair around to face the other direction and planting said nose back into the Advanced Potion Making book she was re-reading for the second time.

Harry Potter still wasn't sure if that counted as flirting or not.

Scattered in between his reference books, borrowed books and slowly growing collection of interesting magical artifacts a scroll rested. More specifically, a map. Very specifically, a magical map that accurately drew Hogwarts and its occupants then magically erased and re-draw their updated positions, as well as the ever changing campus itself. People's names appeared next to small footstep icons as they walked, ran, snuck or otherwise moved around campus. Harry had flown a broom around campus while staring at the map, but it still portrayed his motion with little icons that any illustrator would recognize as 'footprints,' despite the fact that he'd been flying and his feet never touched the ground.

The Maurader's Map intrigued Harry. It provided a reasonable and - as far as Harry could tell - true depiction of Hogwarts and its inhabitants. The question that Harry had spent a few percent of his spare time investigating: How?

As fields of science went, Information Theory had barely gotten out of diapers. Claude Shannon had figuratively conjured the entire field into existence when he published "The Mathematical Theory of Communication" at the famous Bell Labs shortly after the Second World War. Harry Potter hadn't mastered the maths necessary to fully grasp the work, but he'd read enough commentary to understand the basics of how information worked.

In Harry's brief forays into investigating the intersection between science and magic, only Information Theory had come away unscathed. Some branches of magic respected conservation laws, but generally Magic regarded Science like the boring killjoy you avoided at a party. Sometimes Magic grumbled and said a polite hello but usually Magic ignored Science and did whatever it wanted to.

Magic was Oscar Madison to Science's Felix Ungar.

But Information Theory? So far, Harry hadn't seen any magical violations of its rules.

Magic seemed to have bandwidth that, if not infinite, was big enough to not matter as a practical concern. In any case, divination didn't use much bandwidth, most spells didn't seem to use much. Transfiguration probably used the most, but estimating how much was a tricky matter. Magic had relatively good signal strength. But there was no reason – in theory – that communication channels had to be noisy. (Harry had posited that Divination's relatively useless nature was somehow encrypting information in a way to prevent noise from affecting it, unlike the rest of magic. But he had no way to test this). In any case Technology had made impressive gains on reducing noise, so magic's signal strength was not a theoretical concern.

If information theory failed, Harry suspected it would by violating the restriction on moving faster than light. Given the existence of time turners there were probably some modifications to Shannon's theory, and the possibility of sending information faster than light would be of pressing importance, once humanity spread to multiple planets. Harry hoped that magic violated that rule, it would be useful. But so far this one branch of science had avoided Magic's lecherous advances and sly come-ons. It remained pure, unbroken by magic.

That surprised Harry, but Information implies Surprise. After all, if someone told you a fact that didn't surprise you at all, you already knew it.

Part of the proof that English has redundancy built into it was that if you named the letters of a plaintext message one at a time, people could guess the next letter much more often than random chance dictated. Similarly with the words. If you asked any American to say the next word in the phrase 'The President of the United' then most would say 'States.'

"States" wouldn't surprise them. "Auto" would be surprising, except at a union rally.

As far as Harry could tell, the Marauder's Map had been the rare surprise for Voldemort during his year at Hogwarts. Not only had he not known of its existence, he'd been doubly surprised that the map printed 'Tom Riddle' for him. It hadn't shown Harry's legal name, or the name given him by his parents, or the name he called himself. It somehow knew that he was an imprint of Tom Riddle.

That was a disturbingly compelling argument for the concept of souls. Not as a religious concept but as an actual mental state, albeit only an initial state. For the time being, Harry had shoved aside the more complex philosophical questions and focused on what other information the Map could convey. It could be a profoundly useful security device. The map could detect invisible intruders – Alastor had tried a number of spells, but he showed up on the map at all times. Hermione disappeared when hidden under her Deathly Hallow, but otherwise people were clearly labeled. Harry had also wondered if the Map – which recognized Harry's origins before he had – could tell if someone was under an external influence. However, experimentation had shown that imperiused subjects were labelled as themselves, not their controller.

Harry had felt a twinge of guilt, having Minerva confiscate the Map from the Twins, although he'd at least made sure their memories were restored. But he needed to experiment with it. He'd have it 'accidentally' returned later. Even with its limitations, the Map could revolutionize security. Once Harry figured out how to replicate it, anyway.

Harry built Peverell adjacent to Hogwarts, connected at the infirmary, but it was not part of Hogwarts proper, which meant it didn't show up on the Map. Harry had wanted them separate for logistical reasons and to keep people from asking too many questions – which was another reason he'd reluctantly asked the Headmistress to confiscate the Map – but once Harry understood this device that could detect invisible intruders he'd announced that Peverell was part of Hogwarts. Then he'd decreed it. Then he'd had a law passed to that effect.

The Map didn't care, or show any of the new addition. Whatever logic it used to decide what to show, the map didn't seem influenced by politics or what people said. It didn't matter that Harry Potter felt like Harry Potter, to the map he was Tom Riddle. It didn't care that Harry called Peverell part of Hogwarts.

Harry's experiments – and thousands of galleons to pay wizarding craftsmen – had let him develop 'his' map he used for the Muggle Naval Simulation. The displaying was the easy part. He'd just gotten some computer programs to run the simulation (using thousands of dollars to pay programmers) and his map reflected the reality of the program.

But that information existed on a concrete level – on a computer monitor, or in the hard drive. Sure, the Marauder's map looked at people on the grounds. But how did it see into him? How did it see the invisible? Was it the same way that the Sorting Hat worked? Harry didn't expect an answer soon.

Good research – by definition – was full of surprises.

At this moment Harry idly studied the Great Hall. It was lunch time, which meant that most of the students were in the great hall. The sheer number of names meant that the map couldn't show them all. Rather, it could, but they'd fill up the entire Hallway with ink, so the Map didn't. Harry wondered how it decided. Did it have some intelligence, like the Hat? If so, who did it borrow it from? Or did it just work on simple rules. You could get surprisingly subtle and complex behavior from a few simple rules.

Harry had been tinkering with the map most of the morning. He was supposed to be dealing with the Wizengamot and the political fallout that was starting to happen because people weren't dying as much as they used to. Other countries were becoming concerned about their political power in this suddenly changed world. Harry wished that he'd gotten Hari Seldon when he'd recruited Professor Asimov. Figuring out the future history was beyond him, beyond anyone. So he was just muddling along, trying to smooth things out.

He'd taken a break to play with the map because he was bored and procrastinating. He'd almost resolved to get back to looking at the correspondence that had come from Casciora, a parliament of Romanian Witches, when something struck him. The students had been filing out of the Great Hall, which now was almost empty. He'd seen them streaming out through various doors, names appearing once they were far enough apart that they could be distinguished. Harry had spent the morning tracking people around, trying to think of clever security tricks or how he'd hide from the Map, if he suspected someone was watching him. If he could do that, he could return it sooner. But as he'd been thinking about this, something about the lunchtime crowd struck him. Harry pushed his glasses back up the bridge of his nose.

"Show me my room," Harry said. And the scene shifted, scrolling smoothly, and Harry saw his room, empty. Lesath was walking through the Slytherin Commons room by himself, apparently heading back to his room. Harry glanced at the clock on the wall, it was a bit after 1pm. There was a Quiddich game scheduled, Ravenclaw versus Hufflepuff.

"Show me the bleachers, Slytherin seating." Harry examined the names quickly, then shifted over to the Hufflepuff stands, just in case. Lots of people, but not who he was hunting.

"Show me the library," Harry said. Hermione was there, of course. Her unmoving name was scrawled elegantly next to her favorite table. Madam Pince and a few students, mostly fifth years, walked around the stacks. Harry studied the map for another second.

"Fine," Harry said, more to himself than the map. "Show me Draco Malfoy."

The map erased itself, just a blank piece of parchment.

"Huh," Harry said to himself, surprised.

A few minutes earlier.

A man, hair tangled in thick curls, with mutton chop sideburns steps up into the carriage, almost tripping because he cannot keep his eyes on the small step of the entrance, but is looking towards the front, at the horrific beasts tethered to the carriage that only he can see.

Draco turned his head from the window he'd been staring out of, at the front of Hogwarts and gives a slight nod to the man. "Thank you again for this, Isaac. I know it's an imposition on your day off, and I appreciate it."

"It's no trouble at all, Draco. Frankly I welcome the chance to get out and about. It's not that anyone is rude, or impolite. But I really feel like a movie shooting victim when I'm on that campus." Professor Asimov laughed and Draco realized there was probably some joke.

"I'm afraid I don't get it," Draco said. With other people he'd force a wan smile or just nod, but given the cultural differences Draco considered it better to just admit ignorance and learn from it. In this situation at least. The carriage gave a small jostle as it started off.

"Ah, a fake gunshot in movies is done with a packet of fake blood and a small explosive, referred to as a 'squib.'"

"That's actually clever," Draco said, smiling.

"Unlike the rest of my jokes, you mean?" Professor Asimov had an artificially dour look on his face.

"Exactly." They both laughed.

"Tell me, Draco, what are the beasts that are pulling this carriage?"

"What animals?" Draco said.

"They look like … two skeletal pegasus."

"Pegasus...," Draco screwed up his face, thinking. "That's a breed of winged horse, isn't it? And skeletal." Draco reached into his robes and pulled out a small black notebook, opened it, then spoke to it. "Reminder for later, research skeletal winged horses that children cannot see." The words appeared in an elegant handwriting. Draco closed the book and slipped it back into his robes.

"Quite a useful device," Professor Asimov said.

"More convenient than a scroll, but basically the same idea as a Self Writing Quill, except the spell is on the book, not the writing instrument. I'll look this up later and see what I find, although I suspect you could just ask the groundskeeper."

Draco did look up Thestrals later, his diary sketching a horrifying image. The fact this his research would take no longer than a minute was something he felt slightly guilty about, but he gave no outward sign of discomfort.

"I hope it's not much trouble but, thank you Draco. Much like this trip, which you view as a burden to me, but I'm actually happy to get out and about, and some slight errands along the way pose no real issue. I do have something for you." He handed a slim paperback book to Draco, who flipped it over.

"Nine Tomorrows," he read. By Isaac Asimov.

"I particularly recommend Gentle Vultures to you. Your speech to Gilderoy's class after that last war reminded me of the story. Not the writing or plot, but the general moral nature."

"You heard about the speech?"

"Professors Lockhart and Slughorn discussed it at some length, and in some detail. Professor Lockhart, in particular, seemed impressed with your insight and said that it showed surprising moral development."

Professor Asimov smiled as they passed underneath the gate to the entrance of Hogwarts.

Six days earlier.

Professor Asimov took one bite of Dragon Tartare and made a face. Gilderoy was still speaking "... it was gripping, as you'd expect from a Malfoy, but what astonished me was that he showed surprising moral development for a Slytherin."

"What do you mean 'for a Slytherin?'" Horace dropped his fork and leaned over, practically placing his chest onto the table. That got the attention of the entire head table, most of whom had been ignoring yet another speech by the Professor of Offenses against the Social Arts, as Professor Trewlaney dubbed him.

"Well, its just that you don't often hear about the glories of protecting the innocent and tales for the fallen from Slytherin. I mean, a speech about the nobility of those who died in war seems right for Hufflepuff."

At this moment Pomona Spout tossed her fork down on the table, which clattered loudly against her plate. "Oh, so we're victims, not like the heroic Gryffindors," she said. Professor Lockhart's smile wavered for a second, and he was about to speak when the Headmistress gently set down her spoon.

"I'm sure he didn't mean it that way, Did you?" Headmistress McGonagall cocked her head gently towards Professor Lockhart.

"No, of course not. What I meant to say. That is, the idea that good and noble soldiers die all the time is a common theme that applies to everyone. And since the outcome of the battle doesn't affect the moral nature of the combatant. Well, those facts seems like just the sort of thing that Helga Hufflepuff would agree with." Pomona sniffed dismissively, while he continued. "And while I don't think that Rowena Ravenclaw would dispute the fact that being clever in war is no guarantee of survival, I don't recall her ever saying anything to that effect."

Gilderoy Lockhart kept talking before anyone could interrupt, because he couldn't actually recall anything that Rowena Ravenclaw had ever said, and didn't want to learn at this time. In fact, he'd somewhat lost the train of thought as to why he was defending himself. After another sentence or two he remembered.

"And I'm sure that Salazar also knew what Draco said, but he didn't really emphasize it. Whereas Gryffindors have more history with heroic failure than most, because we tend to leap before we look. We don't have to dig deeply into our history to see our heroes die fairly often. Oh, we sing about the winners more than remember the losers, but the lesson is there. That's all I that I meant. Do you see what I'm saying, Horace?"

"I see you have no idea what you are talking about. You carry your simplistic view of the world and forsake nuance. Do you want to know the burden of House Slytherin? Well, I'll tell you anyway, not to enlighten you but because you deserve to shoulder the weight. We know that the dead who rot in the streets may not have been innocent, we know that you cannot reduce people to songs you sing about them when you get drunk. We know the world isn't black and white, but merely shades of grey."

"You call me a fool for seeing only two colours, then reduce it to one!" The headmistress started to speak, but Horace jabbed his pudgy finger into the puffy finery worn by Gilderoy Lockhart and poked him twice while speaking.

"Not one, infinite. You blame us for the last two decades because you are ignorant. Slytherin is the house that traditionally stops most wars. We murder them when they are babies, strangle them in their cribs or snap their beautiful necks and then go off to console their parents. Sometimes we fail, then we fight them when they are fully grown. We prefer to murder their pregnant mothers, no matter how pretty the young woman may be. And we don't go marching off with some foolish bird on our shoulder singing to us. We make hard choices, because we understand. Albus understood. He ordered people to die and did it knowingly, and it almost destroyed him. Could you do that? No, you'd just rush in yourself and fight for glory and die whether it won the war or not. Would you let Albus order you to your death? Of course you would, because you'd never imagine anything but victory and it wouldn't be prudent for Dumbledore to mention otherwise. No, the curse of my house is that we know that you cannot deal with the world you actually live in, so you tell yourself lies."

Professor Horace Slughorn shoved back from the table so violently that his chair topped over. Several students saw that, and saw his face red with rage even though no raised voices could be heard.

"Your problem, Gilderoy, is that you've only learned from your own experience. Enough to be here, but you only know Slytherins from your past. And it isn't pretty, I'll grant you. It's dark. But due to your nature you'll be outclassed by our students soon enough, because they learn from other people's mistakes. That's why you can't conceive that Draco Malfoy has learned the wisdom of war without having ever been in a real battle, because you've never learned anything by thinking and you can't imagine we Slytherins do."

As Horace Slughorn stormed away, meal uneaten, it occurred to Gilderoy Lockhart that he'd never seen a Slytherin get truly angry before.

Author's Note - If you haven't left a review on , please consider it. I'm getting paid in ego.

Chapter 44: Release

Delay is the strongest form of Denial - Lucius Malfoy

"I'm sorry if I kept you waiting, Professor." Draco slid easily into the opposite chair of the Leaky Cauldron, then caught the eye of the barmaid that Isaac had been flirting with for the last half hour. To some avail, Isaac thought, and chuckled. Then the chair next to him skidded noisily and Augusta Longbottom dropped into the chair, loudly dropping a purse that could hold a medium sized cauldron onto the table.

"You know, there's something to this entire rejuvenation business. I would never have been able to deal with that arrogant snit's pleasant demeanor last year. I'd be too tired, and he'd be too respectful, 'Madam Longbottom, why don't you sit down?' and 'Can I get you any tea?' But now that I'm young, they just sneer and look down at me. And they underestimate me, isn't that delightful, Draco? Enjoy that while you can. It shan't last long."

The waitress Arianna came to the table, not as friendly as she had been a few moments ago. "I shall get simply plastered with all the wine you've got, dear," said Augusta.

Arianna looked dubious, and Draco ordered a butterbeer.

"No problem at all. Augusta dropped me off here and I've explored Diagon Alley all afternoon. I'd just ordered my dinner. So, your mission was a success?"

"They didn't let me in, if that's what you are asking. But yes, I think it was a success." Augusta stopped fidgeting to fix Draco with a look, which spared Isaac the problem of asking for clarification. "It was just a hunch. I don't know that there would be something important in the Hall of Prophecy, but I had a ... feeling. It may be important, Originally I just wanted to rule it out. But they are so obstinate about hiding something, they brought out the big guns to stop me."

"The clerk?" Isaac laughed. "That boy looked absolutely petrified. You can't mean him."

"No. They just kept stringing me along. He'd never define all the steps he had to fulfill. He just set up an obstacle, and when I passed it, he set up the next one. Always apologetic. 'I'm very s-s-s-sorry, Lord Malfoy' and 'Well, there is this other regulation, you see.' Why, if I didn't have to run by my vault for some business – thank you again Madam Longbottom for that. You didn't really need to stay for the whole day."

Delay is the strongest form of denial. Father taught that lesson yearly. If you told someone 'no,' they'd act against you. But if you could drag out the decision you may be able to placate them. Or they'd just lose interest or hope or find some other more pliable target. Sometimes they'd even just forget. You could eventually impose enough cost to make your adversary drop the matter. Father had also taught him the dangers, if you were ever uncovered.

Draco had been on the other side today.

And now you see just how dangerous it is to play that game, Draco heard in Lucius voice. They've confirmed your idle hunch, and even now you are planning to act. Not impetuously, I hope?

"You don't need to convince me that it's important, Draco. I want to make sure we are fully quit with that foul would-be-imperator. Voldemort, not the clerk." Her words had a harsh quality, and to Isaac could just imagine that Augusta Longbottom was secretly all three Greek Furies. She'd just changed from the Atropos - the crone that kills - into Clotho, who spins the web into life. But just as soon as she finished her words, practically spitting, she smiled and was a young lady again.

It was an odd effect, but Isaac had started to get used to it. Arianna came back with the drinks and Augusta took her wine glass, drained it in one motion, set it back on the serving tray, and leaned over to him and said "And what did you do today, hmmm?" she said, batting her eyes at him.

Headmistress McGonagall pulled her head out of the Pensieve and sat thinking for several moments.

Amelia Bones, hair brown with streaks of grey since her youthening last summer, had been sitting at her desk, quill scritching out memoranda, not wasting any time. She didn't look up as Minerva finished the memory, just kept writing. How Albus Dumbledore had done anything as Chief Warlock while also managing Hogwarts was beyond her. Actually, everyone felt either so afraid of him they didn't interfere, or so inspired by him that they did all the work he didn't have time for, she thought. But I inspire little fear or loyalty. She kept writing.

"Well, now I know why he gave up his cane so easily. He could summon it back at any time," Minerva's voice sounded resigned.

"The memory goes on for several more hours. Madam Longbottom comes back soon after that. She only left to be polite to your Professor and take him to Diagon Alley. We sent Aurors to confirm that. She returned quickly, along with Xenophilius Lovegood and the Lady Greengrass. Honestly if that boy had any idea where the Hall of Prophecy was, he'd have marched them straight to it by the end."

"Poor Harrod," said Minerva, "Always so eager to please. This must have been terribly trying for him."

"Well, Draco didn't berate him. If I'd gotten the run-around all day my temper would flair." Amelie Bones dipped her quill in the inkwell, flipped over to the next scroll, and scribbled corrections on the wording, then set down her quill. "You need to control your people, Minerva."

"Professor Asimov had no idea what he was doing. A student asked him a convenient favor and he agreed. Frankly, I got stir crazy my first year here, and I'm not a squib, but..."

"Not him. I meant Malfoy. And Potter."

"Harry Potter," said Minerva, pausing. "I'm not in a position to order him around, and neither are you Amelia. I should think that after all you've seen..."

"I've seen plenty. He doesn't need to be ordered around. He needs to be controlled. Gently. Persuasively. I'm not sure how Albus managed him, but figure it out. We're in a precarious enough situation as it stands right now. Voldemort killed all the right people - thank Merlin for small favors - and that bought us months of time. But I ... no, not just me. We can't have this."

Minerva pursed her lips. "What exactly can't we have, Amelia?"

"We can't have it come out that Albus ransacked the Hall of Prophecy. We're in a tenuous situation, and if people lose confidence... They'd think Albus mad. Madder than they thought him. We need normalcy for years or maybe even a decade, before Harry can officially assume his position. Albus is only looked on favorably because he's a martyr. Imagine how they'll react if they knew. Or how they'll react when they discover he made that child Chief Warlock. Potter's plans..."

"Seem to be proceeding quite well," Minerva sniffed.

"Because they aren't his, as far as the public is concerned." The Chief Warlock got up and sat on her desk, looking slightly down at the Headmistress of Hogwarts. "Minerva, you know me. I'm not a politician. I never wanted to be. I didn't want this job and nothing would make me happier than running the DMLE. But you don't get to be head of any department, even DMLE, by ignoring politics. Young Malfoy stirred up a hornet's nest, and he did it well. If he'd been some foolish Gryffindor and charged into the Ministry firing spells, or even just snuck in we could write this off. But what he did ... Even Lucius couldn't have pulled this off, nobody would trust him. Draco doesn't have his father's baggage. Just like Albus, he's a martyr, but a living breathing one who never raved on about the mystical properties of licorice during a three day session of the Wizengamot. Draco almost died then renounced vengeance against House Potter. He practically owns the Prophet, the Quibbler is with him on this and he's been courting key votes. Imagine how this will play out!"

"Voldemort's dead, and I don't think..."

"He's already come back once. Even if we know it won't happen again, the public doesn't. Best case, we spin it that Voldemort destroyed the Hall of Prophecy, although that doesn't make us look good either and the timeline may not withstand scrutiny. I'm not sure which Unspeakables know the truth, but I suspect several do. Imagine if it comes out. Then people start to ask the question – what was Dumbledore hiding?"

"You give too little credit to people," said Minerva.

"The same people that voted to send Hermione Granger to Azkaban?" asked the Chief Warlock, cocking her head.

Hermione heard Draco walking through the stacks a few seconds before he sat down at her table. The disturbing part was that she wasn't actually sure how she knew it was Draco. Maybe I recognized his pace, he does stride around.

"Hi Draco. How are you?" she asked, smiling at him.

"Well, thank you." He shifted in his seat for a second as Hermione closed the book she was reading, and Draco read off the title. "The Structure of Scientific Revolutions. Is it interesting?"

"Not really. I'd rather be studying potions, but that's my reward for finishing this."

Draco just let out a laugh, a real one, relaxed. He didn't even seem worried as Madam Pince glared at him, barely two aisles away. "Well, we all have so much to do. But I can offer you something much more interesting to do."

"And what's that?"

"Research. Can Xare transport you any place you want?"

"Trying to break into Peverell? I'm sorry Draco. I don't have time for that. But I imagine so, she's taken me everywhere else. They don't really have a defense against it, except that Xare wouldn't take anyone who wanted to steal the chalice."

"No, not Peverell." Draco leaned across the table and whispered conspiratorially. "There's a room underneath the Ministry of Magic. According to legend its lit by the glow of souls and the sounds of the dead echo across time. In reality its probably lit by torches and guarded by Aurors and traps. Clever people who work for misguided fools feel that ignorance is safer than troubling knowledge, because in this room the greatest secrets of our day sit undisturbed and unheard by human ears."

He leaned back as Madam Pince walked by, and spoke in a normal, but still quiet tone. "Or they may not be important. I'll be able to get in once I pass my O.W.L.s and officially become Lord Malfoy, but I worry that may be too late. The knowledge that there may be something important. We need to know. I'm not really sure what else to do about it, but if a secret that may save lives bothers a Slytherin, perhaps the best way to discover it is to tell a Ravenclaw turned Heroic Gryffindor and ask for help."

Hermione closed her book. "What can these secrets reveal?"

"I don't know. Possibly how to save us all."

"I cannot believe you would do such a thing. A Professor at Hogwarts."

Minerva McGonagall stood behind her desk. On her head her hat sat, bolt upright, freshly stretched and starched. Not a single article of her robes gave any indication of sloth, lazyness, laxity, or casualness. Her voice hinted at deep disappointment. Not the disappointment of a hopeful parent, but of a betrayed party. "And I don't want to hear about the troubles you've had adjusting to the position. Of all people, you should have seen this coming, Professor Slughorn."

Horace Slughorn blinked. "I consider myself fairly well informed, Headmistress. But I am not exactly sure why am I here."

"Because of Malfoy and his antics at the Ministry."

"Ah ... now that, I did hear about. After the fact, of course. Shouldn't your scolds be directed at Professor Asimov, who took him, or Professor Lockhart, who asked Isaac on Draco's behalf?"

"I can hardly blame a squib for being unaware when he's walking into a magical hornet's nest. And you and I both know that the new Head of Griffyndor isn't exactly renowned for thinking. But the three of you are the tangled bezoar, always chatting. You must have known. And you would understand that Draco's walk into the Ministry would be nothing but trouble. I'm getting owls from three under secretaries, what if they cut our funding? I don't expect you to know everything, but it doesn't take a subtle wizard to know the potential explosiveness of a student going to the Ministry. A potions master studies miscibility, some ingredients you just don't mix."

Horace Slughorn stood there, and bowed his head. "I apologize. Of course as the Head of his House I should be more aware of Young Malfoy's comings and goings and take an interest in his political tutelage. I will speak with him, and also gently correct my less experienced colleagues."

"I'm not being unreasonable," said the Headmistress, sitting down. "That's all I demand."

Draco knocked at the door, heard the grunting "Enter" and walked into Professor Slughorns room. It was just over the bridge and opposite the Potions classroom, technically not inside the Dungeon but he could stroll into it easily enough, just a minute from his House, and a minute from his classroom. A minute from Draco's room.

Draco entered and closed the door behind him. The furniture was sparse, just a desk and some chairs. There were bookshelves all around the room, mostly covered with autographed pictures that waved to Draco pleasantly.

"The Headmistress took away your Sigil," Professor Slughorn said.

Draco lifted it up and looked at it, then shrugged. "She returned it at Christmas, with the understanding that I wouldn't be bringing it back. And she did fashion me a replacement, to use as a bludgeon. That was nice of her."

"I take it as an honour that you feel I'm enough of a threat to warrant risking expulsion just to see to your safety. Sit down Draco. I've just spent a rather unpleasant hour being lectured by the Headmistress and as it happens I'm not in a mood to reenact the experience to someone else, even you. So, I'll just ask what you hoped to accomplish."

Draco stared into Professor Slughorn's eyes, and saw his surprise at the bold act. After a moment he lowered his gaze, submissively.

"Exactly what it seemed. You know there was a prophecy that Professor Trewlaney spoke, before the Headmaster took her."

"Yes," Professor Slughorn said, "I heard about it too, at the time. Of course."

"What if it wasn't about Voldemort? And what is he coming for? What will he tear apart?" Draco let just a hint of desperation from his voice.

Professor Slughorn picked up a small china cup and took a sip of tea. Draco noticed that he hadn't been offered any. A snub? Or recognition that I would refuse? Draco just sat as Professor Slughorn considered for a second cup of tea.

"What does the name 'Tom Riddle' mean to you?"

"I can't say that I've heard it," Draco said calmly, hoping it wasn't too calmly.

"No, I imagine you can't," said Professor Slughorn, chucking. "Well, let me tell about him. Riddle was my brilliant student, clever. Not just book clever, he would use spells in ways you wouldn't imagine in years. Even though he was raised by muggles his power grew quickly, and by the time he graduated ... well, I had no doubt he'd eclipse all of my previous proteges. I had such high hopes for him."

"And what became of him, sir?"

"If I believe the stories? Your friend Miss Granger killed him last year." Professor Slughorn put down his tea cup. "Consider yourself reprimanded and show yourself out, Draco."

Draco walked back towards his room.

If Professor Slughorn was right, Tom Riddle was Voldemort's real name. He finally had confirmation that his vision of Dumbledore had been true. Or at least contained new factual information. The vision predicted that Tom Riddle was Voldemort's name.

It was always possible that Professor Slughorn had pulled the information from Draco's head, but if so, why confirm it? And if not ... Draco had received a wholly unexpected bonus from yesterday's tedious adventure. The entire trip to the Hall of Prophecy had been a long shot, a gambit. Apparently it had attracted much more attention than he'd hoped.

Draco smiled. He'd gotten quite lucky. He'd expected to waste a few hours or an afternoon, but had apparently stuck a nerve. He'd rattled branches and a valuable piece of information had tumbled to the ground. And nobody at all seemed to notice that he'd stopped in his vault on a side errand.

Draco twirled his Sigil once before dismissing it, and it disappeared into the aether.

Draco had work to do and spells to master.

Chapter 45: January

Auror Behry saw Draco Malfoy and the Weasley Twins walking through the small corridor between the infirmary and Peverell.

"Come to make another try at it, 'eh?" he said cheerfully. "Well, you know the drill." There were trunks to store all of their gear.

"Can we take our wands through? I mean, that isn't allowed, but some people can do wandless magic."

"We're not trying to break it today," said one of the twins. "We just want to experiment on a few spells."

"We've got some ideas," said the other, conspiratorially.

Auror Behry pulled out his mirror. "I'm going to have to call it in..."

"Did you know that there are Muggle Wizards?" Draco Malfoy said, before taking a bite of a waffle.

Daphne looked up from her pancakes. She noticed that most of the table was watching Draco, now. He'd spoken loudly and now he paused, putting down his knife.

"I know, it's stupid. A Muggle Wizard. But they put on shows and they can do some amazing things. They make things float, or disappear. They can tell which piece of paper you picked even when you shuffle them all back together. They can read your mind."

Daphne had recovered first. "Those are all pretty simple spells, Draco," she said.

"Yes, but they can't do magic. They are muggles. They don't know Wingardium Leviosa, but they can fly. They can't do Transfiguration, but they turn people into tigers. They do it for show, to entertain other muggles. They can't actually do it, of course, they use gadgets and have figured out incredibly clever ways to confuse people and hide what they are doing. But the really funny thing? Some of them tricked scientists into thinking they could do real magic."

"But the Statute of Secrecy," gasped Colin Creevey.

"Doesn't apply to Muggles," said Daphne. "And these scientists believed them?"

"Some of them," Draco said, cutting his waffle. "It's funny. Listen to Potter and you begin to think of science as the greatest thing ever. But it's just like magic, only as good as the Wizard. Or Scientist, as the case may be. These scientists got the idea that if they couldn't figure out a way to do it, nobody could. They tricked themselves."

"And so the Muggles believed in magic?" asked Gregory.

"No," said Harry Potter, who had sat down during the conversation. "Other magicians exposed them as frauds. They showed that there were secretly wires to help things fly, or that when people were reading minds they had someone telling them the answers. It wasn't that science was at fault, it was just the all-too-human error of pride. But you know what I find funny about this, Draco?"

Draco, mouth full, just made a waving motion with his fork to ask for the answer.

"They probably got started by seeing a real Wizard. Some young boy sees Merlin float away a woman, and he spends a while trying to figure out how he did it. And that Muggle spends years and then figures out a magic trick that doesn't involve magic. And it builds up to this entire genre of entertainment. As a nice side benefit, now that Muggles are used to seeing magic tricks, they become less likely to believe in magic, because they know how to fake it ..."

"Which makes you wonder if Merlin planned that all along," said Daphne.

"So, what spells did they cast?" ask Harry.

"It might be easier to list what spells they didn't cast," Mad Eye Moody growled. They all sent a Patronus around. The Malfoy boy turned his robes into a muggle outfit. They spilled dirt on the floor then scourgified it. They flew a houseplant around the room. I talked to Li, Behry, Septavius, and everyone who watched them. They each had a list, but it seemed like a hodgepodge. A few powerful spells, those Weasley boys think they're clever. But mostly things you'd find in the Helpful Housewife Grimoire. They were there for hours, and they just went through the list, thanked everyone, and said they'd have to come back to try more things.

"Did he say what this was about?" asked Neville.

"He just said it was important," Vince said. They were walking back from the Quiddich match, which had been exciting but disappointing. Hufflepuff had put up a valiant effort, but Herbert Fleet gave up the final goal with a mere three seconds left on the clock, giving Gryffindor the game. Vincent's voice still sounded gravelly, he'd been screaming the entire final quarter.

The headed up the stairs, breaking away from the rest of the 'Puff contingent. Mike shouted out after them "Watch out for monsters!" and the crowd, mostly quiet after the close loss, laughed. There had been rumours of shadowy hooded figures roaming the halls. Vincent and Neville continued higher and higher into Hogwarts.

"Why the Offense lecture hall, I wonder?" asked Neville. "We have plenty of good meeting places, like, uh..."

"Like the room next to Slytherin?" Vince said.

Neville blushed, "You know about that? I mean, I was going to invite you but I don't know …."

"I lived with Draco all last year," Vince said with a shrug. "Don't worry about it, Draco couldn't invite me, either. Everyone can't do everything."

"Thanks," said Neville, as they got to the lecture hall door. "I can get you into the Muggle wargames. Harry's opening those up."

"That would be cool," said Vince, who'd heard about it from Neville, Gregory and Draco. Each story had a different focus, but they all fascinated him. They stepped into the lecture hall. Draco sat facing the door in a small wooden chair placed next to the tall leathery chair that symbolized Professor Quirrel. Across from Draco sat Daphne Greengrass, who turned her head Neville and Vincent entered. There were two empty chairs on the other two sides of the table, A stoppered flask sat on the desk.

"Shut the door behind you," Draco said, waving them in.

Vincent shut the door - which magically bolted itself after he closed it - and joined Neville as they went and sat down.

"Thanks for coming," Draco said as he opened up the stopper and carefully took out a dropper and placed it on his tongue, then swallowed it. He carefully slid the flask to Neville, who gave a sniff.

"Veritaserum? Where did you … no, I don't want to know." Neville said.

"Best you don't know," Daphne said.

Draco nodded with her. "You don't have to take any. But I wanted to impress on you … on all of you … that this is serious. I realize that my reputation plays against me in some cases. It will take a few minutes for this to kick in. Who won the game?" Draco asked.

Neville gave him a recap for a few minutes, then Draco stiffened a bit.

"It's taken," Draco said and Neville sat, waiting for him to continue. Draco raised an eyebrow. "I'm surprised you took my word for it," Draco said. "Do you want to test it?"

Vincent shook his head. Neville opened his mouth, then closed it. "This seems overly dramatic."

Daphne leaned across the table, "Now that you mention it, you could be an occlumens."

"He isn't," said Vince, "Unless he learned in the fall, or from..." Vincent caught himself. Neville looked over at Vince.

"From Harry," Daphne said, gasping.

"From Grindelwald," Draco corrected, "who was my houseguest for a month. And no, I didn't learn it from him, although he certainly could have started my lessons. But learning Occlumency from one the greatest magicians of the last century would have been a profoundly wasted opportunity."

Daphne seemed to accept this, but Neville started to get up, "Your houseguest? What is he even doing out of prison?" Neville's voice carried across the entire room and echoed slightly.

Vince put his hand on Neville's arm, but didn't pull him down. "Hear him out," he said. "Please?"

Draco nodded. "I need help. I'm investigating something, and it's important. I can't really tell you how important it is, except to say that I think it equals Voldemort's return from last year. And I need help."

Neville thought this over. "I don't see why you asked me. Harry and Hermione would be much better choices."

"I can't tell them. Sorry, I don't dare go into details, but you must not tell them. It's dangerous if they know. That's why I took the Veritaserum, so that you'll believe me when I say it is dangerous. I can't even involve Gregory, because I can't risk him accidentally giving something away. It's not that I don't trust Gregory, but Harry may notice if Gregory's acts weird..." Draco shrugged, "You know how he is."

Neville thought some more. "You don't trust Harry?"

Draco said, "Until I'm done with my investigation, I can't. I want to trust him." Draco's flicked the flask with his finger, the nail causing a small ringing. "I trusted you enough to tell you this. You could just go to Harry and say everything, but right now I need people I trust, and people who can fly under the radar." Draco blanched slightly, "Sorry, I meant under Harry's radar. People who can talk to him, or not, as the case may be."

"I got it," said Vince. "Will you tell us why you believe it?"

Draco shook his head. "Not yet. I'm worried about Legilemency. I've taken some precautions for myself, but it's a huge risk to share the information. If we get some confirmation, or if we need a full brainstorm, yes. But you'll have to swear under Veritaserum that you are behind the investigation. I'm hoping it won't come to that."

Neville ran his hands through his hair. "What did you study with Grindelwald. Dark Magic?"

"Nothing like that," said Draco. "He's under an Unbreakable Vow. Some history and experiments with enchantments and glamours. How to layer them, trigger them. He and Dumbledore were both intrigued with underlying theories of magic. We talked about that. Oh, and Transfigurations."

"Then why make him your house guest."

"He's useful, that's why Harry got him paroled," said Draco softly. "And before you agree. This is dangerous. I mean, I don't think we'll die. But we'll make enemies"

Vince nodded.

"Why me?" said Neville.

"You and Harry are friends. I'd like to think we're friends, too. Maybe this is a wild goose chase, but maybe it's not. Maybe I'm right, or maybe I've gone crazy. In any case, I'm going to need someone brave enough to stand up against his friend. Whether that turns out to be me or Harry, I'm not sure yet. You are my conscience."

Neville let out his breath slowly, then nodded.

"What's our first step?" asked Vince.

"Simple. We go to the Hall of Prophecy."

"Why did they support Voldemort?" Hermione asked Draco quietly, as the sat in the Potions room. The lesson had ended and most had wandered off, but they'd stayed behind. "The death eaters?"

"You ask that like there's just one answer," Draco answered. "Some believed him. They hated Muggles, end of story. Others wanted power. Voldemort carefully recruited powerful individuals and eliminated others, and given the choice between recruitment and elimination. Well, it's not hard."

"Voldemort didn't recruit anyone, he didn't need anyone! He could have ruled this country by himself," said Hermione.

"No, he really couldn't. A fearsome wizard can't do the thousands of things a country needs to do. He can take your money, but can he really go door to door to every salesman, crafter, author, haruspector, diviner, and tax half of their earnings? Does he know how much he can take from each person? Can he solve all the murders he didn't commit, because those criminals are an insult to his power and no government can allow that. Will he learn the thousands of details he needs to know, each day? Of course not, that's boring even if it were possible. Even if Voldemort could do all these things, he would not want to. No, a real government – of any type – requires people. You may not know what the Undersecretary of Divination does, but she has a job and at least half of those bureaucratic jobs involve real issues and knowledge. There's some featherbedding, giving some important ally's dumb nephew a stupid position of authority to cement his aunt's allegiance, but it doesn't happen as often as you'd imagine. Aurors have power, merchants have power, criminals have power, citizens have power, and it's arranged in a complex pattern. If you take it all you'll find that everyone is your enemy. You can take a surprisingly large chunk, but you can't get greedy."

"So, yes, Father cut a deal with Voldemort. He never admitted it, but suppose he hadn't dealt with him, and got murdered along with the others going on? How would that have helped. Voldemort needed Father to handle many aspects of power. All Dark Wizards delegate."

"You wouldn't negotiate with Voldemort, Draco."

"I'd like to think that," Draco said.

"Well, that was a waste" said George.

(Draco thought he could tell them apart, although he also suspected that they sometimes deliberately let him think that as part of some complex game that he didn't understand. Fred and George Weasley were impressive wizards, fiendishly clever, and funny, but they also reminded Draco that you abandoned traditions at some risk. Traditions started for a reason, in most cases).

The Weasley's had explained that you had to hold off on proposing solutions, so they'd decided to just try a bunch of spells and see what happened, not with any particular plan, just as a brainstorming technique. Sometimes an army won by brute force, but often they won by combining two seemingly random ideas into a stunningly powerful combination. They hadn't been able to think of any stunningly powerful combination, so they'd decided to just try casting spells to see if inspiration struck.

It hadn't.

"Even if we do think of something," said Fred (maybe), "we still don't know how we're going to smuggle a wand in."

"Well, if I only had something like the Muggle Naval Simulation's map, that might do it." Draco said. "There must be some spell powering it. If we knew that spell maybe we could sneak in, or find a small time when nobody was guarding the door. I know, it's a stupid idea. The door is always guarded, but there must be a pattern, some movement. No security is perfect, that would make it too expensive..."

Draco saw the twins exchange a look.

"What? What did I say?" he asked. They exchanged another look.

Professor Lockhart sat at his desk, in the small room tucked behind the lecture hall for Offense against the Dark Arts. His first lecture of the day would not be for thirty minutes, and he was using this time to review his notes from the prior weekends battle. He heard a slight scuffling of feet and almost called out "Horace?" before he checked himself.

Professor Slughorn did many things, but routinely climb seven flights of stairs was not one of them.

Besides, they'd just spoken an hour ago at breakfast. Gilderoy took out his wand, opened the top drawer and pulled out a small mirror inside it. The scene showed not his reflection, but a view of the lecture hall from atop a storage cabinet in the back, where Professor Lockhart had stuck the twin mirror.

A horrific robed figure stood in front of the main leather chair. Professor Lockhart gasped quietly, his eyes wanted to drift away from the mirror, to glance anywhere else, but he kept his gaze focused on the mirror as his wand twitched and he started raising defenses. He'd barely setup an explosive tripwire jinx on his doorway when the robed figure tossed back its hood and the effect disappeared. Gilderoy Lockhart gasped at the figure, now looking tiny instead of nearly seven feet tall, finished taking off his Armageddon Cloak and stuffed it into a mokeskin pouch, leaving General Malfoy in his place. Draco quickly checked his appearance and then walked towards the door to the teacher's alcove.

Professor Lockhart had just slid his mirror back into the top drawer and closed it when the knocking started.

"Come in!" he said cheerfully, and as the door opened he shoved aside his scrolls. "General Malfoy! A bit early today? What can I help you with?"

Draco Malfoy stood in his doorway and shifted a bit, and Gilderoy felt his smile falter in spite of himself. That boy has been receiving far too many Owls. Even for a Malfoy. Professor Lockhart could hear Slughorn's whispered confession from the week before. Had Draco reconciled with Narcissa, or had she told him something that upsetting? Lie or truth?

Professor Lockhart's moment of self-doubt lasted for about a second before Draco said, a bit too loudly. "I've been told to give you a message."

"You'd better come in, then," Gilderoy said. He took out his wand and motioned for Draco to shut the door behind him, then proceeded to cast a full dozen wards. He started off with the simplest wards, then moved onto more complex ones. If Draco knew them he gave no signs of recognition, but neither did he give any sign of surprise. Professor Lockhart cast more complex wards, things he doubted any student had ever heard. Certainly any second year. Only then did he slip in some detection spells, again complex ones, and he could see that Draco had several invisible shields raised.

Spells no second year should know.

He nodded at Draco. "What's the message?"

Draco looked at him, his face showing a bead of sweat on his forehead. Draco's hand clenched his wand, although he kept it lowered towards the ground. That, more than his expression, revealed Draco's fear. Draco, eyes slightly downcast, said "The eyes of the Basilisk are on you." His body barely moved when he spoke.

A moment later his eyes glanced up. "Professor?"

"I heard the message, Draco. Thank you." And he shifted his wand to point at Draco, who had already started to dodge. Of course, his entire attitude, his precautions, the Armageddon Cloak all demonstrate suspicion.

But Draco couldn't move faster than a wand. Gilderoy respected the boy's considerable skills, so he'd raised his own shields instantly.

Draco's defenses protected against stunning, jinxes, being put to sleep, and blunt physical trauma. They wouldn't stop Gilderoy's attacks - advanced or not Draco was still just a student - but they would have slowed him down. If he'd been attacking.

Gilderoy Lockhart, wand pointed at Draco, spoke "Eunoe" in a voice barely above a whisper.

Draco fired off an Expelliarmus at the same time, which Professor Lockhart's shields easily deflected as his own spell hit Draco. Draco had started to cast a second spell, but then spluttered and stopped. He turned away for a second, mouth working silently and then he brought his hands up to his forehead and crumpled into a corner, face covered.

When he finally got back up Professor Lockhart couldn't see Draco's eyes, still downcast. But his cheeks were wet.

"I'm sorry," Draco said, "I thought..."

"I can imagine," said Professor Lockhart, sitting back down and putting his wand away. "Do you need any help?"

Draco shook his head. "I don't know. I need time to think."

"I had to tell Professor Slughorn about this," Gilderoy said while releasing the wards on the room.

Draco nodded, and wiped his cheeks. He cast several spells and when he turned back around his face looked calm and serene, as though nothing had happened at all. "Tell him it makes sense now, and I thank him. But if he goes digging around my mind again..."

Professor Lockhart waited, but Draco just let the sentence hang between them, then left.

Chapter 46: Reflections, Pt 4

Draco had raised shields as soon as he'd entered the room. He'd even put harmonics into them, although he'd only just learned to do that reliably. He fired off an expelliarmus at Lockhart, but as the blinding flash of white light hit him he heard Eunoe and then the world went blank.

Harry Potter Day.

Despair washed over Draco. "This isn't an answer," he mumbled to the room, empty except for the shade of his former Headmaster. Then he shouted "I still don't know!" at the image of Albus Dumbledore, who was saying 'Hello, Tom' again. "It's not enough! How does this qualify as an answer? You trusted Harry knowing he was Voldemort, but Voldemort fooled you too!" Draco took out his wand and lashed out, cutting the mirror, smashing spell after spell at it, first normal spells he'd use in classes, on the battlefield, then the forbidden spells, he levitated a chair from across the room and flung it at the mirror. The chair itself shattered from the impact, leaving no cracks appeared on the glass.

After a few minutes, exhausted, he slumped back to the ground, mumbling. "It's not fair. That's not an answer."

"No, it most definitely is not," said Albus Dumbledore, standing besides the mirror and examining his own shade over half-moon glasses. He raised his head and turned his back on his reflection in the mirror, which continued its looping soliloquy.

"Hello, Draco." Draco scrambled to his feet, wand instinctively out. "I hardly fault you for that, Draco. I imagine you've had a rough time of it, and you've a particular reason to hate me. Still, I would never dream of hurting you."

Draco lowered his wand. "You didn't burn Mother alive, you only pretended to. I can still hate you for all those years, but not as much. It ... was war."

Father would have done worse, Draco thought.

Dumbledore's blue eye's twinkled. "Narcissa is returned? I am glad. Voldemort is destroyed then. But you are still so young..."

"He was destroyed the night you got trapped," Draco waved at the mirror. Then he brightened up. "You got free! You were only pretending to be trapped? I'm confused. It's only Halloween, the fall after."

"So soon?" Dumbledore sounded wistful. "No, Draco, I am still trapped. But it feels like a mere instant ago, and I suspect that however long it takes until I am truly freed will be just another instant. As to how this happened, well, Let's just say that I'd set up something for just such a situation."

"For the situation of someone here in this room..."

"I believe it is called the Room of Requirements, and even by Hogwarts standards it is exceedingly powerful. You required answers, the room naturally wanted to give them to you."

"So it dragged you out of time, Hogwarts freed you!"

"No, even Hogwarts lacks that power. It ... loosened my bonds, so to speak. Although I helped the process along, which now explains that ridiculous night I stumbled around looking for a bathroom and a certain ritual. No, I am but temporarily freed. Once I have your forgiveness and you have your answers I will be gone again."

"Why should I have to forgive you?"

"Oh, you do not have to forgive me, Draco, but I do hope that you will."

"No. I mean, I don't think you've done anything unforgivable." Draco paused, choosing his words carefully. "I'm not happy about it. But you were fighting Voldemort and I now realize what that meant. The Voldemort Father told me about, he was nothing like the real one was he?"

"Ah, well, as to that I suppose there is some debate. But no, Draco, the real Voldemort was yet another mask worn by Tom Riddle. Who I taught, as you surmised from the mirror. So I bear true blame, even if I could not quite bring myself to burn your mother alive. Such a dreadful cost..." Dumbledore trailed off.

Draco rubbed his temples. "I'm not sure I should believe this. Any of this."

Albus gave a small chuckle, and sat down in a small chair heavily, as if his age had finally caught up with him. "That would be Harry's influence rubbing off on you. How do you suppose he would decide what to believe?"

Draco thought about it. "If this is just a dream or false memory, then something won't add up. But if it's real, there are facts I can verify. So even if it's not you I'll know something."

"Very good. In fact, you can get facts to confirm simply from my conversation with Tom Riddle."

"And those facts will let me confirm that Harry Potter is good."

"Well, they should confirm that I thought so. Which I do. But meaning well and doing well are two entirely different things, don't you think Draco? I think you have done very well indeed. Although we both know there are things you have done you should not be proud of. Torturing Harry with a Dark Hex, for example."

Draco considered this. "That's something I already knew. But no," he said quietly, "I'm not proud of that. I don't suppose I was nice, back then. But … it's funny. I acquired power and made allies because everyone expected it of me. Father. The rest of the students. You, I suppose. And if nothing had happened I would continue. Maybe you should have stopped me, but I doubt you would have. And then, after the trial, I acquired a purpose. I was driven, maybe more so than anyone but Harry himself. I had a worthy ambition and if I turned out to be wrong it would still serve me well. The uncertainty drove me even more, because the one thing I knew was that I might need to use it. Now that I have something like confirmation and I can relax..."

Dumbledore has been listening with growing interest but at the last phrase he flickered and his face turned into a frown, and he interrupted Draco and got up, coughing slightly.

"I am sorry, Draco, if I gave you the impression that trusting Harry Potter sufficed. That may not be as comforting as you'd hoped. You see, there is a prophecy. Harry Potter will destroy the world. I listened to it myself, in the Hall of Prophecies."

Draco stuttered a few times, speechless.

"No, Harry means well. But destroying the world while meaning well still seems … extreme. I have balanced things out as best I can. But I cannot do that while trapped."

Draco gasped, "You want me to kill Harry..."

"Oh Merlin no. Harry might live for thousands of years, now. If he were to die suddenly he'd have to destroy the world before he died you see. Prophecies are tricky things, and Harry might very well destroy the world trying to save it. Or he may destroy it in a fit of rage, or through carelessness. I rather think he will destroy the world in a good way. But I may have misjudged and Harry will in fact turn evil. As you pointed out, Voldemort has fooled me before. While Harry's alive there's always hope. No, you must ensure that if he does destroy the world, he does so in the best possible way. And if he does not, well, you must deny him, without killing him."

Draco thought about it. "I can't. Not forever. A year, sure. I have a head start, but he's gaining rapidly. Can I keep ahead of him through through school? Maybe. But after that, he'll be too powerful. I'll slip up. I don't even know Occlumency. I'll slip up and he'll catch on. No, you have to send me a message later on when I'm older. I can't remember this now," Draco pointed his wand firmly at his head but Albus Dumbledore strode over and knocked his wand away, and it skittered along the floor, almost all the way back to the mirror where the shade of Albus Dumbledore was saying "Hello, Tom," again.

"No! This you must remember, I cannot do this again! There are no other messages." Dumbledore deflated and sighed, then opened his hand and Draco's wand flew back into it. When he spoke again his voice was sad and serene.

"I can plot no further, Draco, and so I ask your forgiveness, just as I asked Severus when I gave him his tasks. And when I finally see him, rest assured that I will ask for Salazar's forgiveness, for the demands I've made on his followers, but this you must do."

"How?"

"That must be your plot, Draco. I dare not tell you a plan, lest you follow it blindly. You will need to make adjustments on the way. But you are not alone. I still have allies here, and help is always available at Hogwarts to those who ask. Do you really need to hide this memory?"

Draco nodded.

"Very well, go see Professor Lockhart and tell him what you require. If he balks, tell him 'The eyes of the Basilisk are on you.' He'll lock this memory safely away, but recoverable. I only have a few moments left," Dumbledore handed Draco his wand back.

"I would ask you to tell Narcissa that I am sorry, but our conversation must remain a secret. So I ask you again, Draco, for forgiveness. Not for the past, but for your future. It is a hard task I set before you, but the world hangs in the balance."

Albus Dumbledore looked at Draco Malfoy over the half-moon glasses, eyes pleading. But when Draco finally opened his mouth to reply the Headmaster and the mirror disappeared. Draco paused for a moment, then took out his journal and wrote a few notes before heading out to find Professor Lockhart.

Draco looked around as the memory faded to see that he was still in Professor Lockhart's office. He'd crumpled into the corner and as he pulled himself up Draco realized he'd been crying.

"I'm sorry," Draco said, "I thought..."

I thought I was going crazy. I thought I was going to die. And now I don't know what to think.

"I can imagine," said Professor Lockhart, sitting back down and stowing his wand. Draco suspected he didn't have the slightest inkling. "Do you need any help?"

Draco shook his head. "I don't know. I need time to think."

"I had to tell Professor Slughorn about this," Professor Lockhart said.

Draco nodded, and wiped his cheeks and cast three glamours to improve his appearance. "Tell him it makes sense now, and I thank him. But if he goes digging around my mind again..."

Draco slipped out of the room, and started walking back towards Slytherin. As he walked, he pulled a silver ring out of his pouch, then took off an identical ring off his left hand. As Draco switched them, he made his way back to his room.

Things were starting to make sense.

All he needed now was all the information he'd lost and a plan.

At least for the information, he knew where to begin.

Author's Note - Due to having a full October, I'm switching back to a single update per week. Next update on Tuesday the 13th.

Chapter 47: Wargames, Pt 7

Draco stretched, taking a few precious seconds to rub his neck and rest his eyes. I'm tired of that map.

The view never changed, mostly water. Land from the south jutted up into the lake or sea or wherever it was, a small bump ships moved around. A gentle curve of land starting in the east and gently curving to the north. A few islands - including one that looked vaguely like a dolphin. The Bludger bobbed gently, roughly halfway between the invading land to the south and the northern shore. A good position to monitor air traffic. Hermione said she'd seen it before, but Draco didn't recognize it and Harry had asked them not to investigate.

Which was fine with Draco. He had more pressing concerns.

Dozens of brooms moved across the map, but the voices around him spoke calmly and softly. This simulation had just started its third hour: they'd gotten up early on a Saturday morning so that they could do a full day.

Like Muggle Movie Night, The Muggle Broom Simulation (as it was now called) had proven popular. Harry had opened them up to other students and asked each of the Bayesian Conspiracy Members to run groups through. Draco still didn't know how to create or operate a scenario, but once you started it the spell took over. By now over twenty groups had finished the basic simulation that the Conspiracy ran the first night. That left hundreds of students who wanted to try. A spectator area had been set up, which helped now. Since people witnessed other missions, the adjudicator didn't need to explain every detail every time. Several special training sessions had been run to explain things to the entire crowd, and there were a few variant simulations, to add to the surprise.

Harry had warned this new scenario was much more complicated.

Draco couldn't disagree.

Draco couldn't see the spectators, but The Bludger usually drew a crowd. Each crew named their own ship, and kept tallies of their wins and losses. So far this morning they'd dealt with several brooms trying to take advantage of blind spots, a large broom attack, and an accidental fire had rendered them blind for several minutes before their map had been restored. Now several boats had started an assault against the Doppleganger Defense. They'd been small boats - practically invisible to radar - but The DD was vulnerable to even the smallest boats.

It was another Skysweeper, after all.

"How long until our brooms reach the DD?" Draco asked, eyes still closed. He could remember the rough broom positions. The Doppelganger Defense was off to their west, and the brooms were on it. Green brooms were converging on their position. Draco felt like the map image had been burnt onto his retina.

"Five minutes," said Daphne, who was running communications for today.

"Contact 4474, presumed red," said Gregory.

Draco opened his eyes and looked at the map. 4474 had just taken off from the mixed use northern-central airbase. The clock showed 10:17:15. Barely three hours into the simulation, five hours to go. Harry had explained that this scenario studied fatigue on decision making. This was meant to be tiring, Draco felt exhausted already. This was another hassling run, probably. The enemy almost never directly attacked, not without a local force advantage, but they'd send out brooms to divide forces or probe for weak spots. Right now the Bludger had sent its brooms to help the DD, so it didn't have great defenses.

Draco sat in the big chair today.

An automated voice, sounding like a middle aged woman said, "Bludger, Request information on P-3." The simulation had gotten more complicated. Now the team also fielded requests from the rest of the fleet, as well as getting support from them. Draco scanned the map for the P-3, which was apparently a command broom carrying equipment similar to a skysweeper. He'd been incredulous last week when they'd been added to the scenario, that Muggles had flying command centers. But Harry assured him they did.

Since the P-3 flew it could scrye farther than the Bludger. It was probably coordinating the red brooms. Draco didn't see it on the map.

"Southern view? That P-3?" The broom had been seen in the south west … fifteen minutes ago. Was it that long? Draco had a rough feel for how fast it could go, but that covered a large portion of the map.

Hermione ran the Southern view today. "It's been out of our range for over eight minutes. I've got last known coordinates. Let me see ..." As Hermione spoke the simulation continued asking about target numbers. They'd complained about that, but apparently that was realistic. The simulation didn't listen to them. Just gave information. Draco saw Hermione's notation appear on the main map.

"Comms, relay the information back on the P-3," said Draco. Daphne acknowledged the command and Draco could forget about this. A few seconds later Daphne spoke up again.

"DD is firing on incoming boats and taking fire. Still requesting support." Draco saw a red broom disappear near the DD. He almost cursed, it would be at least five more minutes before they could support. A broom appeared at the edge of the eastern coast, well inside the outer circle. It had probably been flying low to avoid radar. A second. Both red. Draco didn't need to do anything, the team ran smoothly.

"New targets," said Hermione. "4802 and 4845 coming in from the east. ETA five minutes." They'd seen dozens of hassling sorties over the last two sessions. If these two brooms followed the pattern, they'd rush towards the Bludger for a few minutes, then break off. Two brooms weren't a serious threat, but could provoke an incident if Draco over-reacted. Eventually one would try something … and given the current attack on their sister ship now might just be the time.

"Captain," Gregory said. "4474 hasn't acknowledged my challenges."

Draco looked at the map. 4474 still had a red question mark. Draco recognized the path, it was used by the grey brooms to go from the mixed use northern airfield to the mixed use southern airfield. But enemy planes sometimes hid in the shadows of the larger skybuses.

"Comms, confirm." Draco said. Draco could hear Daphne's quiet voice talking.

Draco noticed that the red brooms in the east closing in, still a few more minutes away from where he could threaten them. Draco looked at the map and focused on the broom bearing down on them. This didn't feel right. He couldn't do anything about the other brooms. Not yet.

"What do we know about 4474?" Draco asked.

"Uh, took off three minutes ago. No scheduled flight at that time, which is why simulation presumed red. Following the standard path for grey brooms, that's why I checked." Gregory hesitated than offered his opinion. "A gutsy hassle run, maybe?"

Daphne started to say something, but the automated voice cut her off.

"Bludger, be advised brooms 4850 and 4292 breaking off from Doppelganger Defense and targeting you." The voice sounded matronly, like an officious bureaucrat pleased with herself.

"It's not responding," Daphne said.

"Those two breaking from DD to us have priority," Draco said, and he could see the readouts indicating that Neville had moved the shields to cover the brooms breaking away from the DD towards them. Blaise was also bringing weapons to bear. He watched them, they'd be here in a few minutes. That was too much of a coincidence. Two brooms coming in from the west, two coming in from the east, and one from the north.

"ETAs on all inbounds?" Draco said. Numbers appeared on all the brooms, All the brooms would hit the red circle within a minute or two. He couldn't deal with them all.

Draco started to speak but the simulation started as well, Draco raised his voice. "Declare a no fly zone, our red circle, effective now. Order all brooms away. Weapons Free. Keep shielding the pair to the west."

The bridge responded with a flurry of voices. The two eastern brooms kept approaching, but the western brooms were veering south. They might clip the no-fly zone, it would be close. The northern broom stayed unchanged.

"Ops, What is 4474 doing? Anyone?"

"I … I can't tell," said Gregory. Hermione flicked her wand at the map. Then again.

Gregory found his voice "Got it. Descending. It's an attack run!"

"It's ascending," said Hermione, her voice rising in tone just like Gregory's had.

"Which is it?" Draco said. The ETA counter was timing down. "Shields cover 4474. Weapons, you are free to shoot the others, but hold off on 4474."

"Something is weird about it," said Gregory and Hermione quickly agreed but they were both working their wands. The ETA timer was counting down.

"Covering 4474," said Neville. The timer was at five seconds. Draco watched it counting down to four three, two, one, zero, the broom was flashing as it crossed the red circle. It could fire on them now, and the closer it got the worse it would be.

Neville, staring intently at his readout, spoke up "Thirty more seconds and our shields won't matter."

They'd learned early on that, at least for these type of scenarios, Muggle shields worked on deception, not brute strength. Once a broom could see the ship it could fire a missile, shields or no.

"What's it doing?" Draco said, barely getting his words out before the DD requested another update on the P-3.

"It's … gone?" said Hermione, but the broom still showed up on the map. Her wand was moving furiously now, searching the map.

"No, descending, gaining speed," Gregory's voice was steady again. "It's right on the same path, how could you ..." Gregory's voice trailed off, the question unasked. Draco stared at the main map, the broom was right there.

"Twenty," said Neville.

Draco "Weapons, target them. Hermione, I see it on the map. Comms, are they talking?"

"Targeting," Blaise shouted to be heard over the intercom, which was reporting Green brooms engaged over Doppelganger Defense. The simulation was still speaking, listing new broom contacts from other ships, when Daphne answered "Still no communications from them."

Draco looked as the eastern broom tracks veered suddenly off. The western brooms would miss the no-fly zone. 4474 hadn't changed course.

"Ten seconds," said Neville.

Even before he finished Draco responded "Fire."

Several long seconds later the 4474 disappeared from the map.

"Confirmed," said Neville.

Draco turned his attention to situation to the west. "When will we reach shielding distance to help the DD?"

"Two minutes," said Gregory.

With the green brooms engaging the enemy and the hassling sorties out of position to coordinate against the Doppelganger Defense the operation became easy, even routine. A mopping up effort. Twenty minutes later the skies were green. Suddenly, the map disappeared.

Draco blinked, the clock said 10:45.

"Another fire? We've still got four hours to go," Draco said. "Get the sailors to estimate the damage..."

"No, we're done," said Harry. "A bit of misdirection, I never intended to run an eight hour simulation. That would take too long. I just wanted you to think it would be eight hours when we started. I'd like to run this simulation for a few other teams, so please don't talk about it with anyone. We'll start Monday night. Gregory, are you available to operate?"

"Sure," said Gregory.

"Why lie about the time," Draco asked.

"Well, so you wouldn't know when the critical moment was. You'd assume it would come in the end of the test, so I had to make 'the end of the test' seem much further away."

"So we won? We saved the DD" asked Blaise.

"It's not about winning or losing," said Harry, voice carefully neutral. "It's about operating efficiently under stress and making right decisions."

Something in Harry's tone triggered a warning bell in Draco's head. Harry acted socially ... inept, but gave praise easily. Harry spent countless nights encouraging the Bayesian Conspiracy. Over the last month Harry had commended the bridge of the Bludger and other crews. He tutored Hufflepuffs, for Merlin's sake. Harry's days remained a mystery, but during evenings he encouraged anyone and helped all who asked. Draco saw Hermione's shoulders slump, she apparently shared his opinion.

Only one decision had been stressful for the entire four hours, and Harry's tone implied Draco had gotten it wrong.

"4474," Draco's voice quieted the room. "It was grey, wasn't it?"

Harry paused and shifted uncomfortably. "The HMS Bludger just killed 290 civilians."

The lights came up and Draco felt relieved to see that the spectator area was empty, except for Professor Lockhart.

Chapter 48: Wargames, Pt 8

Draco replayed the decision in his head while the House Elves appeared, setting up a small table for lunch. After a moment Draco opened his eyes and saw Hermione sitting in her chair, hunched over. After Harry had announced that they'd killed innocent civilians the room descended into several arguments, but Hermione just sat there.

Draco paused. Father's voice quickly listed all of the reasons not to talk to Hermione. Draco ignored him, walked over and sat down beside her, angled slightly away. He didn't want to appear confrontational.

"It was my fault, Hermione." Draco's voice wasn't soothing, didn't sound comforting. Just stating a fact. "I was in command. I gave the order."

"I should have known. I knew something was wrong." Draco saw that Harry walking over towards them. "I knew I'd seen that map before. It was on the news." Her voice was quivering.

"We all knew something was wrong. I felt it. And it came down to a choice. In many ways it's just the counter to my speech after the Purple/Green War. These things happen, and just like we shouldn't beat ourselves up if we die in war..."

"I have less tolerance for murder than death," she glared at him angrily. "And what happened to 'save them all', Draco?'"

"That's the standard we aspire to," Draco said softly. "But it's an impossible standard."

Harry was walking over towards them, and Professor Lockhart had come down from the spectator area. They were both converging on Draco and Hermione.

Draco ignored that, and continued talking "We didn't know what the target was. Shooting it down was a risk. Not shooting it down was a different risk. There were no certainties. I knew that. The cost of being wrong differed, mainly. I couldn't save everyone and that eats at me, a little. But it's only because I messed up. Better to do it now, during a simulation."

Hermione wasn't quite crying, but her eyes weren't dry. Draco felt a spark of rage at Harry. He should have known she'd take this badly. Most of the team wasn't taking it well – losing had that effect on teams – but Hermione felt it deeply. "If I'd killed that many people in real life, I think I'd be hurt. But I can't really feel it. The fact that it upsets you shows you are a good person. Better than me." Draco put his arm around Hermione's shoulder and squeezed, once.

"We should have been able to save everyone," Hermione said.

"It wasn't a fair test," Professor Lockhart said, staring over the heads of Hermione and Draco. "For a number of reasons, but I would say mainly that in terrible situations terrible things happen. And I cannot find it in me to blame people for making the decision that keeps them out of danger. Even if the danger was imaginary."

Harry looked uncomfortable, and Draco glanced around the room. Blaise and Gregory were still yelling, and Neville and Daphne were standing in front of the big map, talking with the Professors. The map showed the positions of the brooms during the attack, right as the pair had broken off from the Doppelganger Defense. Neville pointed out a gap that could have bought them some time, another few seconds.

Gregory had stormed away from Blaise and walked over to Daphne, and said "How could you not contact them?" finger pointing accusingly at her chest. If she'd been a boy, Gregory would have poked her. Draco felt sure that Gregory didn't really feel guilty, but in his mind Gregory had lost and he was lashing out.

"Nobody knows, Gregory." Harry said firmly. "Nobody knows. This was real. It really happened, pretty much like the simulation said." Everyone had stopped arguing and turned to Harry.

"Obviously it's more complicated and didn't involve magic. But the sequence of events is pretty close. You have a crew dealing with harassing brooms, and brooms that color switch, and then a few details get confused and events spiral out of control. I wanted to witness how it happened, so I could learn from their mistake. Maybe I shouldn't have done this. I didn't realize it would hit so hard. I'm sorry."

"There was no right answer," Draco said. "I was just telling Hermione that. If I'd been wrong the other way, we would have all died."

Neville spoke up, "What happened? I mean, something weird happened."

"4474 was renumbered to 4131 automatically by the simulation. I changed the number on you."

"That's cheating," Neville said, over the other protesting voices, but Harry just talked over them.

"Yes, yes. But that's necessary for the fleet to talk to each other. If you don't renumber, then you'll refer to 4474 and the other ships will know it as their number. There was an announcement, but it was in the middle of other things. I didn't expect anyone to notice, and you didn't. People think they notice everything, but you each had a task and with the stress you filtered out the routine background announcements to focus on the threats. You say its cheating, but you didn't really understand the system the simulation used. Not that you necessarily should have, but if you had asked it would have been explained."

"That's not fair," said Blaise.

"There have been studies where they ask people to count the number of times a sports team tosses a ball around a circle. Most people get the number right, but don't even notice the person in the background dressed as a gorilla that comes out and does a little dance," said Harry.

"When did the announcement happen?" Daphne asked.

"During the request for the P-3, shortly after the flight took off. Later on Gregory keyed in the the number which brought up the wrong information, since 4474 now referred to a different plane. Hermione used her wand to pick out the correct plane..."

At the last one Hermione wiped her eyes and a look of despair came across her face. "I wasn't looking for the contact number. Just the altitude. I didn't think to check..."

Harry interrupted her, rather than let her continue to blame herself. "Everyone knew something was wrong, and didn't have time to figure out why. By that point, you had already lost. Draco might have picked the right solution by accident but that would just be luck."

Professor Lockhart nodded and his voice came out low, like a growl. "That's a rather brutal lesson. But correct. You lost when the situation became something beyond your understanding." He paused, then suddenly spoke in a normal voice. "But no harm done! That's why we have these lessons! Very commendable, Mr. Potter."

Harry paused as the last House Elf disappeared. There was a small table set up with assorted meats, cheeses and breads, as well as a bowl of fresh salad and pitchers of tea. A working lunch.

Harry kept talking. "Compared to most students and Muggles you are all battle hardened professionals, but so was the original crew. They argued amongst themselves, possibly even broke military discipline. They knew they were confused, just like you. Already you are so much further ahead than from last year."

"We didn't have time," Daphne's voice was cold, accusing.

"Such is realism," Harry shot back, then grimaced. "I don't want to talk about solutions to this particular problem in general, I just want to hear about what you were thinking as it went on. In wars, lots of people die when you get into situations like this, where people feel threatened and lash out. Muggle Wars kill the innocent much more often than the soldier, but I'm sure it happens in Wizarding Wars as well."

Harry looked around to the Wizarding born. Draco nodded.

"It's not as bad." said Professor Lockhart, "Wizards typically see their victims, but curses still miss and the Killing Curse always finds a victim..."

Draco saw that Hermione had calmed down. She hadn't spoken yet.

"So, I just want to see what we learned. This is a hard problem. You lost the simulation because several improbable factors happened. None of them were rare, but put together it built up a world view that was easy to get wrong. The actual crew got it wrong in the real world, and they had months of training, not a few evenings scattered over six weeks. So, that's the problem. Let's discuss what happened, exactly, for at least half an hour and only then see if we can figure out how to solve it."

Draco sat in the Slytherin common room, facing the roaring fire. They'd talked about the battle for about an hour, everyone eventually grabbing some food. After they'd ended the session Draco had come back and spent the rest of his day sitting. Lodged in front of the fire thinking, pausing only to eat dinner. He'd considered today's lessons and compared them to the past two years. People came and went in the common room, Draco barely noticed. Draco only glanced up at Gregory when he said it was time for dinner.

Draco shook his head and fell back into thought.

Hours later, well, after the sun went down, Draco went to his room, got a small scroll, and sat down at his desk. He sharpened a quill and started to write.

The keys to defeating a clever enemy are several fold:

There must be some information that the enemy does not know, or knows incorrectly.

If there is a solution that the enemy can spot, you can still make it difficult by creating so many possibilities that they cannot be evaluated in time. Suppose there are two key facts that the enemy needs to piece together. Even if they know both, if they have to compare 50 facts it may be impossible to link them. And if the fact has to link through an intermediate fact, it becomes even harder.

Draco considered this. Harry had full advantage of the methods, but Harry's lesson on maths had been revealing. Sometime you had to have a key insight, and how difficult that is depends on how many facts you have to compare to reach it. If you have just two facts, you can draw a line between them in only a single way. If you have three facts you draw three lines, it makes a triangle. If you have four facts, you draw a square, but you can also connect the corners. Six possibilities. Five facts and you have a pentagon with five internal lines. The number of lines grows faster than the number of dots. And that's just if you have to compare two facts. If you have to group three facts together, you matched pairs of lines. Draco's Arithmancy wasn't up to the task of figuring out the exact number, but it didn't matter. If you got to even fifteen or twenty facts, it would become impossible.

Too much information can, paradoxically, make decisions less obvious.

Motives and Goals are key facts, easily hidden in some cases.

Even in a puzzle, an ambush is the best way to go.

Coupled with stress and time pressure, the enemy will discover themselves in a situation where they can only win by luck.

Try to reduce your enemy's knowledge of their current situation.

Ideally, take action to counter luck and make it so that either obvious decision is the wrong one.

Draco glanced down at the paper, read over it once, then crumpled it up. He stared at the ceiling for a few moments, then nodded to himself. Draco walked back to the common room and tossed the crumpled scroll into the fire and sat back down into his chair.

For the first time all day he smiled.

Author's Note - As several people on r/hpmor noticed, this scenario is (loosely) based on the USS Vincennes which shot down Iran Air Flight 655 over the Straits of Hormuz on July 3rd, 1988. The incident is modeled in "Sources of Power: How People Make Decisions" by Gary Klein, which goes into more detail than the Wikipedia account.

I have not independently confirmed the details provided by Klein. There are considerable differences between his review and the information presented on Wikipedia. My presentation is based on one version of the facts, facts that were hotly debated for years.

I have changed some details (with an eye towards simplification, but also to make the situation more stressful). In the real world the Vincennes was responding to a hostile attack on an allied ship at the time, so open hostilities were occurring. The severity of this attack is under dispute. Others (including some in the US Navy) believe the Captain of the Vincennes over-reacted, but for purposes of the simulation, Harry simulated a true threat.

The AEGIS Targeting computer labelled 4474 "presumed hostile" because it had delayed from its scheduled departure time. Further confusing the issue was that the computer re-labeled the target from 4474 to 4131 shortly after take off and in the confusion most of the crew did not hear this announcement. If anybody did hear, it apparently did not register. Which means that some crew typed in the number 4474 on their consoles and reported the airspeed indicators of the new target 4474, an A-6 which was descending and speeding up.

Taking all this (mis)information together, some crew interpreted the commercial airliner as "making an attack run" against the ship. Iran Air Flight 655 did have a civilian transponder code, but the Iranian Military sometimes spoofed civilian transponders on their military planes and had done that recently.

There is still some question as to why the commercial airliner did not respond to clarify. The Vincennes requested contact on civilian channels (3 times, according to Wikipedia), but apparently did not have the communication capacity to contact commercial air traffic control to ask them to relay the message. (According to Klein). Why IA 655 did not respond is a mystery.

Records show that the crew was divided before the captain gave the order to fire.

The entire incident - from takeoff until the USS Vincenness fired - lasted eight minutes.

None of the 290 people onboard IA 655 survived.

Chapter 51: Good Words

March 10th

Harry woke with a start at Hermione's touch on his shoulder, lifting his face off the desk while blindly groping for the grey knobby wand. Hermione had already rolled it well away from his hand. After the brief second of shock, Harry relaxed and mumbled sorry. He rubbed his hands through his hair while his elbows and shoulders made strained clicking and snapping sounds.

Sleeping face down on a desk was suboptimal. Harry reached for the wand, stopping his hand a few inches short of it. Nothing happened.

Not that he'd expected it to. By this point repeating that experiment is desperation, not science, Ravenclaw said accusingly. With a sigh Harry pocketed the wand.

"Harry, you need to get ready, " she said. "It's time." Harry didn't say anything. He bit back all the words he felt.

It's a waste of time.

This is a mere status display, like self-flagellation among the more extreme religious sects. But here we just mentally beat ourselves up instead of suffering physical damage.

I need to finish my investigation, to find out if there is going to be another attack.

Private grief counts just as much as grief in public.

All Harry's inner voices were speaking at once, a cacophony of jumbled thoughts trying to drown each other out. Hufflepuff spoke. Humans can't live like that, remember? and Harry's mind went silent for almost a full minute.

Hermione had on her formal robes, and if she hadn't slept much Harry certainly couldn't tell by looking at her. Hermione appeared to need less sleep than most people, although she still got tired. Harry suspected that in stressful situations she suffered no ill long term effects from having adrenaline coursing through her blood, so that she could stay awake much longer than a typical teenage girl. Her hair flowed smoothly as she turned her head to look around Harry's study, full of transcripts, notes, charts, and quickly drawn timelines. New documents, as the scorch marks on the walls and semi-melted shelving had been hurriedly replaced.

Even at times like this, she looks beautiful. Harry quickly pushed that thought aside. He couldn't afford a sudden burst of puberty. Not now. He reached for his new set of formal robes to change, they both knew they'd be late if he didn't hurry.

Hermione had walked over to a corkboard that Harry had used to pin notes and examined it carefully while Harry slipped into his formal robes. Times ran along the top from afternoon of Sunday March 6th until Monday Evening. Persons of Interest ran down the side. Harry's timeline was simple. He'd been smuggled out of Hogwarts, unconscious. Hermione double checked the information on her timeline, if anything was wrong it might mess up the investigation. But it was perfect. Most of the timelines were being filled in as part of the investigation. Draco's position at times had been recorded, several appearances in the hallway, his meeting with Hermione, there was a seperate detailed timeline on the Battle of Peverell and lots of lines and question marks there, ending with the discovery of Draco's body. There were large gaps.

"Any ideas?" Hermione asked, still focused on the corkboard. She wanted to apologize again, for not stopping things when she had a chance, but Harry had simply shrugged and said it was his fault.

"I've pinned down a lot of the how." Harry's voice sounded normal to himself. He wondered if it sounded that way to Hermione, or if it sounded colder. He'd had to summon the cold more and more, these last few days. "There are still some puzzles, and a lot of things that confuse me. But mainly ... I don't get the why. After the ... After we're done we'll go talk to Lockhart."

"You can call it a funeral, Harry" she said quietly.

"I'm not sure he's dead, Hermione," Harry said as he slid into his robes. "I mean, it's amazing Draco survived as long he did. But since he did, he had the near perfect mix of tools to fake his own death, and that can't be an accident..."

Hermione must have heard the swish of his robes, or some other indication that he was finished and dressed, because she spun around to glare at him.

"Harry James Potter. You will not mention anything to that effect at the funeral. Imagine what it would do to everyone. To Narcissa. Not to mention the Longbottoms. Outside of this room you will not breathe a word of Draco being alive until you have solid proof."

Her voice echoed throughout the room for a second, and then she continued, quieter. "Better for everyone to think he's dead and then get a shocked when he re-appears. Far better than false hope. Believe me."

Harry nodded, accepting the rebuke even though he'd had no intention of telling anyone. I'd just been discussing the problem. In any case, he attacked me, Harry thought, but he recognized this as one of those times when other people would just call him insensitive if he discussed his thoughts. They left his study, and Harry continued to review what he knew.

Harry had already rejected many hypothesis. The obvious one was that this was an attack against him, but Draco could have done that without attacking Peverell. At much less risk. Had the point been for Draco to fake his death? Why? Draco could have done that much easier, during a break from school. Harry turned this over and again it felt like he was missing information. He kept coming back to the fact that Draco hadn't killed him, but attacked him. Harry shook his head. He needed another angle of attack.

Consider the equipment Draco used, ignoring the goblin forged items for now. Where had Draco gotten all the potions? They seemed excessive, but then Harry realized he didn't really know how much these things cost. Still, beyond Draco's capability to brew. Had he contacted Snape? If so, he could have an arsenal of potions. After a moment or two of thought, Harry shook his head. Unlikely, and a complexity penalty to boot. Just assume that Draco bought everything, he was rich. Harry frowned and tried to consider another direction to view the problem from.

Harry and Hermione walked in silence, descending down the staircases, past the burnt rooms and missing tapestries, until they arrived at the main level of Hogwarts and joined the procession of students and teachers just as they headed outside.

Overhead the sky was a bright, beautiful blue, with not a cloud in sight, and flocks of birds frolicked in the spring air.

Students sniffled. Most Hufflepuffs were openly crying. Vincent had stood next to the rejuvenated Augusta Longbottom, who could have passed for a fifth year, and Neville's parents. They had cycled through shock, confusion, grief and anger as the ceremony went on before finally breaking down into quiet sobs during Pomona Sprout's eulogy. Few of the words registered with Harry, even though he'd stopped thinking about the investigation.

Now that services were over students milled around, hugging and talking in low murmurs. Professor Slughorn, in resplendent black robes, silk and flowing like water around his form, spoke clearly above the crowd.

"Slytherins."

Slughorn stood immobile for a second then turned and headed back indoors, away from the crowd and the grass and the rest of the mourners. As he turned he pulled his cowl over his round face. Professor Slughorn walked at a deliberate pace, and the students of his house fell in behind him, a solemn procession. Harry looked towards Hermione, who'd gone over to say a few words to Alice Longbottom. He didn't want to join her, didn't want to face them. Harry stood torn between the two groups. I don't have the words, I don't have any power here. Hermione motioned for him to go with a small gesture.

Vincent stood talking to Gregory, and then they both joined the procession. Professor Slughorn stood at the entrance back into Hogwarts. As each students passed by they covered their head with their hood, reminding Harry of medieval monks. Harry made his decision, falling in beside Gregory and Vincent, pulling the hood over his head as he passed into Hogwarts. They walked silently, although not down into the dungeons. The procession veered off, and Harry realized they were heading to the Muggle Studies lecture hall. All Slytherins walked together, each alone in thought for the entire descent.

They arrived back into the large hall. The map for the Muggle Naval simulation stood, empty and solemn behind the lecture podium. The students lined up in a large semi-circle around the podium, squeezing in, with almost no shifting and only the occasional cough or noise as Harry filed in and took the next available space. Harry stood silent, wondering at how easily everyone coordinated. The instinct to blend in, to follow the crowd turned this into a solemn event and Harry didn't want to be the one to ruin it. The first years came and took the center area in front of the podium. Professor Slughorn had apparently fallen in behind them once they'd entered Hogwarts. He entered the room last. No, next to last as Narcissa Malfoy stepped foot in the room, in simple black robes, her face still covered by the veil she'd worn through the funeral. Well, thought Harry, he'd invited all Slytherins. Narcissa hesitated, and stayed by the door.

Professor Slughorn walked to the podium, trailed by a walking chest that Harry hadn't seen before.

He stepped behind the lecturn and threw back his hood, and for the first time Harry could see the pained look on his face. Professor Slughorn had said a few words during the funerals, he'd praised Neville and Draco with a calm ferocity during his brief eulogy, but he'd shown no grief. Now he wiped his cheeks and motioned for the students to reveal their faces and Harry pulled back his hood, he felt ashamed at how many other wet faces there were in the crowd, and his cheeks flushed red.

Professor Slughorn opened his chest, which had stopped beside him, and pulled out a bottle and a goblet.

"This wine was a gift from a former student, one of four casks liberated from Grindelwald's cellars shortly after Headmaster Dumbledore defeated him, and on a happier day I'd tell you the story of how I got a cask, but it doesn't matter now." Professor Slughorn pulled out several more bottles. "I told myself that I'd only drink it when I accomplished something great. So I've been waiting. I don't particularly want to keep them anymore, and I can think of nothing better than to drink them right now."

Normally, the students would have broken into small conversations, gasped at the implications, but most everyone remained silent and the few students that started to say something stopped quickly when the glares of the others silenced them. Professor Slughorn dramatically pulled out a scroll out from inside his robes and rolled it open. He examined it for a second, then sighed and shook his head before rolling the scroll up.

"I had a prepared speech, but there were many kind words said at the funerals," said Professor Slughorn, carefully opening the first bottle and pouring some into his goblet, "and there were many true words, and they were lovely. But there are some words that should only be said in private."

He took a deep drink of the wine, and Harry saw his hands shaking as he took the first sip. Horace Slughorn swallowed the wine in a greedy gulp, paused for a second, and then slammed the goblet back onto the podium.

"Slytherin is the House of Failure," he said in a booming voice as he poured another glass of wine.

"I have this wine because I have done nothing of note, and I have done nothing of note because the vast majority of my ambitions were petty. I only had one great ambition: to mentor great students, you see. To live through their victories. And I have taught and nurtured talent, wonderful talent. I would brag and gloat on them, and wheedle my students into becoming more. They say that Slytherin is the House of Ambition, but to have ambitions means chasing your dreams. And many of us never catch them. But what is worse, what is oh so much worse is to accomplish everything you ever wanted."

"Then you wake up one morning and discover that you only possess things you used to want," he said, then drank a second cup of wine, and this time his hands were steady.

"I wanted to mentor the Greatest Slytherin since Salazar and I have now failed three times, in three different ways. For David Monroe I was just a callow new Potions Professor, and I had no idea what he would become. I missed that opportunity, so I kept my eyes focused on the next great one. And I spotted the next great fighting wizard and poured my energy into helping him. He went on to murder so many people, and I didn't see it coming. And to my shame, I did nothing to stop the monster I'd help create."

Professor Slughorn paused to drink another cup of wine, and finally the room gasped, as the implication was recognized. Harry started to say something, to try and tell Professor Slughorn that it wasn't his fault, that nothing could have fixed Voldemort, to ease the man's pain. But he dare not reveal what he knew, and if Professor Slughorn wanted to get drunk and drown his sorrows after a funeral, Harry understood. Well, he didn't understand the impulse but recognized that it was a common - even typical - response to death.

"And now, again, I recognize a student who had drive and an ambition - a worthy ambition, not like mine. A student born into a Noble House but nobody nobody is born into greatness. You become great by work, courage, cleverness and yes, by ambition. And now I've failed a 3rd time. Because today I buried Draco Malfoy. To Draco," he said, raising his goblet.

"To Draco," the room said in a chant, except for a quiet mewling sob that came from the doorway. Professor Slughorn drained his goblet and then pulled out a set of glasses, small thin glasses that Harry associated with champagne. "Does anyone else wish to say anything?" Professor Slughorn asked, as he poured some wine.

Gregory stepped forward and took the first proffered glass, then turned to face the rest of the students, who fell silent again. "When Dad explained to me, how he worked for Lucius Malfoy. I ... I was appalled. To be in someone's shadow, to be someone's assistant? To never be known for what I did. But as I got to know Draco, it didn't seem bad. He was my friend and Who wouldn't help their friend? But still, I could assist him while being my own person, flying for England in the World Cup," Gregory said, as the crowd gave a small cheer with a few scattered whistles. "I could help him, but the name of Gregory Goyle would also be known throughout the world, while Draco Malfoy's name would be relegated to hushed whispers in political circles."

Gregory paused, and when he spoke again his voice broke. "And now nobody will remember him, and my fame will outlive his. And it tastes like ashes in my mouth."

Gregory quickly drank the wine, face scrunched up, and then set down the glass on the podium. Professor Slughorn refilled it and handed it back to Gregory who had a confused look on his face until Professor Slughorn motioned that he was to hand the glass to someone else. Gregory stood there for a moment, looking around the room, but Blaise Zabini stepped forward and extended his hand.

Gregory passed the wine to him.

"I thought I had a rivalry with Draco; I was the glorious underdog fighting the scion of House Malfoy. I could see how we'd spar, over the years, but I'd subtly outmaneuver him to become Minister of Magic. I'd save the day. I'd get the girl. And now ...," Blaise's voice trailed off for a second, and he almost took a sip of the wine before quickly lowering the glass, "... now I know that when he invited me into his circle, it wasn't just a gambit, it was sincere. Because I don't know what he was doing, but it was bigger than me. I was playing a child's game. Draco probably thought it was cute. To Draco."

"To Draco," the room answered, as Blaise took just a sip of the wine, then held the glass out. Hestia Carrow took it.

"Why should he have gotten someone back, when I lost so much?" she said through tears, looking directly at Narcissa Malfoy. "I'm sorry. He got you back, even though it was more his family's fault than mine, but he came out unscathed. Maybe that was just another mask..." she took a sip of wine before remembering to add "To Draco," and while the room responded she passed the glass along then went over to Narcissa, who spoke to her quietly, before they embraced. Professor Slughorn had poured a few more glasses, which were slowly making their way around the room.

Daphne Greengrass held up a glass, and the room shifted its attention to her. Harry looked at her, at her soft green cheeks that had stayed dry throughout this entire day. She really is lovely, Harry thought. "It is right and proper for us to remember our friend. Draco would have wanted us to remember Neville Longbottom, too. Draco plotted with him. I suppose that's obvious. I thought he was plotting with me, too, but I guess not, since... Draco once called Neville his conscience, the only one that he felt was brave enough to publicly call Draco out if he thought he was wrong. That may be silly, but I was thinking back to last year, to the troll attack, and while the rest of us were frozen in the Great Hall only Harry tried to rescue Hermione ... and only Neville stood up to him."

"And now there are such terrible rumours floating around, and some people are saying Draco attacked Hogwarts, and some are saying that he saved it, and all I can think of is ... Whatever Draco was planning, Neville thought it was a good idea, too. To Draco and Neville."

Everyone said "To Draco," but only about half of the room added "and Neville," Harry noted, while reflecting on Daphne's speech. When Harry interviewed her yesterday Daphne had told him about the meeting in January, when Draco proposed going after the Hall of Prophecies. No doubt whatever Draco had told Neville in their private sessions had been very convincing. Draco had probably dosed himself with Veritaserum ... but that still didn't explain what Draco had planned, why he hadn't just killed Harry if he'd thought he was Voldemort.

Professor Slughorn had started mingling around the room while Daphne spoke, and now he was standing besides Harry. He offered a glass of butterbeer, and Harry looked down at it quizzically, his train of thought broken.

"Unless you'd prefer wine?" Slughorn said.

"No, this is fine," Harry replied. I don't need to cloud my judgment, especially now. Harry felt the rest of the room silence, as glasses stopped moving around and people turned to him.

"Everyone thinks I can just snap my fingers to fix things," he said, haltingly. "Draco knew better. I don't think Slytherin is the House of Failure. Humanity is. We get so many things wrong. A Muggle Prime Minister once said about America, 'That it always does the right thing, after it tries every other possibility' but it's not just one country. We stumble around, groping in the dark without a torch, doing the best we can. Is it any wonder we bang our knees or fall down stairs?"

Harry paused. He knew, at some level, that this plot had been directed against himself. Harry believed, but couldn't yet prove, that Draco may be alive. But if he was alive then he'd certainly planned to fake his own death. One of Draco's mantras was that A good move has multiple purposes and Harry kicked himself for just now realizing that Draco's death had unified House Slytherin, and there was no way Harry Potter would splinter them apart and undo Draco's (possibly) final plot.

"There are people who should have seen the attempted theft of Merlin's Chalice coming and stopped it. They were caught by surprise, and some of them are dead. Maybe I should have seen it coming and snapped my fingers, but I don't actually have any powers. Draco stumbled into this attack and managed to stop several adult wizards. He raised the alarm. He should have run away, but he pretended to lose to the attackers and then struck at a critical moment."

The students nodded, recalling the lesson they'd all learned in one form or another from the second defense lecture. Meanwhile, part of Harry recoiled at what he was saying. Harry still didn't understand all of Draco's plots. Publicly lauding Draco's plot was - at the very least - incautious, but it had been several days and they'd rounded up all the surviving attackers. Draco's plot had taken months to set up, and he couldn't vary it now without revealing he was alive. There was a risk in praising Draco. He'd set up the chess set where Harry would find it, and the message seemed clear. Draco was taking us both out of the game.

But in spite of all that, Harry still considered Draco a friend. He'd plot against him, but he couldn't bring himself to sully Draco's name. Especially not with Narcissa Malfoy in the room, grieving. If nothing else, she was innocent and didn't deserve this pain. Harry knew it was irrational to go the extra step and praise Draco instead of just mouthing a platitude.

"We heard from some Auror's at the funeral, praising Draco and Neville. I think when the truth comes out, their names will live on. To my friends. To Draco and Neville."

Harry noticed - as he drank the butter beer - that everyone responded "To Draco and Neville." Harry grimaced as he finished the glass. Harry knew butter-beer was non-alcoholic, but was it supposed to taste more like beer or more like a desert? Not that he had much in the way to compare it to. Professor Slughorn took the glass back and refilled it, moving among the students.

"I don't think Slytherin is the House of Failure," Vincent said. "I'm not more successful because I left. Maybe, maybe I failed Draco because I left. Not because of Slytherin. He wanted me to go, he wanted me to be happy and it cost him. I was supposed to protect him and I was gone...I'm so sorry..."

Gregory put his arm around Vince's shoulders as he was speaking, and hugged him and Lady Malfoy moved to join them. There was a silence, not awkward Harry thought, but extended, before a small voice said.

"I didn't want to be in Slytherin, not really." Everyone turned to Colin Creevey, who held a glass up high and spoke in a surprisingly steady voice for a first year addressing the rest of the house.

"You were following Harry Potter," chuckled Professor Slughorn. "So when ..."

"No!" Colin said, interrupting. "No. I was trying to follow Hermione Granger, but then she switched houses and when I tried to switch the Sorting Hat accused me of being too sneaky and sent me here..."

Colin didn't get to finish, because by the time he'd gotten halfway through his sentence Professor Slughorn's chuckles had turned into belly laughs and the rest of the room joined in and laughed uproariously. Narcissa's laughter sounded pure, like the ringing of wind chimes. Harry laughed so hard his throat started hurting.

"It wasn't so bad. I mean, I wasn't treated worse than any other first year, which is pretty bad, I guess." The room laughed some more at that. "But then came the Purple-Green war, and I know how a lot of you felt. Mad that I got to be the General, even though it was just random. And then I got murdered. But afterwards, I realized something. Harry could have taken over from me any time, like Daphne said. He probably should have, he was a better General. Harry was being polite, he was holding back."

"But Draco treated me just like any other enemy. Draco didn't condescend to me, he tried to crush me in every way he knew how and Draco got me killed. And then, since it was just a game, he came by later and told me that I'd done a good job and gave me some advice for next time. Maybe he thought I was a joke, but he never treated me like one. To Draco."

Pansy Parkinson had raised her glass during Colin's speech. The room barely finished "To Draco," when she started talking. Harry had spent the latter part of Colin's speech suppressing a cough, and now he could no longer help himself and was coughing quite loudly, doubled over.

"Harry?" said Gregory, "Do you need some water?" just as the fire in his throat spread to his chest and arms.

"No, I just..." Harry couldn't finish the sentence before his body spasmed with another fit of coughs. Unable to talk, Harry started signing with his right hand, getting out B-E-Z before his fingers spasmed uncontrollably and he fell to his knees. Harry heard several shouts. Professor Slughorn cast a spell Harry recognized as a linking spell from the Muggle War Simulation, but that didn't make sense. Several students rushed out the door or summoned their Patronus to fetch help. Someone was trying to push something into his mouth, and Harry opened his eyes to see Professor Slughorn looming in front of him, saying something about poison.

But the most likely poisoner would be Slughorn, Harry thought. He'd provided the drinks. Harry didn't have fine motor control but he jerked his arm and slapped the stone away out of Professor Slughorn's hands and screamed No! although it came out as a wail.

Two seconds later several spells knocked Professor Slughorn to the ground beside him, unblocking Harry's line of sight. Professor Slughorn raised his wand at Harry but several students rushed between them, and he didn't fire. With Slughorn no longer kneeling in front of him, Harry could see clear across the room.

The map on the wall now showed not the standard map for the Muggle Naval Simulation, but the room's layout. Names rushed across the display. Gregory Goyle and Vincent Crabbe - both written in elegant calligraphy - moved from besides the podium towards Tom Riddle. Goyle and Crabbe moved away from Narcissa Malfoy, who stood off in the corner of the room. The poison made thinking difficult, nothing made sense and then Harry saw the real Narcissa in the corner of his eye, facing away from him, unmoving. Staring up at the map on the wall and he focused on the name Tom Riddle and in a flash Harry understood. Vincent and Gregory were pouring spells into Horace Slughorn, although he appeared to already be unconscious. (That doesn't make sense, thought Ravenclaw, a Professor should be able to withstand two second years while the rest of the voices were screaming to Harry that he was dying).

Narcissa said "No," in a quiet voice, lifting her veil to get a better look at the wall.

Harry's vision started contracting, degrees falling away as his focus narrowed. His eyes stung from the smoke. Harry could see foam falling from his mouth to the floor. He heard Hermione's shout and the scream of a Phoenix. Narcissa Malfoy answered with a screaming No! as she whirled and fired a curse as his vision faded completely.

Chapter 59: Testament

For the second time in his life Harry sat in the Malfoy vault in Gringotts. This time nobody made him wait.

There had been rigorous security, of course. He'd been wanded, probed and studied, but allowed to keep his wand and pouch. Mad-Eye Moody had made it clear: under no condition would Harry Potter be left defenceless after two ambushes in as many weeks. He'd demanded that each party be allowed wands and personal guards.

Narcissa Malfoy had accepted graciously, Gringotts had not. Several increasingly heated letters OWLed back and forth.

Gringotts stated that Harry Potter was in no way exempt from typical bank security. While Gringotts (both the company and all individual employees) absolutely believed that Mr. Potter did not intend to steal anything from this (or any other vault) and took no position on the general ... unpleasantness currently being debated. That being said, Gringotts had a fiduciary responsibility to all their customers that mattered more than their (obvious!) sympathies towards Harry Potter. Why, if even mighty Peverell Hospital could be broken into, Gringotts would take no chances.

Politely, and with much legalese, Harry's request for personal security was denied.

At which point the magical government of Britain intervened, again requesting a one time waiver due to extenuating circumstances.

Gringotts initially responded with an outright rejection, then a letter examining in some detail just how much a waiver would cost. An hour latter, a letter marked with the Seal of the Chief Mugwump calmly suggested that if Gringotts did not feel comfortable hosting a meeting between two second year students and Narcissa Malfoy and that the security requirements of said meeting were beyond their ability to handle then Gringotts should simply publicly declare that fact, at which point of course other arrangements could be made.

After sending that letter (having stolen a supply of scrolls and an extra seal of the Chief Mugwump months ago), Harry fully expected a long missive stating something along the lines of 'we feel it is a gross mischaracterisation to refer to the Hermione Granger (aka The-Girl-Who-Revived) and Harry Potter (aka The-Boy-Who-Lived-And-Is-Also-Possibly-Voldemort) as two second year students and said forementioned gross mischaracterization understated the real threats involved. More litigious parties than Gringotts may consider that as a borderline libelous statement,' at which point the letter would continue with a ridiculously long list of counter-demands.

Gringott's actual response simply enumerated convenient times and a request for the typical 27 hours advance notice for the meeting, along with the standard boilerplate detailing in-vault guards.

Harry, feeling mildly insulted that Gringotts accepted (his own) characterization of himself as a mere second year student, briefly toyed with the idea of never using ironic self-effacement again.

And so it came to pass that Harry Potter walked into the Malfoy family vault to face Narcissa Malfoy ten days after her son's funeral. To Harry's surprise, Narcissa didn't appear active in the political drive opposing him. She'd confirmed the relevant facts when interviewed by the Daily Prophet. The only interview she'd given portrayed her as an outraged mother who'd just lost a child, nothing more. Narcissa hadn't attended the Wizengamot during the lengthy debates and votes for sanction, although she'd left instructions to vote for Gilderoy Lockhart's pardon.

Even if Harry wanted to, he dare not keep her under surveillance because somebody would notice (or perhaps an Auror would even leak the information) and he'd look even worse. But Narcissa Malfoy stayed well out of the public spotlight. By all accounts, she was too good an Occlumens for Harry to know if she was just playing the role of a grieving mother. But even if she secretly rejoiced in Draco's death (which Harry sincerely doubted) Narcissa had simply withdrawn from public society, as far as anyone could tell.

His contacts at the Prophet indicated she had not interfered in day-to-day operations the entire time she'd been back. Still, nobody could ever pin that on Lucius, back in the day. Not that direct interference had been necessary. In a situation like this you didn't need a cackling boss dictating the news. There would always be enough people (at all levels) who would consider it generally advantageous for their career to print news that helps the owner. So if the reporters merely imagined that's what Narcissa would want - to have Draco not die in vain - that was enough. The Prophet had printed stories about Harry's connection to Voldemort every day for the last week and a half. It boosted circulation.

Amelia Bones spent her days fighting Harry's political war. Harry understood people in abstract, but he had no special advantage in politics. Horace Slughorn had been investigating Hogwarts since his return just as a matter of routine intrigue. To cement his position. Once he'd sniffed that Harry was Tom Riddle he'd focused intently. Slughorn hadn't found anything solid (apart from the Maurader's Map that Draco provided) but he'd gotten enough circumstantial evidence to indicate that Harry sat behind the scenes, masterminding.

The Prophet parcelled these facts out, a steady stream of curious coincidences and "damning" evidence. Harry understood how people thought, and how mobs worked, but only at a theoretical level. Newspapers lived and died on this, and the country was dividing.

Every day he read the paper, as an internal debate raged.

If I were an uninterested 3rd party (but just as smart), I'd recognize the signs of a hatchet job and all the sloppy logic. said Ravenclaw.

But you'd still note the information, said Hufflepuff. Even if you discounted it you'd have to nudge up the probability that something strange was going on. Harry Potter may not be Dark Wizard level, but still, best to keep an eye on him. Some disturbing facts here.

Harry had some ideas how the Prophet placed him in the same room as Amelia Bones over winter break. And while they didn't have absolute proof, they'd gotten it right on at least that occasion.

And at some point, you'd decide to investigate this Harry Potter yourself, said Gryffindor.

None of his voices said "I'd prove his innocence." If Harry could do that, he wouldn't be in this mess with Draco in the first place.

One lone voice said, I'd prove Harry Potter wasn't a monster.

At which point Slytherin chimed in, Assuming you didn't fall for the one subtle (and hard to disprove) lie the Prophet slipped in.

Harry had been watching for the subtle lie. So far it hadn't appeared.

Still reviewing the latest Daily Prophet, Harry was escorted into the vault with Narcissa and the Malfoy family solicitor for the last two decades, a Mr. Erasmus Farnsworth, Esq. As Harry folded up his paper, he reflected that he'd never seen a Wizard Lawyer (Amelie handled that). Harry recognized the traditional lengthy waxed black moustache, honed to a pair of fine points. The entire effect would inspire feelings of inadequacy in Snidely Whiplash, but it looked no less ridiculous than those terrible wigs that Muggle judges wore, in Harry's opinion. Farnsworth sported a pair of minuscule round eyeglasses, attached to his hat via a small black rope. Narcissa still wore mourning robes and a veil. She sat on the other side of the table, while Mr. Erasmus Farnsworth nodded solemnly and offered the seats to Hermione, then Harry.

By agreement, there were only four seats at the table. Mad-Eye Moody stood back with the guards. Harry couldn't be sure, but it looked like there was significantly less gold than when he'd been here with Lucius and Draco. House Malfoy remained wealthy, but Draco had spent a lot of his assets over the last year. As his eyes scanned the room, a thought popped into Harry's head. Check if Draco moved a bunch of cash around in the last few months to use after he died. House Malfoy may not be familiar with forensic accounting. They probably are, but you never know.

The lawyer took out a scroll and started to read in a solemn voice. "Lady Malfoy, Miss Granger, Mr. Potter, I have asked you here as per the wishes of the deceased for the reading of the will of Draco Malfoy."

"How can that be?" said Harry, shoving down any embarrassment he felt. Hermione kicked him under the table. As far as anyone else was concerned, Draco was most certainly dead. "I mean, Draco had not attained the age of majority. Is this will binding?"

Mr. Erasmus Farnsworth, Esq, pulled off his glasses and they dangled from the rope, while he stared at Harry. His voice was lighter, with more velocity than before. "Technically, this will can be contested by any party directly related to the Testator, named in the will, or named in any prior will or revoked codicil. As Draco had filed no prior relevant legal documents, all parties who could contest the will are located here. If there is a desire to contest we can proceed with negotiation or non-binding arbitration, and should no agreement..."

"I understand," said Harry. The lawyer reeled his glasses back up and perched them on his nose, glancing to all parties to make sure there were no questions. Then he continued in his solemn, slow voice.

"I Draco Malfoy, son of Lucius, son of Abraxis Lords of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Malfoy, son also of Narcissa daughter of Druella Lady of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Black, scion and heir of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Malfoy, declaring that I am of sound mind and body, do hereby declare this my last will and testament."

As the reading paused, Harry marveled at how the lawyer could say all of that in a single breath, and still sound somewhat elegant.

"I do hereby bequeath the Sigil Cane of House Malfoy to Lord Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres of House Potter, so that its presence should not disturb the Lady Narcissa Malfoy with sad memories, on the condition that he acknowledges that he retains it only in stewardship until such time as Narcissa Malfoy produces another child of any name, and that afterwards it will be the property of said child, with his or her parents as regent."

Harry had questions, but he didn't interrupt. Narcissa let out a plaintive sob at the mention of another child.

"If Mr. Potter does not agree to the request, the Sigil cane shall be disposed of following the standard set by the Last Will and Testament of Lucius Malfoy as if I had preceded him in death."

"I bequeath the Diary of Draco Malfoy to Lady Hermione Granger of House Granger in the hopes that she heeds its advice."

"I have arranged for correspondence to be delivered to appropriate parties, as per my instructions."

"All remaining possessions I do leave to Lady Narcissa Malfoy of House Malfoy. Should she precede me in death, I leave everything to Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres or his designated heirs, to use as best he sees fit to enhance the goal of saving the world."

The solicitor took of his glasses and rubbed his nose. "Signed by Draco Malfoy on December 22nd, witnessed by Griphook of Gringotts bank, sealed with Gringotts seal," he displayed the scroll for inspection. "Are there any objections to the will as I have just read?"

Narcissa shook her head, still crying. Hermione's head moved imperceptibly, while Harry simply said no. The cane might be trapped, but I can let Mad Eye inspect it and just shove it away if it's dangerous.

"In that case," the solicitor said, "your correspondence and items." He placed Draco's cane on the table in front of Harry. It was swaddled in a black velvet cloth, and Mr. Farnsworth briefly opened the top, revealing the silver Krait handle, then closed it. On top of the cane he gently set down a sealed letter with the words "Harry Potter" in Draco's elegant handwriting.

The lawyer moved smoothly over and placed a small black book in front of Hermione. Harry recognized it as Draco's notebook he'd used for most of the year. I thought it was just a list of notes, not a diary, he thought. And we'll need to inspect it as well.

In front of Narcissa, the lawyer placed a letter.

Harry broke the seal and started to read.

To my friend Harry Potter,

I write you this letter on Winter Break inside Malfoy Vault, safe from any scrying. Here it will stay, hopefully never to be read, because I have left my solicitor instructions to deliver this letter (and burn all others to you unopened) if I die betraying you.

This is my final plot: If you are Voldemort - or should I say, Tom Riddle - I earn some measure of respect for recognizing you and using all tools in my power to oppose you. Though I failed, at least I failed trying my utmost.

And if you are not...may you understand and gain some measure of wisdom to aid you in the future.

I wish I could have believed you. Or believed in you. My life would've been better.

I know I may be wrong. I hope I am wrong, that I'll soon return to Gringott's and rip this letter up, or perhaps show you some day when we are older. But if you are reading this ... this is not an apology, though I believe you will understand.

Know that I believe you meant well and that I don't believe you are the exact same monster who killed Father. I know you couldn't save him. This is not about him, except for the fear that haunted me all fall term – repeating his mistake of backing a Dark Wizard. It haunts me, the knowledge that I could be wrong, either way. But I think that if I don't act, don't try to resolve this impossible problem, it will haunt me even more.

I am not yet committed, when I write this. I am setting plans in motion – using every resource at my disposal. But I lack information I sorely need. My plots remain flexible, I am ready to pivot them to assisting you and Hermione, an ambition worthy of my family's name.

But if you are reading this, I have failed. Hopefully I am wrong, so in this letter I do my utmost to help you, as I should have done from the beginning.

I have little to offer. My Diary is now merely a book. It will offer advice only to a true Malfoy in name and blood, and I have no heir. The Sigil Cane of my Father will be of some use, though its power is keyed to my family as well. I doubt it will answer your summons, thought I have not tested that experimentally. What I can offer is advice.

All strengths have a corresponding weakness. You saw how I deployed honesty as a weapon. Know that I desperately wished you were not an Occlumens, that you could swear under one drop of Veritaserum that I was wrong. I almost did trust Hermione, despite her training. I do not think deception becomes her, and no magic can hide her inherent goodness. She is the best of us.

I doubt even you could corrupt her but I know you could deceive her, if necessary. We know that is your true power, if not your true nature.

Your skills as a thinker blinds you to people, normal people. I was not your equal in thinking, but this let me see them more clearly. I wish I could have convinced myself to act as your minion, to smooth your politics and ease your way. Gregory and Vincent can help you. I believe they will want to, and I will arrange my plots to ensure that they have no meaningful foreknowledge. They have never plotted against you. In my correspondence to them, I've asked them to answer any questions you may have. I expect there will be a full investigation in any case.

Your strength makes you arrogant. You must temper that.

If you are innocent, examine my mistakes and teach others how to avoid them.

And treasure family. One day you will have a family of your own. I imagine your children will teach you wisdom, Harry. I know that once I understood Father's mistakes - and the motives behind them - that is when I felt perhaps I could become wise.

Your friend,

Draco Malfoy

Harry stared at the letter. Part of him wanted it to be a plot, to have some deeper subtlety beyond the plain confession of the words. A part of Harry thought I could have avoided this. His heart pounded with guilt and shame. He looked over at Hermione and she'd was still just sitting there, the diary untouched. Narcissa cried as she read her letter, but a wry smile was on her face as tears slid down her cheek. Harry started to re-read his letter, but as he did so Hermione reached out and pulled the diary across the table and opened it quickly. Harry could see over her shoulder that all the pages were blank, which made no sense. He'd seen Draco write in this almost every day. Well, every day I saw Draco.

Hermione slowly flipped through the pages, bewildered, then started to close the diary. Right before the diary shut she let out a small gasp and re-opened it to the front page. What had been blank now showed a small sketch of an urn. No, a vase. Slowly the sketch added shading and a design. The pencil drew in two flowers that Harry couldn't identify. The lack of colours made it difficult, perhaps they were roses. Brisk, clean lines filled out the sketch with details and suddenly the motion stopped, the sketch complete.

And then in Draco's elegant cursive, the signature D.M. and, underneath the words appeared

Save Them All

Hermione wept as Narcissa and Harry tried to console her.

A minute later, Alastor Moody - having quietly moved closer during the proceedings - reached over the table, snatched Draco's Diary, and toss it into a sack.

"That was left to me," Hermione protested, wiping away tears. Alastor cut her off.

"Could be a trap," Mad-Eye said, adding the Sigil to the sack. "Never trust anything."

Harry waited for the end of the sentence and then realized that Mad-Eye Moody did not intend to add any qualifiers. Nothing reasonable like, Never trust a gift from someone who has plotted against you, or Never trust a Malfoy or Never trust a gift from someone who clearly intends to oppose you or even somewhat reasonable advice like Never trust anything that was disguised under your nose for a year and may be more than it seems.

No, never trust anything. Full stop. It probably sounded better in Latin.

Harry looked over at Hermione - who looked disturbingly angry - and at Narcissa Malfoy, who did not seem offended at all.

"Lady Malfoy. You don't mind the implication?"

"Lucius never touched a gift unless it was thoroughly inspected, or he trusted the giver implicitly, or knew the full provenance, or felt the giver was a 'milquetoast incapable of anything truly dangerous.' Draco plotted against you. Which exception should apply?" She shook her head as she said it. "No offence was intended. It's like the gift of the wine. Your watchdog's job is to protect you; he would have done the same that had been left to you by Dumbledore himself."

Alastor grumbled about intended offense under his breath, but if Narcissa Malfoy could hear it she gave no response. Mr. Farnsworth had said nothing during this time, but simply stared at his watch, like the entire conversation was just another billable hour. In fact, now that Harry thought about it, Draco's lawyer had been studying the time quite intently ever since delivering their correspondence.

"So, they aren't dangerous?" Hermione asked.

"I won't speak to the Sigil, that's was Lucius and he asked me never to handle it. But the Diary? That's simply the received wisdom of House Malfoy passed down from generation to generation. Lucius and I had no qualms giving it to Draco. In any case, I think if it posed a danger it would have been given to him," at this Narcissa nodded towards Harry, "instead of you."

Harry listened to Narcissa's words, but during her speech her lawyer had stopped staring at his watch and reached into his satchel. Even if Harry hadn't noticed that, Alastor's abrupt shift of focus would have startled him, but the lawyer simply pulled out two small letters, one labeled "Harry Potter," and the other labeled "Gringotts." Mr. Erasmus Farnsworth, Esq, walked over to Harry and handed him the second letter, then glanced at his watch again.

"You ... you are under an Unbreakable Vow," Harry recognized the signs now, Draco's lawyer was too punctual. Of course it made sense that the best lawyers, the most expensive ones would be bound not by something so weak as the threat of disbarment or other legal sanctions. The best lawyers would be bound to follow their client's instructions that didn't violate any laws. So long as they paid.

"We need to leave," Harry said, opening up the letter.

Harry,

Our lawyers may be cute, but even they know how to argue grey areas of the law.

My letter to Gringotts will be delivered in ten minutes. I suggest you be someplace defensible by then.

"Guards, open the vault! We're leaving," Harry announced to the room, quickly standing up. The two goblins gave a small bow and then started the process of unsealing the door. "Lady Malfoy, my respects. But we're going back to Hogwarts. Mr. Farnsworth, I don't suppose you would be willing to advise us ..."

"I am bound not to take on any potential conflicts of interest for at least one year plus a day after the end of my service," he said, eyes still firmly on his watch.

"Of course, just checking," Harry waited impatiently for the guards to open the vault door, which took several seconds. Hermione had caught up to them by now, and even Mad Eye Moody seemed agitated as he glanced around the room.

"Harry, what's the matter," Hermione asked.

Harry glanced at the guards. They still wore their magical eyepieces and goggles. They couldn't have overheard him, not unless he addressed them specifically. "Draco's going to try and convince the goblins we transfigured money."

"They won't possibly believe him," Hermione said, but Mad Eye's single barked laugh ended the conversation as the vault door swung open.

Author's Note - Thanks again for my proofreader. Next chapter in one week.

Chapter 62: Thirty-Four Years Later, Pt 2

Li Kao, personal secretary to Alexio Vasconcelos, stood in front of his boss's desk. A short, wiry man who wore asian robes, Ko placed a sealed file on the desk and cleared his throat. Alexio hadn't changed after the Council meeting and still wore the traditional robes with a formal serape draped over his shoulders and down his back instead of his typical ratty robes he wore in his private office. Alexio looked up at Kao, who pointed to the formal invitation pushed off to the side, where it had been sitting for nearly two weeks.

"You need to decide, and soon. They expect an answer," Kao said.

Alexio ignored it, scowling. He reached over to the new file instead and opened it.

"I'll decide tonight," Alexio said simply, and his secretary turned away, satisfied. The soft swish of silk announced Kao's departure while Alexio read slowly through the file. Routine requests. He thought briefly, then jotted several short memos in English and Portuguese and sealed them. As the door closed behind his secretary's disappearing form Alexio let out a sigh and rubbed his eyes. He allowed himself a moment of rest.

Alexio took out his wand and warded the envelopes. These weren't wards to protect his memos, there was nothing in those memos of note. But it wouldn't do to let those spying on him know that. Alexio didn't have perfect security. Nothing ever was perfect. But between codes, wards, and obscurity it was the best he could do. He dropped the envelopes into the "out" basket, stood up, and looked out through the penthouse window over downtown Rio and Alexio Vasconcelos - secure in his private sanctum - took a moment to reflect.

Alexio stared out across the city. He never tired of looking down at it. Rio had transformed. The last five years had seen pollution drop dramatically as clean energy came online. Alexio's magic helped pay for the factories but it was pure technology, unlike most of his ventures. No doubt that was why Kao Li had sent his resume, looking for experience for a wizard who dealt with both worlds. Working with the powerful always appealed to any recent graduate, but surely Harry Potter had twisted Kao's ear, asked him to keep his eyes open. Still, Kao had worked out well. Having a diligent Englishman keep an eye on his more relaxed employees kept them diligent and taught good habits, no matter how much they grumbled. It helped immensely.

As far as Kao knew, he'd worked (and occasionally spied on) a good but misguided Wizard to help his former Headmaster.

Alexio had moved slowly. Building an empire while deflecting attention took time.

Alexio's eyes glanced around the room, such a far cry from the attic he'd lived in during his first year while learning the language and using his rather monstrous physique to explore the city and society as a muggle bodyguard and thug. Strong and silent. That work let Alexio mingle among the elite, visible but in many ways unseen by them, overlooked as servants often are. After two years, finally confident he spoke well, Alexio opened his mouth to make introductions. Which lead to deals with many, and opened up doors to the halls of power.

Alexio walked those Halls smoothly, negotiating from some and simply taking what he required from the truly evil. The world did not miss them.

For years Alexio acquired power in the shadows, never overtly. It would not do to attract non-local attention. Not until all the pieces were in place.

The light of the moon let Alexio glimpse his reflection in the windows. His somewhat youthful looks had faded into middle age. At least no lines creased across his face, they were smoothed out by his extra weight and pulled taught by his jowls. He'd let himself go, no longer the hard enforcer. Alexio didn't spend any time out on the streets down below, and had never had a taste for exercise. He still kept his head shaved - when he'd been younger the baldness helped intimidate those who might be otherwise inclined to test him. Now he felt like letting his hair grow back would be interpreted by his enemies as a sign of weakness. But his body was weakening, although at a much slower rate than a muggle. Alexio had settled into middle age a decade ago, perhaps he should finally admit it. He'd already considered embracing a softer look to go with his rounder face.

Only here, only alone did he dare to contemplate on how far he'd come from the boy who'd been Draco Malfoy. Alexio removed a few of the barriers in his mind to converse with himself and closed his eyes.

Draco Malfoy opened them.

Draco didn't flinch at the reflection. He hadn't flinched after the first few times he caught a glimpse of himself in the mirror, but he still felt the body he inhabited didn't match his personality, although he'd built his persona around it. Perhaps one day he'd change back, once he'd saved the world. Draco hadn't dared keep a locket of his blond hair. No traces of his former life or his youth, back when he'd been thin and handsome. But wizards had gotten quite good at plastic surgery. One day, with magic, he could have his body changed. As long as nobody at Peverell inspected him too closely. For now, he didn't look handsome, merely ominous.

Ominous had suited Draco's purpose.

Draco looked at the invitation to the Convocation, where Harry planned to resolve the final negotiations to undo the Statute of Secrecy. Kao was obviously Harry's agent, but keeping him as a personal assistant built credibility. He'd passed along some damning secrets to Harry, but not the truly important one. Harry Potter would much more easily believe in some petty corruption and abuse, some questionable ethics. True innocence was always suspicious, to Draco and Harry.

Draco respected Li Kao, formerly of House Hufflepuff and son of the now famous auror. Draco admired his drive. Of course Kao had been one of Harry's obvious moles, but Draco ensured that he (and the others) were well fed and placated, happy in their discoveries. The others he ran in circles, chasing leads that invariably led to a juicy but ultimately irrelavant morsel. Kao was kept close.

Neither Alexio nor Draco felt inclined to waste the boy's talents merely because of his split allegiance.

Alexio Vasconcelos hadn't led the local opposition against Harry Potter. But he'd aided it in subtle and not-so-subtle ways. That's what Harry would expect from a wizard who had been building his fortune and power by working between the two worlds. Once magic was revealed, his competitors would understand how they'd been beat, and be able to take appropriate precautions. The first envoy from the Chief Mugwump of England had shown up fifteen years ago, when he was still a local power. Just a friendly visit, trying to negotiate support. Alexio remembered the poor lad's look as he ranted and raved, all emotion to the boy's logic. That boy had probably never met anyone fundamentally illogical since entering Hogwarts, and he ... what was his name?

Alexio had forgotten his name.

Humbolt, Draco whispered deep inside Alexio, Horatio Humbolt.

Ah yes, Alexio whispered back.

Alexio sent Horatio Humbolt packing, angrily accosting him for daring to nit pick the actions of a great man.

The threats arrived two years later, snide insinuations that the investigations into his past had turned up the dark secrets he'd run away from Portugal to hide, and pointing out his frequent violations (or near-misses) of the Statute could be investigated more vigorously than the local government had done, but if he joined the movement for repeal... why, then he wouldn't have to break any more laws.

Alexio had allowed himself a brief smile, that day. But it had quickly faded as he realized that it could mean that the investigator believed it, or had merely wanted him to believe it. The game is played on so many levels, it gets tiring sometimes, Father. He'd filed the letter away and toned down his political maneuverings regarding the Statute, playing the part of a cowed businessman and minor Lord. Kao had been next, a bit too eager to be hired, not demanding his value, which he obviously knew.

Many times over the years Draco had tired of the game and secretly hoped that one day he'd be able to stroll into Peverell, confess and apologize. To be able to announce that he'd finally found some proof of Harry's innocence, that it was all just a mistake. For years he'd held out hope, until he finally confirmed that someone (no doubt Harry or acting on his behalf) had destroyed the Hall of Prophecy, removing Draco's last possible source for independent proof. At that point, Alexio no longer squandered any time in doubt and hope. He redoubled his efforts to build a sufficient power base and delay Harry Potter. Augusta Longbottom had never forgiven Harry, so he'd fed her information through proxies, studied, and waited. Alexio Vasconcelos had made fortunes greater than most countries and had spent most of it gaining real power. And he'd succeeded.

Millions relied on him. He'd used them, profited from them. They praised him for it.

Father would be proud, Draco agreed.

As Alexio consolidated his power, he'd consult with Draco. They tried to deduce Harry's endgame. The Chief Mugwump never did anything obviously malicious, but then again, he did nothing obvious. Alexio spent the last decade content to toss delays in Harry's way while building influence for the decisive moment. Delay still is the strongest form of denial, after all. But Alexio's hands would be tied when the Statute of Secrecy got repealed. Alexio held a comparative advantage because he skirted the Statute, whereas Harry (and especially Hermione) did not. Freed from its restriction, Harry stood better placed to use the full power of the scientific method afterwards.

Draco absentmindedly fiddled with his golden ring. It reminded him of Hogwarts, the months he'd worn the silver ring that warned him of Legilmency, before he'd finished his own training. Back when he played at being Alexio, before he'd completely inhabited the persona. Alexio never played with his wedding band in public, but sometimes when he was alone, particularly when he spent a few minutes looking at the city, he just twisted it around his finger. Alexio stared at the city, contemplating whether he should attend the Convocation.

I am still angry at Lord Potter's refusal to visit me in Rio those two years ago, Alexio thought. Declining would just be my impetuous nature, it would not arouse suspicion.

We are powerful, but not political powerful enough to require a personal visit. Harry's acceptance would have angered others, Draco countered. There is nothing to read beyond that, although the excuse would hold. Alexio's refusal is based on hubris. Our refusal ... are we afraid? If Harry has managed to unlock the secrets of the Maurader's Map, we would be revealed.

If he had done that, he would have given it to a trusted ally years ago, Alexio reminded him. But he may posses some personal magic that he cannot transfer. We cannot rule out that chance that we'll be discovered, in a situation under his control.

The security for the Convocation would be as air-tight, despite Mad Eye's absence. Alexio had spent decades neutralizing Alastor Moody, who now lived as a hermit in a secluded woods, growing his own food, killing anyone who tried to get close. Mad Eye would live forever, if he didn't starve to death. Draco knew he'd never be able to kill Mad Eye, whose security was perfect. It could be, because Mad-Eye no longer cared to do anything useful. Nudging Mad-Eye's paranoia worked well enough. Draco smiled, remembering this obvious insight he'd learned from his heist, the first one. So, for the Convocation, Harry had delegated security to the best remaining aurors. Still, they were impressive. But no security could predict everything, and again Draco had no plans to take anything out or into the Convocation. That would be impossible, just as stealing the Philosopher's Stone would have been, so many years ago.

We are at an inflection point, Draco said. Apart from advancing his plans, the repeal of the Statute will reduce Hermione Granger's influence on Harry. She will gain notoriety a second time, and helping the less fortunate will distract her. She will be mobbed by them, and her compassion will overcome her judgement for years. Her natural cautious advice to Harry will be reduced.

Fortunately Alexio didn't have to steal the security plans this time. He'd simply demanded assurances and coordination with his personal bodyguards and he'd studied them himself with Draco. They weren't complete, but what he'd been shown had been exhaustive.

Alexio had smiled at the inclusion of Basilisks. That's when they'd devised his latest plan - radiation poisoning. Still incredibly difficult to deal with, despite all the advances in magic and medicine. No, the optimal cure to radiation poisoning remained brute force. More accurately, brute time. Allow yourself to be turned to stone and simply wait for radioactive decay to solve the problem.

If we detonated our device near the Convocation, Harry would no doubt pounce on the plan of turning himself (and as many around him) into statues, Draco had declared. And so they'd gotten to work over the last year, arranging everything.

The flow of traffic on the highway below reminded Draco of a sinuous silvery Krait. Draco wished he could cast his Patronus and see it again for the first time in over three decades. Only Healani's birth, three years ago, convinced him he'd ever be able to cast it again. He'd never dared - of course - lest some unknown discovery reveal him after all these years. Assuming I am not already revealed.

Draco turned and walked away from the window and over to the table where he picked up a glass and sipped the last bit of scotch. Although Alexio never played, Draco sometimes read the daily (muggle) chess column, today's was covering one of Capablanca's great games. Draco hadn't played in decades, but he enjoyed seeing the games of the Grandmasters. Capablanca was the local favorite, of course.

Twenty days until the Convocation, plans mostly done. Draco wondered if they'd be enough. Had he missed something? The security plans probably had some mis-information. Was Potter too powerful? He'd gained 34 years of time, and spent it all wisely, and Draco still didn't know.

Lord Potter had to juggle so much more, Alexio offered. We have had more efficient use of time. And we are attacking, not defending.

Harry has his own plans, Draco answered.

They'd considered as many angles as possible. During his thuggish past, Alexio had collected curses, gathered any attack and spell he could torture out of other Dark Wizards. His politics hadn't taken much time, at least not until recently.

Draco poured another glass of scotch and considered the decision: attend the convocation or not? Both had risks.

Draco wondered how any playwright would treat this tale, if they somehow discovered it. Would they consider these thirty-five years as one unbroken path. Inevitable? Probably, but they would be wrong. But perhaps it would make a better play, which is why they would write it that way. That story had dramatic tension. Improvisation had been necessary, it could have gone many ways.

Alexio nodded, in silent conversation with Draco. There is a story, possibly even true. José Raúl Capablanca was with a gathering of experts, before he was terribly famous. And they were boasting about how far in advance they could calculation positions. And each expert added to the number. One would say, 'I see five moves ahead,' and the next would say ten, and the next would say twelve, and Capablanca said 'I see only one move ahead,' and when the other experts protested that he was much better than they were, he added 'but it is always the best move.'

They sipped whiskey.

Alexio and the small part of him that remained Draco pondered the problem. The Convocation would change the world. And, as far as they were concerned, the only conceivable spot for an ambush.

But who would ambushing who?

If Lord Potter knows, we will be captured and lose, Alexio said.

And if Harry doesn't know, Draco replied, the world would be saved. At least for another few centuries. although the casualties will be horrific.

We do not shy from such things, Alexio reminded him.

We need more time, Draco thought. Harry Potter remained too clever and increasingly powerful. The world was too important.

We do not have that luxury. We must decide. Against a clever opponent there is always risk. You taught me that.

Alexio made his decision, he walked back over to his desk, took out the elegant invitation. He quickly marked a note that he would attend, but only after his security detail had been there and returned briefing him to his satisfaction. He added a footnote stating that Alexio Vasconcelos understood Lord Potter's concerns with security, but he would not walk in blindly. He tossed the letter into the outbox, unsealed. Kao would read it, of course. And he would understand his boss' reluctance.

A powerful. arrogant man like Alexio would not be treated like a lackey, even by the Chief Mugwump of England. This he would relay to Lord Potter.

Draco sighed. There may still be some better way, but I haven't spotted it yet. Perhaps there is still time to improvise.

Perhaps he'd discover some other solution. Doubtful, but he had to take that chance.

Draco hoped that Harry Potter wouldn't spot the ambush. He'd surely work out the solution in time but he'd be busy and have no time to ponder how he'd gotten into such a dire position. Draco didn't worry about escape, Harry's own security would work against them. And of course his own wards would obliterate those who fled hastily. And on a purely magical level, few could stand up to his might.

No, Draco Malfoy hoped Harry wouldn't see the wand leveled at him and have that one second to recognize his failure. Or worse, recognize the hand holding the wand. Draco Malfoy and the man he created would never shy away from mass murder to save the world.

Still, he hoped to spare his friend's feelings.

If Draco Malfoy failed, he would fail as a Slytherin should, trying his utmost. Succeed or fail, Draco wondered if Harry would forgive him. When he realized.

He never wondered about Hermione. She would not. Perhaps after all this was over, Draco would - if he survived - try to rescue Dumbledore. He'd found some tantalizing leads over the last decade, but hadn't dared take the time to explore them fully. But he still had more pressing concerns.

Draco retreated back into the hidden recesses of his own mind as Alexio left his office to announce that he would attend the Convocation in a few weeks, and he wanted to take a small vacation and spend time relaxing with his wife and daughter.

Author's Note - This concludes the story, barring an epilogue I may write next year. I personally think that the universe has a wide variety of stories left to tell (both in HPMOR, DMPOR and related) but I have said what I wanted. I intended merely a novella at most.

(Which reminds me, thanks go out to the inestimable u/veruchai who helped proof my final five or so chapters. I should have asked for help much earlier, since my eyes gloss over my own mistakes. There are still mistakes in the later chapters and they are still my fault - I sometimes revise at the last moment. He also shed light on obtuse and unclear writing).

As the saying goes "I don't want to write, I want to have written," and pulling together over 180k words in under ten months is more than I expected. I've discovered some strengths and their corresponding weaknesses along the way, and I'm sure that others have noticed them as well. Some people are annoyed at how this turned out for a variety of reasons. This story isn't what they expected and my idea of an intellectual ambush (to put the reader in Harry's frame of mind) turned off many.

But while it may not have been the story you hoped was coming, it was the story I intended to tell. I found myself intensely interested in writing it, which made it easy - well, less difficult - to put words on the screen at a brisk pace, and I found myself adding side arcs that probably led to this looking like it would be more 'complete' than not. But I had always intended it to be what it is - an origin story. I've struggled with other writing projects and had (until this year) simply decided that I was incapable of putting together a long story. Now that I have discovered I was wrong, so now I will revisit some of my original ideas and see which hold my interest, after I take a break, and how I can pick a story that plays to my strengths and hides my weaknesses.

I hope the reasons I made the choice to have flash-forwards and show what happened indirectly are now understandable, even if you think them wrong.

As these are original works I doubt I will post them here. I will also continue writing about board games at my website (taogaming dot wordpress dot com).

I may write smaller works - and I do have an epilogue in mind. The biggest shock to me was how much fun it was to write Quirrell's lecture. If I did come back to this universe, I think that Quirrell-The Lost Lectures would be wonderful.

If you are now desperate for other HPMOR fan fiction, I recommend the sub-reddit r/hpmor to find others. If you lurk or post there, you already know that the clear best continuation (in terms of writing) is 'Significant Digits,' which is the only one I have consistently read without fear that there would be much cross-contamination (since it skipped ahead seven years). I would have read it in any case, it is so well crafted, and I've been pleased (for no rational reason) by some points of convergent evolution between our stories (totally unintended by both sides). I put ideas on paper, he is a master wordsmith.

I never felt more correct in my decision to not show Hermione's harrowing of Azkaban then after I read his version. Even if you don't read the full story, read that chapter (16).

I also would like to thank the author of Ginny Weasley and the Sealed Intelligence (which I stopped reading when I decided to make this a full fledged story) for convincing me that Lockhart could make a worth-while addition to this story.

Chapter 64: Gates of Ivory and Horn, Epilogue Pt 2

"The Angel hearing this became almost blue

but mastering himself he grew yellow,

& at last white, pink & smiling, and then replied:

'Thou Idolator, is not God One?

& is not he visible in Jesus Christ?

and has not Jesus Christ given his sanction to the law of the ten commandments,

and are not all other men fools, sinners, & nothings?"

Harry Potter stared at the Kraken gently floating in the distance.

It stretched across his entire field of vision, covering the full arc. Directly in front of him was the thorax and one large tentacle that branched off towards him before drifting down from the light blue water in front of him and disappearing in the inky black depths of a crevasse that marked the edge of Atlantis. The tip of a second tentacle lolled through Atlantis' main agora, twisting between buildings like an errant oil pipeline from the bygone days of fossil fuels. Other tentacles trailed away in various directions to his (current) left side.

Presumably the head was off to his right, perhaps a nautical mile or two distant. Harry couldn't see it as the body disappeared into the murky ocean in the distance. A dolphin gamboled along the edge of the Kraken, nudging it once or twice. Schools of fished pirouetted in their eternal dance in the background, splitting up and regrouping according to simple rules to produce complex beauty. Harry's gaze lingered on the dolphin for a second. Its behaviour increased the probability that Harry's research was correct, that the Kraken wasn't a threat, assuming dolphins understand Krakens better than humans. The dolphin didn't seem afraid of the slumbering Kraken.

The Kraken didn't bother Harry.

He'd practiced dealing with Krakens. He'd made detailed plans on dealing with any number of magical aquatic beasts, both common and uncommon. Krakens were rare, and had been considered mythical for centuries, but they existed and so Harry had prepared. The Ancient Libraries of Pacifis contained records dating back nearly fifteen hundred years tied, woven in giant kelp strands. They were knotted into the language of Merfolk much like ancient Andeans used knotted strings as records and books. As tempting as it had been, Harry hadn't bothered learning to read archaic Mermish. He'd simply hired experts to literally comb through the library and summarize the information for him.

There were three references that contained the rings of truth, and not just tall tales passed along. From those Harry hoped he knew what to expect. Krakens were notoriously difficult to deal with physically but had no specialized mental defenses. An unnamed Viking from the early twelfth century had Imperiused a Kraken that had happened to be lolling on the surface near his skiff. But the viking had gotten lucky that the beast had ignored him. Much like anything else, a strength often implied a corresponding weakness. Krakens rarely bothered attacking anything smaller than a ship displacing ten-thousand tonnes, and probably couldn't even detect a swimming wizard (or dolphin). If the Viking sailed an 18th century Ship of the Line, the Kraken would have crushed him instead of sunning itself, oblivious to his approach. Hide thick enough to repel the strongest magics rendered it insensitive to small pests like humans, dolphins, or row boats. The odds of a Kraken deliberately crushing a nearby swimmer were miniscule.

The odds of getting accidentally sucked into its gills or smashed by a tentacle as the Kraken swam along were phenomenally higher.

If you needed to defeat a Kraken? Other encounters compiled by the Merpeople confirmed that a Kraken's eyes were the windows to the soul and mind. The trick was finding the eye then stunning the Kraken before it saw you. Or crushed you to death accidentally. Harry had expected at least one amazing mythical beast, and had prepared.

The Kraken didn't bother Harry. It was already unconscious.

That fact troubled Harry, because he hadn't done anything. He'd just arrived.

What good was a defense system that didn't work? The Kraken seemed like the Atlantean equivalent to a laser-filled hallway with exquisitely precise motion sensors, floor pressure plates capable of detecting the smallest change in weight, mana detection runes and lethal countermeasures ... all turned off. Harry swam away from the Kraken, down into the main ruins of Atlantis. All of his sensors - magical spells, sonar, pressure and current gauges - indicated no threat other than the Kraken.

That also disturbed him, and he thought as he swam towards the city.

Theory #1 - Conspicuous Consumption. The Kraken's mere existence represented a phenomenal show of force, a symbolic warning against those who would dare to trespass. It said that Atlantis has such ridiculously good defences that we wasted a Kraken. This would not fit Harry's style - a 'Do not disturb' sign would work nicely - but perhaps the ancients had their own peculiar style. Warnings shouldn't depend on subtlety or the target making inferential leaps, so Harry was inclined to discount this theory. If the Kraken had been intended as a warning, Harry considered that it would probably be prudent to heed it. But he swam on, thinking still.

Theory #2 - Coincidence. Perhaps the Kraken was just passing through, or had made Atlantis its home. There was a logic to that - Atlantis had been an above-water city and only later an underwater ruin. While Harry had trained with Merpeople, there was no reason to believe that Atlantis had specialized ocean-based defenses. It might not have any traps remaining after all this time underwater. Perhaps the Kraken just liked the view, its own little miniature town to play with. Maybe it felt attracted by the nature of the city. Harry could feel the magic in his bones, it made his hair try to stand up underneath his wet-suit. The Kraken might enjoy that feeling.

After all, the nature of Atlantis attracted Harry. Harry didn't plan based on coincidences, but they happened more often than plots and he couldn't rule out that the Kraken simply admired the magical decor of the place.

Theory #3 - Someone else had beaten him to Atlantis and dealt with the Kraken. This was the most troubling theory.

By all accounts Krakens slept hard. If someone else had knocked it out, it would sleep for years. Decades. At least one (non-verified) story said that the famous Greek Kraken slept for four or five centuries at a time when Zeus wasn't releasing it. Apocryphal, but that would account for the disappearance of Kraken's from Muggle sea lore from the time of Admiral Nelson. Harry briefly worried his dallying had cost him, which was ludicrous. Atlantis had been down here for Millennia. The chances that he'd been beaten by a year or even a decade seemed small.

Of all of the theories Harry imagined, this wasn't the most plausible theory. But it was the most actionable.

And it wasn't like looking out for a potentially hostile other wizard differed much much from watching for magical defenses in general.

Harry swam down to the ocean floor. Entering the city on the east side, well away from the stray tentacle.

The buildings had a style Harry labelled Classically Greek, but with more ornamentation that he'd seen in the Parthenon or the recreations of other ancient sites. Falcons, Owls and other sculptures of Patronuses looked down on the ocean floor from the tops of buildings. Atlantis had a simpler architecture, more consistent than the magical buildings of his youth which, like Hogwarts, tended more towards chaos than consistency. But statuary and carvings made each building distinct. Harry could look from building to building and see the same shapes. Houses were all roughly the same size with the same layout of doors. He could pick out repeated features, not mass produced like Muggle technology, but either the Atlanteans had a building code or specific reasons for design. Large windows faced north, with smaller doorways to the south. Apart from the ornamentation, sigils near each door and etchings on the side, the buildings looked near identical.

Smaller buildings clustered along the outskirts of town. Larger buildings - probably meeting houses, marketplaces, and the like - were towards the center.

The city looked serene, as if it had been gently lowered into a bowl of water and then ... nothing. The difficulty of finding Atlantis had doubtless helped to keep it from being looted, but Harry had expected much more damage and decay. Most buildings looked intact, although a few had collapsed into the crevasse. Historians had never nailed down the exact nature of Atlantis' destruction, although the topic was hotly argued. (Harry had long since stopped using the word debated when discussing differences of opinions about legend), but Harry had expected it to look like ... , well, more like a disaster.

What kind of natural disaster destroys an entire population, but leaves the city intact? Disease seems obvious, but then it would be above ground. An odd coincidence. Even now, swimming among the ruins, no answer presented itself to Harry. If Atlantis sank slowly, the citizens would have relocated. Muggles did that all the time, abandoning cities that became uninhabitable. For powerful wizards it would be minor annoyance, no more. If Hogsmeade fell into a newly-created sea, the world would hear the complaints. Complaining occupied a good portion of every day life. But Atlantis had just - ceased, with not a single record or complaint.

It seemed unlikely that the population survived the disaster.

But the city of Atlantis had. It looked abandoned, but peaceful. Just submerged as if it had been placed inside an unshaken snow globe. If it had been a quickly submerged, enough to kill the population (if a natural dam had burst, for example) then Harry's quick Fermi calculation indicated more buildings would be destroyed. Unless they were magically reinforced, Harry thought, doubting himself automatically.

A neutron bomb or other modern technological horror could have done the trick, but technologically those hadn't existed (had they?). Magically ... Harry didn't know.

Harry swam up to one of the smaller houses and wordlessly cast five spells to verify his solitude. His panoptis incantation caused his vision to flash yellow and Harry quickly spun around, wand in hand. He started to cast a wide ranging stunning spell, but the only created he saw was a dolphin that stopped abruptly and stared at him. It floated just past the corner of the alleyway, halfway between the ground and the roof.

Harry remembered the dolphin inspecting the Kraken. Was this the same one? Even if he'd been looking down at the dolphin swimming in a pool, Harry doubted he could tell dolphins apart. Underwater, in the depths illuminated by some natural light and the glare of his headlamps, he had no chance. The dolphin floated there, waiting and watching him. Harry didn't lower his guard, but relaxed a bit. Dolphins could be dangerous, but they were no Krakens.

In other ways dolphins posed more of a threat. Dolphins weren't magical, but were definitely sentient. That also meant they could be reasoned with.

"My name is Harry Potter," Harry said calmly in his passable (albeit heavily accented) Mermish. Well, his name he bubbled in closest equivalent he could find phonetically, which basically sounded like 'Harry Potter' spoken underwater. Hahahahrraaeyeeye Potttototor. The dolphin's head swiveled around a bit, to take in Harry with one eye. It was tough to judge another species facial expressions. The human mind spent immense power to read human faces, but those didn't translate well the further you walked the evolutionary tree. But some part of Harry thought the the dolphin looked ... intrigued.

The dolphin didn't move beyond small gestures to hold its position in the mild current. It just watched him, fins slowly pushing up and down in the water. Harry dare not turn his back on it. But Blboblb had not withdrawn his objections trivially. Harry slowly reached into his pouch and pulled out a small crystal. He gave it a squeeze and made a small mental command: 'Dolphin greeting.'

The crystal erupted in a series of squeaks, chirps and squeals. Even in his own range of hearing, it sounded impressive, but Harry knew the sounds had a range many kilohertz above human hearing.

Even before the sounds died out, the dolphin convulsed with laughter. Bubbles of air escaped the blowhole as it rolled back and forth slightly, shuddering with amusement. Harry squeezed his crystal again, waiting for the translated answer, but there was nothing. He frowned.

"The Devil answer'd,

'Bray a fool in a morter with wheat,

yet shall not his folly be beaten out of him;

If Jesus Christ is the greatest man,

you ought to love him in the greatest degree:

now hear how he has given his sanction to the law of the ten commandments:"

Alexio laughed like he hadn't in years.

Earlier, Alexio Vasconcelos had been stunned to see Harry Potter. All of his spies, moles, sources and spells agreed that Harry had been a statue for several decades now. Harry, along with one-hundred thirteen other unfortunate victims, were safely inside the Department of Mysteries, until their radiation levels allowed for depetrification. When had Harry gotten free? Had he never truly been trapped? How had they circumvented the radiation? Alexio didn't trust any of his spies - that's why he had so many, and why they were all ignorant of the others existence - but he trusted physics and radioactive decay followed a predictable schedule. In the first year after his trap, Alexio confirmed and double checked the list of victims, to make sure that Harry hadn't escaped. Then Alexio had relaxed and decided to use his time fulfilling an earlier goal of his - of Draco's.

Alexio's search led him to Atlantis. The obvious destination, in hindsight. Finding it hadn't been simple, but Alexio had access to esoteric works and vaults and accumulated lore that wizards decades his senior would have killed for, had they known he possessed it. His search had taken extensive resources and years, but the resolution had never been in doubt.

Alexio found Atlantis.

And, unexpectedly, Harry Potter.

He froze when he stumbled across Harry swimming through Atlantis as though it was just another adventure. He'd been stunned to see the Harry Potter he'd spent decades plotting and conspiring against swimming in the immaculate ruins. It was so wildly improbable and unexpected that, for once, Alexio had no idea what to do.

Fortunately Alexio's passive defenses continued working. Over his wet-suit he wore his newest invention, robes with a calming illusions. He'd had the idea decades ago, after a few bad experiences with Armageddon Enchantments. Armageddon robes had their purpose, but lacked subtlety. The viewer's eyes slid off the wearer, to be sure. But the apprehension and fear that the spell caused triggered a fight or flight response. Armageddon robes put everyone on high alert, which was counter-productive.

Alexio often needed to appear innocuous, like he belonged in the situation. The enchantment worked on the same principle as before - don't bother with illusions and simply attack the victim's mental state - but with more serene results. Often times Alexio could pass unawares through a crowd and even walk past supposedly guarded doors. It was not that the guard weren't aware of him, the robes did not make you forget.

They just made it seemed like you belonged. Guards didn't see Alexio, they saw their employer, or an Auror, or any number of 'authorized personnel,' walk through the restricted door. Anything that seemed reasonable. So when Harry whirled on Alexio, somehow detecting him, he'd simply frozen and hoped that his Affinity Robes worked.

Alexio dare not raise shields. Armaggedon robes worked on brute force, but he'd learned the price payed for a more subtle illusion was that it was more easily disrupted. If the guard stopped to think about it, he may wonder why his employer was here instead of on that business trip. Doing anything that contradicted the viewer's beliefs would shatter the illusion and break the spell. And while Alexio had a decent mental model of Harry Potter, nobody could be said to have a good one.

Still, Alexio's wand was ready.

Harry spoke something that sounded like Mermish. Alexio stared. That could be a problem ... Alexio didn't speak Mermish and if Harry was seeing a Merperson, he'd get suspicious if he wasn't answered. Alexio's wand twitched nervously. Harry had obvious shields up, and that meant he had other less-visible means of defence. Alexio glanced at Harry's wand. It was the same one he always had. That was good, some of his spies said that Harry had been seen (rarely, but from time to time) with the Elder Wand. Perhaps if he attacked Harry, he could win.

Possible, but probably no better than a coin toss. Non-lethally? That seemed unlikely.

Alexio considered raising more subtle shields, perhaps if he just retreated... he furiously considered his options.

Harry had pulled out some magical bauble like nothing Alexio had encountered and then the dolphin squeals started.

He couldn't help himself. He laughed with relief, laughter that echoed in his mind by Draco Malfoy.

A Dolphin! Harry Potter sees a dolphin!

A stroke of luck, or perhaps his invention worked even better than he'd hoped? After a few second Alexio controlled himself and calmly swam away into the nearest building. It's what a dolphin would do, and in any case Alexio was in no position to deal with Harry now. Given that Harry considered Alexio to be part of the local fauna, he doubted Harry would attack him. The prudent course of action was to retreat and try to figure out what had gone horribly wrong and why Harry was awake - and in Atlantis of all places - but that meant ceding any discoveries to Harry.

As long as Alexio's Robes functioned Harry would simply view him as something that belonged. Harry would be thinking, to be sure, but even if he did somehow see through the illusion - well, just because he'd managed to escape his fate as a statue didn't mean that Harry had any particular knowledge of Alexio Vasconcelos' past identity. At worst, Alexio and Harry were rival archeologists searching the same site. Some deception and secrecy would be expected. Even if Harry later worked out that he'd been tricked, Alexio could simply admit that he'd been racing Harry Potter to discover the secrets of Atlantis, which was true enough.

It was rational. Harry would accept that, even if he was annoyed. He might try to bargain or negotiate or cajole, but he would not attack if he discovered Alexio's deception. Of this, Alexio felt sure.

So, Alexio continued his exploration. If Harry thought starting in one of the side buildings had value, Alexio saw no reason to second guess that. He swam through the doorway and paused to take stock.

The house could have passed for a Muggle apartment, albeit spartan and low technology. It looked comfortable, even elegant. A plush couch ran along one side of the room between two ornately crafted end tables, legs made of what appeared to be twirled ivory. Narwhale horns. Beautiful shells lined the table, reflecting all the colours of the rainbow from the glowing light that emanated from the very walls themselves. The couch faced a simple fireplace carved into the building's stone wall. Wrought iron pokers, dull black, stood sentry in a rack beside it. The couch's fabric appeared bright and unfaded, a clean floral print.

Alexio was impressed. Magical items degraded slower than Muggle tools, but they degraded all the same. The elements would not be denied, at least not by the modern magics he grew up with. Spells had to be renewed, so seeing Atlantis in such pristine condition after eons spoke well of the magic of its inhabitants. Nothing rusted or faded. The lighting spells had not faltered, either. These were just throw-away enchantments meant to keep houses tidy.

Alexio whistled his appreciation inside his bubble head sphere, idly wondering what that sounded like to Harry. Probably a high pitched squeal, he thought as he swam through the house.

Alexio heard Harry swim into the house behind him, while he inspected the kitchen.

The kitchen table was still set. Small ivory spears the size of knitting needles were set besides plates in lieu of knives and forks. But also spoons and glasses. Red wine filled one of the glasses, the color clear and ominous and Draco was reminded of the phrase "The Wine Dark Sea." Besides the glass, a crystal pitcher also held wine, as if the pourer had only had time to pour one glass when the disaster occurred. Alexio stared as the wine from the glass and pitcher started to mix with the surrounding water, viscous globes slowly spreading and diffusing into the salty brine.

Alexio watched the scene for several seconds, uncomprehending and merely observing before realization sunk in.

The disaster just happened here. Moments ago. Seconds ago. Atlantis was frozen, somehow. Which explains why my search ended here. Atlantis is also trapped beyond time. No matter when I arrived in Atlantis, it would have always been right after the disaster, in the Atlantean frame of reference. And if that is true for me, it would be true of any searcher ... Harry wouldn't bother with Atlantis until he had no pressing business, which means ...

Alexio spun around. He saw Harry Potter staring through the doorway, eyes fixed on the same place setting, tracking the wine diffusing into the ocean. Alexio raised his wand and started Al-Jabber's Silent Stupefication spells. Alexio raised his shields just as Harry calmly flicked his wand.

Alexio's Robes rent apart just as his shields went up.

Harry's eyes widened, but he made no move to cast again. Harry seemed to be searching for the right words.

Alexio could imagine Harry's predicament. Harry faced significant information leakage problems. Difficult enough when limited to six hours. How much of a problem did this Harry face? Alexio watched the range of emotions playing across Harry's face for the briefest moment. Harry had been stunned, as surprised as Alexio had been when he realized Harry saw him as a dolphin. Potter's training kicked in, but it was too late. Before all emotion drained from his face at some level Alexio ... Draco ... knew. This Harry arrived from far enough in the future.

This Harry had witnessed their endgame. Harry had come out of his enforced delay and Alexio's next plan had failed. Or perhaps the one after that. It didn't matter. Harry had discovered who had plotted against him. He had no logic to back it up, but Alexio knew.

Had Harry imprisoned me out of necessity? Had he killed me? Did he hate me? Did Harry regret what had happened as much as I did?

And the last thought, his greatest fear. Had it all been a misunderstanding?

More than he'd wanted anything in a long time, Alexio/Draco yearned to know the answers. How it all turned out.

And he knew again he just knew that Harry wouldn't tell him. Harry Potter would be capable of biting his tongue no matter how much he wanted to explain. (If he did).

Alexio reminded himself that the possibility remained that Draco was merely projecting his hopes and desires onto the Harry Potter that swam before him today. Today there would be no answers.

"I know you are from the future, Harry Potter," Alexio said. He'd seen numerous small details in Harry's equipment and general bearing that confirmed his hypothesis. In hindsight it was obvious that the Crystal melded technology and magic in a strange hybrid function (although an MP3 player would have done just as well).

Alexio didn't berate himself for missing it. Time-traveling (beyond the six hour limit of Time turners) had never entered his mind as a hypothesis.

Harry seemed satisfied with Alexio's statement, like it settled a number of issues and made everything smoother. Harry still paused for a second, apparently considering implications. Alexio waited patiently. If Harry was from the future, he would have more to consider. After a few more seconds, during which Harry tugged on his recently trimmed beard, he finally spoke up.

"One question, a safe question that has no bearing on our situation, but I'd like to know. Your robes. Did you invent the Lotus Eater Enchantment ... Alexio, isn't it?"

Is he calling me Alexio because he doesn't know? Or on the off chance that I don't suspect? In the end, it didn't matter. The game had rules, and now was not the time to break them.

"Lotus Eater?" Alexio cocked his head, carefully pronouncing the words. "I am not familiar with that phrase," he said, emphasizing his normally mild Portuguese accent.

"In Muggle Greek mythology, those who ate the Lotus became complacent with the world around them. Not oblivious, just ... content."

"That is a good name," Alexio agreed with a chuckle, "better than the one I used. Yes, it is mine. I take some comfort you overcame it only because it was already known to you."

"It's on my checklist. Along with many other mind-altering magics. I still didn't catch it right away," Harry added in a comforting voice. "That's the trouble with Pasithean illusions. They seem so reasonable. You don't notice your confusion. At some level I always thought whoever designed them ..." Harry trailed off, and didn't finish explaining what he thought.

Alexio slowly lowered his wand, other hand up in a surrendering gesture and spoke calmly and confidently.

"You saw the wine. You of all people understand the implications. Everyone who has ever sought out Atlantis has arrived now - at the same time. I suspect you and I are here for the same purpose, Harry Potter. Later on, I may have questions. Perhaps you do, too. Those must wait until we both pass this time in your timeline. We each possess different knowledge, but we share the same goal."

"Tell me my purpose, then," Harry said. His wand never wavered from Alexio.

"We are both here to rescue Albus Dumbledore," Alexio said solemnly. The seconds ticked by.

"Truce?" Harry Potter asked.

"Truce," Alexio agreed.

They swam out of the doorway side by side, discussing their respective plans for exploring Atlantis.